<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260212</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12816544</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1177/17562848251414825</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12816544</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">10.1177_17562848251414825</infon><infon key="elocation-id">17562848251414825</infon><infon key="kwd">Crohn’s disease immunomodulator pharmacokinetics ulcerative colitis vedolizumab</infon><infon key="license">This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/) which permits non-commercial use, reproduction and distribution of the work without further permission provided the original work is attributed as specified on the SAGE and Open Access pages (https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/open-access-at-sage).</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:Aviv</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chaemsupaphan;given-names:Thanaboon</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Arzivian;given-names:Arteen</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kim;given-names:Yong-Sul</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Paramsothy;given-names:Sudarshan</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Kariyawasam;given-names:Viraj</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Leong;given-names:Rupert W.</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2026</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease: pharmacokinetics and the role of immunomodulator co-therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>103</offset><text>Vedolizumab (VED) is a gut-selective monoclonal antibody and an effective biological agent for many patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Therapeutic drug monitoring has been used to optimise treatment with other biological agents; however, the clinical applicability of measuring vedolizumab trough concentrations is unclear. Initial registration trial data demonstrated a positive exposure–efficacy relationship of vedolizumab in IBD. However, there is conflicting data in more recent studies, with no definitive benefit of vedolizumab dose-escalation and no consistent target vedolizumab trough concentration identified. Also, unlike with anti-tumour necrosis factor agents, the clinical benefit of immunomodulator co-therapy with vedolizumab is uncertain. Although initial research suggested no clinical advantage of combining vedolizumab with an immunomodulator, more recent studies have shown potential benefit. This narrative review aims to explore current evidence on vedolizumab pharmacokinetics and whether immunomodulator co-therapy should be considered with vedolizumab.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1198</offset><text>Plain language summary</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1221</offset><text> Vedolizumab: how it works and if it should be combined with other medications in inflammatory bowel disease </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1331</offset><text>This article reviews how the medication vedolizumab works in the body (called pharmacokinetics) when used to treat people with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), such as Crohn’s disease and ulcerative colitis. It also looks at how using vedolizumab together with other immune-suppressing drugs (called immunomodulators) might affect its effectiveness. The goal is to help doctors better understand how to use these treatments together to manage IBD more effectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1799</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1812</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), consisting of ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn’s disease (CD), is a chronic health condition characterised by inflammation affecting the gastrointestinal tract. Symptoms include diarrhoea, abdominal pain, rectal bleeding, fatigue and weight loss. Whilst prevalence rates of IBD have been increasing over time, the therapeutic armamentarium has expanded over the last two decades. Particularly, biological and oral small-molecule agents have revolutionised the management of IBD. These medications target various immunological pathways that have been implicated in the pathogenesis of IBD. However, the only current advanced therapy that selectively targets the gastrointestinal tract is vedolizumab (VED).  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2557</offset><text>VED (Entyvio; Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd, Tokyo, Japan) is a humanised IgG1 monoclonal antibody that specifically binds to the α4β7 integrin, which is preferentially expressed on gut-homing T-helper lymphocytes.   This binding inhibits the adhesion of these lymphocytes to mucosal-addressin-cell-adhesion molecule-1, which is predominantly found on endothelial cells of the gastrointestinal tract and involved in T lymphocyte migration (Figure 1). As such, VED selectively blocks leukocyte trafficking to the gastrointestinal tract.   The GEMINI 1 and VISIBLE 1 randomised controlled trials found that intravenous (IV) and subcutaneous (SC) VED, respectively, led to superior rates of clinical and endoscopic remission versus placebo at week 52 in UC. Similarly, higher rates of clinical remission were seen with IV and SC VED in CD in the GEMINI 2 and VISIBLE 2 trials.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">10.1177_17562848251414825-fig1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>3442</offset><text>Mechanisms of action of advanced therapies in inflammatory bowel disease.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">10.1177_17562848251414825-fig1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>3516</offset><text>Source: Kobayashi and Hibi.

</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">10.1177_17562848251414825-fig1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig</infon><offset>3546</offset><text>Diagram visualizing the mechanisms of action of advanced therapies in inflammatory bowel disease, showing the pathways and drugs involved.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3685</offset><text>Therapeutic drug monitoring (TDM) involves measuring drug and anti-drug antibodies, differentiating underexposed patients from those with mechanistic failure.   It is a proven strategy to optimise the effectiveness of anti-tumour necrosis factor (anti-TNF) antagonists, and although its use is not fully implemented in routine clinical practice, it forms part of consensus statements and management guidelines. One strategy that has also been shown to reduce the risk of anti-drug antibody formation and resultant loss of response is combining anti-TNF therapy with an immunomodulator.   However, unlike with anti-TNF therapy, there are no guidelines on target VED trough levels despite its use for over a decade. The role of measuring VED trough levels is currently not standard practice, and there has been mixed data regarding the efficacious role of combining an immunomodulator with VED. We aimed to examine the evolving literature on TDM of VED, together with reviewing the benefit, or lack thereof, of combination VED and thiopurine therapy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>4734</offset><text>Materials and methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4756</offset><text>We performed a comprehensive review of PubMed and Embase from inception through to 1 February 2025. The combination of search terms used included ‘Vedolizumab’, ‘pharmacokinetics’, ‘immunomodulator’, ‘thiopurine’ and ‘combination therapy’. Reference lists of published articles were manually searched to identify additional relevant studies. We included both full-text articles and key abstracts published in English that were relevant to the topic, with the aim of conducting a narrative review.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5273</offset><text>Studies meeting the following inclusion criteria were included: (1) patients were diagnosed with UC or CD; (2) information on vedolizumab pharmacokinetics and/or immunomodulator co-therapy; (3) studies were original articles. Exclusion criteria were as follows: (1) studies focused on paediatric UC or CD; (2) case reports, case series, review articles, or editorials; and (3) studies in languages other than English. Two reviewers (A.P. and T.C.) independently screened the titles and abstracts of all articles. Disagreements were resolved through discussion, and if consensus was not reached, then a third reviewer (R.W.L.) was consulted. Full-text screening then occurred to determine studies for inclusion. Extracted data included author, year, region, study design, sample size, comparison data, week of assessment and relevant statistics available (odds ratios (ORs) and hazard ratios (HRs)). The methodologic quality and risk of bias were assessed using the Newcastle–Ottawa Scale.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>6266</offset><text>Pharmacokinetic role of vedolizumab and TDM</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6310</offset><text>The recommended treatment regimen of VED consists of a 6-week induction phase (weeks 0, 2 and 6) of fixed 300 mg IV infusions, followed by a maintenance phase of 300 mg IV every 8 weeks or 108 mg SC every 2 weeks. To address primary non-response and secondary loss of response after fixed dosing administration, numerous studies have investigated the VED exposure–response relationship and the role of TDM.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>6729</offset><text>Trial data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>6740</offset><text>IV administration of vedolizumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6773</offset><text>The exposure–efficacy relationships of IV VED from the GEMINI studies examined VED trough concentrations during induction, together with quartile analyses and their associations with clinical outcomes. GEMINI 1 and 2 included patients with UC and CD, respectively, who received VED 300 mg IV at weeks 0 and 2, with disease status assessment at week 6. Outcomes analysed included clinical response, clinical remission and mucosal healing. Anti-TNF exposure occurred in 48% of the patients from GEMINI 1, and 62% of patients from GEMINI 2. GEMINI 3 included patients with CD who all had prior anti-TNF exposure and received VED 300 mg IV at weeks 0, 2 and 6.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7436</offset><text>The analysis from GEMINI 1 by Rosario et al.   revealed a positive exposure–efficacy relationship for clinical response, clinical remission and mucosal healing for IV VED induction. A trough concentration increase from quartile 1 (⩽17.1 µg/mL) to quartile 4 (&gt;35.7–140 µg/mL) corresponded to absolute increases of 31% for clinical remission, 34% for clinical response and 43% for mucosal healing at week 6.   These findings are supported by higher median VED trough concentrations in UC remitters versus non-remitters (34.7 vs 23.7 µg/mL) at week 6.   A propensity-score-based analysis from GEMINI 1 further identified VED trough concentrations of 37.1 µg/mL at week 6, 18.4 µg/mL at week 14 and 12.7 µg/mL during maintenance that were associated with clinical remission.   In CD, GEMINI 2 demonstrated a modest exposure–efficacy gradient, with a 14% absolute increase in clinical remission from quartile 1 (⩽16.0 µg/mL) to quartile 4 (&gt;33.7–177 µg/mL) at week 6.   Like in UC, higher median VED trough concentrations were seen in CD remitters versus non-remitters (26.8 vs 23.5 µg/mL, respectively) at week 6. Possible contributing factors to the lower exposure–efficacy relationship at week 6 in CD versus UC include disease pathophysiology and the time needed to respond to treatment. This interpretation is supported by GEMINI 3, which showed a steeper exposure–efficacy relationship for clinical remission at week 10. The absolute rate increase in clinical remission from quartile 1 to quartile 4 was 22% at week 10 (compared with 14% at week 6).  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9033</offset><text>The strength of these analyses is the large, well-conducted randomised controlled trial design, enabling the exploration of drug exposure patterns across multiple clinical and endoscopic outcomes. However, the exposure–efficacy relationships are derived post hoc and cannot establish causality. Furthermore, quartile analyses are broad and may not consider interpatient variability in drug clearance, disease activity and concomitant therapies. Also, although higher concentrations correlated with better outcomes, these studies do not clarify whether proactively targeting particular VED trough concentrations improves outcomes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9665</offset><text>Hanzel et al.   aimed to develop a pharmacokinetic–pharmacodynamic model linking VED exposure to endoscopic remission in the LOVE-CD trial. This study provides valuable mechanistic insight, particularly because VED trough concentrations were paired with scheduled endoscopic assessments. Patients received VED 300 mg IV every 8 weeks, and serum concentration measurements were performed before each infusion and at endoscopic assessments at baseline, week 26 and week 52. A VED trough concentration of 20.0 mg/L corresponded to a 35% probability of achieving endoscopic remission. However, the cohort consisted predominantly of patients with refractory CD (89% had prior anti-TNF exposure), which likely reduced overall remission rates and may limit generalisability to biologic-naïve populations. Moreover, dose-optimised regimens were not evaluated, restricting the ability to infer whether higher drug exposure would translate into improved outcomes. Both Hanzel et al.   and Rosario et al.   identified low albumin as a predictor of higher VED clearance and reduced probability of remission, reinforcing the relevance of host factors in interpreting VED pharmacokinetics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10850</offset><text>Okamoto et al.   demonstrated that VED pharmacokinetics did not differ between Asian and non-Asian patients with IBD. This is an important finding given that pivotal trials were conducted predominantly in Western populations. Additionally, across multiple analyses, no substantive difference in VED clearance has been observed between UC and CD. This suggests that inter-individual rather than disease-specific pharmacokinetic variation is the primary driver of exposure differences.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11334</offset><text>Maintenance IV VED levels were analysed in the VIEWS trial, which evaluated thiopurine withdrawal for patients with UC receiving IV VED every 8 weeks.   Patients were in steroid-free clinical remission for at least 6 months, and had a Mayo endoscopic subscore of ⩽1 at baseline. Higher week 48 VED trough concentration levels were associated with clinical remission (16.3 vs 9.2 µg/mL, p = 0.04).   A week 48 VED trough concentration of 17.7 µg/mL was associated with clinical remission at 2 years, versus 12.4 µg/mL for those not in remission (p = 0.02).   In quartile analysis, a VED concentration of &gt;11.3 µg/mL was associated with sustained clinical remission at week 48 (AUC 0.71 (95% confidence interval (CI): 0.49–0.93) sensitivity 82.4%, specificity 60.0%).   Although these results add evidence to potential target concentrations during maintenance therapy, the sample size was modest, and VED trough concentrations were measured in a highly selected population already in deep remission at baseline. Importantly, combination therapy with a thiopurine did not significantly impact VED concentrations (14.7 µg/mL (interquartile rate (IQR), 12.3–18.5 µg/mL) in the combination group vs 15.9 µg/mL (IQR, 10.1–22.7 µg/mL) in the VED monotherapy group, respectively, p = 0.36).   This is substantiated by Yarur et al. in a prospective cohort study that included 133 patients on VED. The addition of a thiopurine, with 6-TGN levels ⩾152 pmol per 8 × 108 RBCs, did not significantly impact VED trough concentrations (8.8 µg/mL for combination therapy vs 10.5 µg/mL for VED monotherapy, p &gt; 0.05).  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13004</offset><text>In the ENTERPRISE study, Schwartz et al.   conducted a randomised controlled trial assessing VED in 32 patients with active perianal fistulising CD. Patients received either standard induction or an additional IV dose at week 10. Although higher VED concentrations were observed from weeks 14 to 30 in the intensified arm, this did not translate into superior clinical outcomes compared to standard dosing (64.3% response in the standard group vs 42.9% in the week 10 group). Notably, the higher concentrations in the intensified group were not consistently maintained, and the small sample size may limit the applicability of these findings.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13649</offset><text>Dose-escalation strategies, widely used for anti-TNF agents, have shown mixed results with VED. Outtier et al. performed a multi-centre, prospective study of patients on VED 300 mg IV every 4 weeks undergoing secondary loss of response, and escalated to 4-weekly dosing. Whilst median VED trough concentrations increased from 8.7 to 19.1 µg/mL, clinical response was achieved in 54% of patients at week 8.   Similarly, a systematic review and meta-analysis by Peyrin-Biroulet et al.   found that dose escalation restored response in 53.8% of secondary non-responders. These findings suggest that, at least in some patients, higher VED exposure may recapture response. However, the evidence base largely consists of observational cohorts without control groups, and definitions of secondary non-response and clinical remission vary widely between studies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14511</offset><text>The recent ENTERPRET study provides an important counterbalance.   It investigated the potential benefit of VED dose-optimisation in patients with UC who had high drug clearance at week 5 and clinical non-response at week 6.   Patients received VED 300 mg IV at weeks 0, 2 and 6, and were then randomised 1:1 to receive standard dosing (300 mg every 8 weeks) or dose-optimised VED (600 mg at week 6, then 300 mg every 4 weeks; or 600 mg at week 6, and then 600 mg every 4 weeks (based on week 5 serum VED concentration)). Clinical remission rates at week 30 were similar between standard dosing and dose-optimised (300 or 600 mg every 4 weeks) patients, despite higher VED trough concentrations in the dose-optimised group.   These results imply that early pharmacokinetic non-response may reflect intrinsic VED non-responsiveness rather than insufficient drug exposure. This suggests there is limited benefit of dose-optimisation in early non-responders with UC.   Notably, ENTERPRET evaluated early non-responders, whereas previous cohort studies focused primarily on secondary non-responders. Therefore, its conclusions may not apply directly to the latter group, and a randomised controlled trial in secondary non-responders would be required to provide definitive evidence regarding the efficacy of dose intensification in this setting.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>15875</offset><text>SC administration of vedolizumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15908</offset><text>Similar to GEMINI 1, positive exposure–efficacy outcomes were seen with SC VED from the VISIBILE 1 trial.   After receiving IV VED at week 0 and week 2, patients were randomised to either receive SC VED 108 mg every 2 weeks, IV VED 300 mg every 8 weeks or placebo. Prior anti-TNF exposure occurred in 37.7%, 44.4% and 35.7% of patients in each group, respectively. The primary endpoint was the proportion of patients in clinical remission, defined as a total Mayo score of ⩽2 with no subscore &gt;1 point, at week 52.   Median serum VED trough concentrations were estimated to be higher for SC VED (34.6 µg/mL (90% CI: 15.5–72.8 µg/mL)) than IV VED (11.1 µg/mL (90% CI: 2.1–34.2 µg/mL)), with consistent observed values across study visits.   The proportion of patients who achieved clinical remission at week 52 increased with higher VED exposure. The absolute rate increased from quartile 1 (⩽26.4 µg/mL) to quartile 4 (&gt;44.5 µg/mL) was 33% for clinical remission and 39% for endoscopic improvement.   Positive exposure–efficacy outcomes were also seen with SC VED in CD from the VISIBILE 2 trial.   In this trial, patients received IV VED at week 0 and week 2, and were then randomised 2:1 to SC VED 108 mg every 2 weeks or placebo. The primary outcome was clinical remission (defined as a Crohn’s disease activity index [CDAI] ⩽150) at week 52. There was an absolute rate increase from quartile 1 (9.2–25.7 µg/mL) to quartile 4 (42.6–131.0 µg/mL) of 13% for clinical remission and 16% for clinical response at week 52.   This association was less pronounced than in UC.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17537</offset><text>Real-world data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17553</offset><text>Several real-world studies have examined the exposure–efficacy relationship of VED in UC and CD, with mixed results. Many have demonstrated a positive association between VED trough concentrations and clinical, biochemical, endoscopic and histological remission.   Factors identified through univariate and multivariate analyses that correlate with higher VED concentrations include smaller body size, less severe disease activity, higher albumin level, lower faecal calprotectin and C-reactive protein levels. Singh et al.   conducted a meta-analysis of five cohort studies, revealing that UC patients who achieve clinical remission have significantly higher vedolizumab trough concentrations during maintenance therapy (14.3 vs 10.5 µg/mL; mean difference 5.1 µg/mL (95% CI: 2.8–7.4), p &lt; 0.01). Similarly, VED trough concentrations were significantly higher in patients achieving endoscopic remission (13.0 vs 9.7 µg/mL; mean difference 5.1 µg/mL (95% CI: 2.2–7.9), p &lt; 0.01). Statistically significant differences were not observed in CD patients.   Overall, Singh et al.   suggested a VED trough concentration of &gt;18–20 µg/mL at week 6 is associated with a higher likelihood of favourable outcomes on follow-up, whilst a maintenance concentration of &gt;10–12 µg/mL is associated with clinical remission. However, the thresholds varied across the studies, which can be attributable to multiple factors such as study design, number of participants, outcome definitions, duration and interval of vedolizumab therapy, previous exposure to biologics (particularly anti-TNF) and assays measuring vedolizumab concentrations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19210</offset><text>Consequently, universal cut-off values have not been clearly defined.   It is important to note that while these real-world studies demonstrated dose–response relationships, they do not establish causation. Higher drug concentrations may simply reflect low disease activity, therefore low drug clearance. Notably, the formation of anti-vedolizumab antibodies was low, regardless of vedolizumab trough levels. The studies on 108 mg SC vedolizumab every second week have also shown comparable efficacy to the IV formulation with higher VED trough levels.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19767</offset><text>Taken together, these studies highlight important nuances in interpreting VED pharmacokinetics. While higher exposure is associated with better outcomes, particularly in UC, the evidence supporting proactive dose optimisation or routine TDM remains limited. In our view, universal dose-intensification or target-concentration-based dosing is not recommended for all patients. Further controlled studies are needed to clarify which patient subgroups truly benefit from dose escalation and to define clinically actionable concentration thresholds.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20313</offset><text>Clinical impact of vedolizumab with or without immunomodulators</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20377</offset><text>Combination therapy between a biological agent and an immunomodulator is a potential strategy to improve patient outcomes. With anti-TNF therapy, the addition of an immunomodulator has been shown to improve clinical and endoscopic outcomes whilst reducing the formation of anti-TNF antibodies. Prior studies have consistently shown no significant benefit of immunomodulator co-therapy with VED; however, more recent studies suggest a potential therapeutic effect (Table 1).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table1-17562848251414825.xml</infon><infon key="id">table1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>20851</offset><text>Studies on vedolizumab and immunomodulator concomitant therapy in patients with inflammatory bowel disease.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table1-17562848251414825.xml</infon><infon key="id">table1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Country of origin&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Number of patients&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Type of study&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Comparison&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No. of patients on concomitant IMM&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week of assessment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Statistics&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sustained immunomodulator therapy?&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Shelton et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr47-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;47&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 65&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 107&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical response/remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD = 34/107&lt;break/&gt;UC = 17/65&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;OR 0.56 (95% CI: 0.19–1.66) &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.30&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Lenti et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr48-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;48&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 68&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 135&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical response or remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD = 70/135&lt;break/&gt;UC = 31/68&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weeks 14 and 52&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = NS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Stallmach et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr49-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;49&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 60&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 67&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, prospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission at week 54&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD: 15/67 – 15%&lt;break/&gt;UC: 13/60 – 21.7%&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 54&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC: 0.2 (CI: 0.02–1.66) &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.13&lt;break/&gt;CD: 0.38 (CI: 0.04–3.25) &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.37&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Baumgart et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr50-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;50&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 115&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 97&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Prospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD: 78/97&lt;break/&gt;UC: 88/115&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.825&lt;break/&gt;CD, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.369&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Kopylov et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr51-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;51&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Israel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 74&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 130&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, prospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD: 32/130&lt;break/&gt;UC: 16/74&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = NS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Samaan et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr52-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;52&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UK&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 20&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 27&lt;break/&gt;IBD-U&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Proportion of patients on combination therapy vs monotherapy with active disease at initiation of VED who achieved clinical remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD + UC = 16/50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Combo – 8/16 (50%) vs Mono – 6/21 (29%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Eriksson et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr53-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;53&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 92&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 147&lt;break/&gt;IBD-U &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, prospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and drug discontinuation, because of lack of or loss of response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;End of follow-up&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Adjusted HR 1.39; 95% CI: 0.85–2.30, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Unsure whether sustained&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Allegreti et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr54-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;54&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 40&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 96&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of an immunomodulator at the initiation of VED and response or remission&lt;break/&gt;Initiation of immunomodulators after initiation of VED and response or remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant IMM at induction:&lt;break/&gt;–CD: 20/50&lt;break/&gt;–UC: 9/46&lt;break/&gt;IMM added after induction&lt;break/&gt;–CD: 20/50&lt;break/&gt;–UC: 3/46&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 54&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC: OR 1.27, 95% CI: 0.27–5.96&lt;break/&gt;CD: OR 1.89, 95% CI: 0.66–5.38&lt;break/&gt;UC: OR 0.43; 95% CI: 0.09–2.00&lt;break/&gt;CD: OR 8.33; 95% CI: 2.15–32.26&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Amiot et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr55-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;55&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;France&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 121&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 173&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, prospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulators and steroid-free clinical remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;At week 54,&lt;break/&gt;CD: 17/78&lt;break/&gt;UC: 2/71&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weeks 14 and 54&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = NS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Hu et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr56-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;56&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 263&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 286&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Multicentre, retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulator and clinical response or remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant IMM at induction:&lt;break/&gt;–CD: 65/286&lt;break/&gt;–UC: 66/263&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weeks 30 and 54&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD (OR 1.38, 95% CI: 0.63–3.00) or UC (OR 0.63, 95% CI: 0.33–1.20).&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Kirchgesner et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr57-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;57&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;USA and France&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 2176&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 1608&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Retrospective study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of thiopurine and treatment failure – defined as hospitalisation/surgery, switch to another biologic agent or exposure to systemic steroids&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD: 804&lt;break/&gt;UC: 1088&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 26&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Combination therapy CD: RR 0.85, 95% CI: 0.74–0.98)&lt;break/&gt;Combination therapy UC: RR 0.90, 95% CI: 0.77–1.05)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Naganuma et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr58-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;58&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 164&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Explorative analysis of previous randomised controlled trial&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Efficacy of concomitant immunomodulator use in induction and maintenance phase&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use at weeks 0–10 (UC) – 80/164&lt;break/&gt;Concomitant use by week 60 22/41&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weeks 10 and 60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Difference in clinical response, remission and mucosal healing − 0.7 (95% CI: −14.3 to 15.7), 3.3 (95% CI: −8.5 to 15.2) and 1.8 (95% CI: −13 to 6.5)&lt;break/&gt;Difference in clinical remission and mucosal healing between subgroups − 26.1 (95% CI: −3.5 to 55.6) and 29.9 (95% CI: 1.4–58.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Jeffrey et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr59-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;59&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Australia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 61&lt;break/&gt;CD&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Single-centre, retrospective cohort study&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Concomitant use of immunomodulator (thiopurine or methotrexate) and clinical response&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC: 22/61&lt;break/&gt;CD: 7/24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 52 (1 year)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;No difference in clinical response/remission week 12 (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.38), 26 (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.83) or 52 (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.32)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pudipeddi et al.&lt;sup&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;bibr25-17562848251414825&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;25&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Australia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC&lt;break/&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; = 62&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Randomised controlled trial&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Continuing azathioprine vs withdrawing azathioprine and clinical remission&lt;break/&gt;Continuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and clinical relapse&lt;break/&gt;Continuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and endoscopic remission&lt;break/&gt;Continuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and histologic remission&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC: 20/62&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Week 48&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;OR 2.5 (95% CI: 0.5–12.7)&lt;break/&gt;OR 2.5 (95% CI: 0.5–12.7)&lt;break/&gt;OR 3.4 (95% CI: 0.95–12.2), &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.05&lt;break/&gt;OR 4.2 (95% CI: 1.2–15.2), &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;p&lt;/italic&gt; = 0.02&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>20959</offset><text>Reference	Year	Country of origin	Number of patients	Type of study	Comparison	No. of patients on concomitant IMM	Week of assessment	Statistics	Sustained immunomodulator therapy?	 	Shelton et al.	2015	USA	UCn = 65CDn = 107	Multicentre, retrospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical response/remission	CD = 34/107UC = 17/65	Week 14	OR 0.56 (95% CI: 0.19–1.66) p = 0.30	Unsure whether sustained	 	Lenti et al.	2018	UK	UCn = 68CDn = 135	Multicentre, retrospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical response or remission	CD = 70/135UC = 31/68	Weeks 14 and 52	p = NS	Unsure whether sustained	 	Stallmach et al.	2016	Germany	UCn = 60CDn = 67	Multicentre, prospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission at week 54	CD: 15/67 – 15%UC: 13/60 – 21.7%	Week 54	UC: 0.2 (CI: 0.02–1.66) p = 0.13CD: 0.38 (CI: 0.04–3.25) p = 0.37	Unsure whether sustained	 	Baumgart et al.	2016	Germany	UCn = 115CDn = 97	Prospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission	CD: 78/97UC: 88/115	Week 14	UC, p = 0.825CD, p = 0.369	Unsure whether sustained	 	Kopylov et al.	2017	Israel	UCn = 74CDn = 130	Multicentre, prospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and clinical remission	CD: 32/130UC: 16/74	Week 14	p = NS	Unsure whether sustained	 	Samaan et al.	2017	UK	UCn = 20CDn = 27IBD-Un = 3	Multicentre, retrospective study	Proportion of patients on combination therapy vs monotherapy with active disease at initiation of VED who achieved clinical remission	CD + UC = 16/50	Week 14	Combo – 8/16 (50%) vs Mono – 6/21 (29%)	Unsure whether sustained	 	Eriksson et al.	2017	Sweden	UCn = 92CDn = 147IBD-U n = 7	Multicentre, prospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and drug discontinuation, because of lack of or loss of response		End of follow-up	Adjusted HR 1.39; 95% CI: 0.85–2.30, p = 0.19	Unsure whether sustained	 	Allegreti et al.	2017	USA	UCn = 40CDn = 96	Multicentre, retrospective study	Concomitant use of an immunomodulator at the initiation of VED and response or remissionInitiation of immunomodulators after initiation of VED and response or remission	Concomitant IMM at induction:–CD: 20/50–UC: 9/46IMM added after induction–CD: 20/50–UC: 3/46	Week 54	UC: OR 1.27, 95% CI: 0.27–5.96CD: OR 1.89, 95% CI: 0.66–5.38UC: OR 0.43; 95% CI: 0.09–2.00CD: OR 8.33; 95% CI: 2.15–32.26	Yes	 	Amiot et al.	2016	France	UCn = 121CDn = 173	Multicentre, prospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulators and steroid-free clinical remission	At week 54,CD: 17/78UC: 2/71	Weeks 14 and 54	p = NS	Yes	 	Hu et al.	2021	USA	UCn = 263CDn = 286	Multicentre, retrospective study	Concomitant use of immunomodulator and clinical response or remission	Concomitant IMM at induction:–CD: 65/286–UC: 66/263	Weeks 30 and 54	CD (OR 1.38, 95% CI: 0.63–3.00) or UC (OR 0.63, 95% CI: 0.33–1.20).	Yes	 	Kirchgesner et al.	2022	USA and France	UCn = 2176CDn = 1608	Retrospective study	Concomitant use of thiopurine and treatment failure – defined as hospitalisation/surgery, switch to another biologic agent or exposure to systemic steroids	CD: 804UC: 1088	Week 26	Combination therapy CD: RR 0.85, 95% CI: 0.74–0.98)Combination therapy UC: RR 0.90, 95% CI: 0.77–1.05)	Yes	 	Naganuma et al.	2022	Japan	UCn = 164	Explorative analysis of previous randomised controlled trial	Efficacy of concomitant immunomodulator use in induction and maintenance phase	Concomitant use at weeks 0–10 (UC) – 80/164Concomitant use by week 60 22/41	Weeks 10 and 60	Difference in clinical response, remission and mucosal healing − 0.7 (95% CI: −14.3 to 15.7), 3.3 (95% CI: −8.5 to 15.2) and 1.8 (95% CI: −13 to 6.5)Difference in clinical remission and mucosal healing between subgroups − 26.1 (95% CI: −3.5 to 55.6) and 29.9 (95% CI: 1.4–58.4)	Yes	 	Jeffrey et al.	2023	Australia	UCn = 61CDn = 24	Single-centre, retrospective cohort study	Concomitant use of immunomodulator (thiopurine or methotrexate) and clinical response	UC: 22/61CD: 7/24	Week 52 (1 year)	No difference in clinical response/remission week 12 (p = 0.38), 26 (p = 0.83) or 52 (p = 0.32)	Yes	 	Pudipeddi et al.	2024	Australia	UCn = 62	Randomised controlled trial	Continuing azathioprine vs withdrawing azathioprine and clinical remissionContinuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and clinical relapseContinuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and endoscopic remissionContinuing AZA vs withdrawing AZA and histologic remission	UC: 20/62	Week 48	OR 2.5 (95% CI: 0.5–12.7)OR 2.5 (95% CI: 0.5–12.7)OR 3.4 (95% CI: 0.95–12.2), p = 0.05OR 4.2 (95% CI: 1.2–15.2), p = 0.02	Yes	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">table1-17562848251414825.xml</infon><infon key="id">table1-17562848251414825</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>25785</offset><text>AZA, azathioprine; CD, Crohn’s disease; CI, confidence interval; HR, hazard ratio; IBD, inflammatory bowel disease; IMM, immunomodulator; NS, not significant; OR, odds ratio; RR, relative risk; UC, ulcerative colitis; UK, United Kingdom; USA, United States of America; VED, vedolizumab.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26074</offset><text>Evidence for combination therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>26107</offset><text>Trial data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26118</offset><text>Recent years have seen more robust studies explore whether combining VED with an immunomodulator offers additional therapeutic benefit. Pudipeddi et al.   studied the effect of thiopurine withdrawal when used in combination with VED in 62 patients with UC. The primary outcome was VED trough concentration at week 48, which was not significantly different between continued versus withdrawal groups (14.7 µg/mL (IQR, 12.3–18.5 µg/mL) vs 15.9 µg/mL (IQR, 10.1–22.7 µg/mL), respectively, p = 0.36).   However, thiopurine continuation was associated with higher faecal calprotectin remission (95.0% (19/20) vs 71.4% (30/42), p = 0.03), histologic remission (80.0% (16/20) vs 48.6% (18/37), p = 0.02) and histo-endoscopic remission (75.0% (15/20) vs 32.4% (12/37), p = 0.002).   No anti-VED antibodies were detected in either group, and hence, the prevention of immunogenicity did not explain the possible thiopurine benefit. Rather, combination therapy with the thiopurine was likely providing an additive immunosuppressive effect. However, these clinical, biochemical and endoscopic outcomes were secondary outcomes in a study primarily powered to assess VED trough concentrations. Thus, the findings should be interpreted cautiously. It should be noted that adverse events were higher in the thiopurine group, mainly relating to mild infections that did not require discontinuation of the thiopurine. Nonetheless, safety considerations are required when using immunomodulator co-therapy given their association with infections, lymphoma and non-melanoma skin cancers.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27719</offset><text>Naganuma et al.   performed an exploratory analysis of data from a randomised controlled trial studying the efficacy of combination therapy in Japanese patients with moderate to severe UC. Despite lower VED trough concentrations in the combination group, mucosal healing rates at week 60 were significantly higher with combination therapy (77.3% vs 47.4%, difference 29.9% (95% CI: 1.4–58.4)), with a numerical, but not statistically significant, advantage in clinical remission (68.2% vs 42.1%, difference 26.1% (95% CI: −3.5 to 55.6]).   These findings raise the possibility of pharmacodynamic superiority rather than a purely pharmacokinetic effect. However, the study was exploratory, had relatively small group sizes and may not be generalisable beyond the Japanese population. The similar rates of adverse events between groups are reassuring, but longer-term safety remains uncertain.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>28615</offset><text>Real-world data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28631</offset><text>Two retrospective studies also showed the potential benefit of combination therapy in CD. Allegreti et al. assessed clinical response and remission at week 54 after VED initiation.   In patients with CD, the addition of immunomodulators after induction was associated with higher clinical response and remission rates in multivariate analysis (OR: 8.3 (95% CI: 2.2–32.3)).   The authors concluded that adding immunomodulator therapy may represent a salvage therapy for patients demonstrating less than adequate response after induction with VED.   However, these findings are limited by the retrospective design, risk of bias (patients more unwell may have preferentially received combination therapy) and potential confounders. The second study was a retrospective observational review of USA and French healthcare databases comparing the effectiveness of combination therapy with VED and thiopurines against VED monotherapy in patients with CD and UC.   The risk of treatment failure (defined as a composite of hospitalisation or surgery related to IBD, treatment switch to another biological agent or exposure to systemic corticosteroids) was decreased with combination therapy compared with vedolizumab monotherapy in CD (RR: 0.85 (95% CI: 0.74–0.98)) but not in UC (RR: 0.90 (95% CI: 0.77–1.05)).   Although strengthened by a large sample size, the use of administrative coding to define outcomes and medication exposure introduces misclassification risk. Furthermore, prescribing data from the Australian Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme showed that VED persistence was longer when used as a first-line biological agent in combination with immunomodulators, compared to patients on VED monotherapy (&gt;50.2 vs 40.8 months (95% CI: 10.3–71.3), p = 0.02).  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30403</offset><text>To prevent the potential bias inherent in observational studies, Hudesman et al.   compared combination VED and immunomodulator therapy against VED monotherapy by applying propensity score matching. They found that UC and CD patients treated with combination therapy had significantly higher cumulative 12-month rates of clinical remission (47% vs 30%; HR: 4.1 (95% CI: 1.06–15.90) for UC, and 38% vs 32%; HR: 2.3 (95% CI: 1.12–4.74) for CD).   There were numerically but not statistically significant higher rates of endoscopic healing with combination therapy in UC (54% vs 41%; HR: 1.59 (95% CI: 0.37–6.70)) but comparable rates in CD (43% vs 43%; HR: 1.18 (95% CI: 0.45–2.77)).   While propensity matching enhances comparability between groups, the study may not account for variations in thiopurine dosing, adherence or metabolite levels.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>31255</offset><text>Evidence against combination therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>31292</offset><text>Trial data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31303</offset><text>The pivotal GEMINI 1 trial demonstrated the effectiveness of VED in UC.   Of 374 patients randomised to double-blind placebo or VED as induction treatment, 32% were on concomitant immunomodulator therapy. Rates of clinical response, clinical remission and mucosal healing were numerically higher with VED at weeks 6 and 52, irrespective of immunomodulator co-therapy.   Furthermore, of 368 patients with CD in the GEMINI 2 trial, 34% were on concomitant immunomodulator therapy.   Clinical response and clinical remission were similar for patients on VED, irrespective of immunomodulator use at baseline.   However, these studies were not designed to specifically address the effects of concomitant immunomodulator therapy. Also, concomitant therapy was defined as baseline immunomodulator use; however, patients from the United States had their immunomodulator discontinued at week 6 for patients in the double-blind VED group, or at study entry for open-label VED patients. Nonetheless, there was no significant difference in clinical remission rates between non-US (23.2%) and US (28.9%) patients at week 52.   Additionally, short follow-up for some endpoints reduces the ability to detect differences in outcomes that may require sustained exposure to combination therapy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>32580</offset><text>Real-world data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32596</offset><text>Real-world data have also questioned the added value of immunomodulators. A large retrospective study by Hu et al.   with 549 patients examined clinical, endoscopic and persistence outcomes for patients using VED with or without an immunomodulator. There was no difference in clinical response or remission at week 54 in the combination versus monotherapy groups (78.3% vs 72.9%, p = 0.33).   The proportion of patients with endoscopic response or remaining on VED was similar in combination versus monotherapy groups too.   Importantly, propensity-score matching was used to help overcome the limitations of a retrospective analysis with selection bias. Yzet et al.   performed a meta-analysis examining the effects of immunomodulator therapy with VED and ustekinumab. A total of 16 studies were reviewed for the VED analysis on clinical efficacy, and they found that combination therapy was not associated with superior clinical outcomes compared with monotherapy (OR, 0.84; 95% CI: 0.68–1.05).   However, 10 of 16 (62.5%) of these studies only described baseline immunomodulator use at the initiation of VED, and there were no data as to whether patients continued using an immunomodulator throughout the course of VED.   It is unclear whether immunomodulator use was continued in the remaining studies. As such, similar to GEMINI 1, patients may have had their immunomodulator discontinued at an early time point after VED initiation; however, they were still defined in the combination group. This may not reflect true combination therapy. Furthermore, many studies had short follow-up time periods. At least six of the VED studies had a follow-up period of no more than 14 weeks, despite it being unlikely that a benefit of combination therapy would be found with such limited follow-up duration. However, as pointed out by Yzet et al.,   none of the included studies were designed to primarily analyse the benefit of immunomodulator co-therapy with VED.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>34567</offset><text>Future directions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34585</offset><text>Future work should focus on identifying patient subgroups who would benefit most from VED dose optimisation. Randomised trials specifically targeting secondary non-responders are needed to determine whether dose-escalation improves long-term outcomes, while biomarker and pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic-driven approaches may help distinguish mechanistic failure from modifiable underexposure. The role of immunomodulator co-therapy also requires clarification through prospective studies that ensure consistent thiopurine use with analysis of metabolite levels and incorporate robust safety monitoring. As evidence evolves, these efforts will be crucial to guide the rational use of VED TDM, dose escalation and combination therapy in clinical practice.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>35340</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35351</offset><text>Overall, the available literature on VED pharmacokinetics and immunomodulator co-therapy is heterogeneous, complex and sometimes contradictory. Despite demonstration of a positive exposure–efficacy relationship of VED in initial clinical trials, a lack of consistent pharmacokinetic results from numerous studies thereafter has limited the utilisation of measuring VED trough concentrations in clinical practice. Furthermore, although combining VED with an immunomodulator does not reduce immunogenicity nor increase VED trough concentrations (like with anti-TNFs), recent higher-quality, yet limited studies suggest that patient outcomes may be improved through an additive immunosuppressive effect. Nonetheless, most of the evidence stems from retrospective observational data, introducing bias and impacting on applicability. Further studies specifically designed to assess clinical, biochemical, endoscopic and histologic outcomes of combination VED and immunomodulator versus VED monotherapy, similar to the SONIC study,   are required to definitively answer this question.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36432</offset><text>ORCID iDs: Aviv Pudipeddi  https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3664-2246</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36497</offset><text>Thanaboon Chaemsupaphan  https://orcid.org/0009-0001-3408-7277</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36560</offset><text>Viraj Kariyawasam  https://orcid.org/0000-0003-2623-1336</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36617</offset><text>Rupert W. Leong  https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5944-3488</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>36672</offset><text>Declarations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36685</offset><text>Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36745</offset><text>Consent for publication: Not applicable.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36786</offset><text>Author contributions: Aviv Pudipeddi: Data curation; Supervision; Writing – original draft; Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>36910</offset><text>Thanaboon Chaemsupaphan: Data curation; Writing – original draft; Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37008</offset><text>Arteen Arzivian: Data curation; Writing – original draft.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37068</offset><text>Yong-Sul Kim: Writing – original draft.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37110</offset><text>Sudarshan Paramsothy: Supervision; Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37175</offset><text>Viraj Kariyawasam: Supervision; Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37237</offset><text>Rupert W. Leong: Conceptualisation; Data curation; Supervision; Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37331</offset><text>Funding: The authors received no financial support for the research, authorship and/or publication of this article.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>37447</offset><text>A.P. has received speaking fees from Johnson &amp; Johnson, AbbVie, Takeda, Ferring, Dr Falk Pharma and Pfizer, and has been on advisory board meetings for AbbVie and Takeda. S.P. has received speaker fees from Ferring, Janssen and Takeda. V.K. has been on the advisory board for Takeda and received grants and speaker fees from Takeda. R.W.L. reports advisory board fees from AbbVie, Aspen, Celgene, Ferring, Gilead, Hospira, Janssen, MSD, Pfizer and Takeda; research fees from Endochoice, Janssen, National Health and Medical Research Council of Australia, Shire and Takeda and speaker fees from Emerge Health, Ferring, Janssen, Shire and Takeda.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>38092</offset><text>Availability of data and materials: Not applicable.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>38144</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1756</infon><infon key="issue">10080</infon><infon key="lpage">1770</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ungaro;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mehandru;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Allen;given-names:PB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27914657</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">389</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>38155</offset><text>Ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1741</infon><infon key="issue">10080</infon><infon key="lpage">1755</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Torres;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mehandru;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Colombel;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27914655</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">389</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>38174</offset><text>Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2769</infon><infon key="issue">10114</infon><infon key="lpage">2778</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ng;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shi;given-names:HY</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hamidi;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29050646</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">390</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>38192</offset><text>Worldwide incidence and prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in the 21st century: a systematic review of population-based studies</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">365</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">370</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kariyawasam;given-names:V</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33502004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Med J Aust</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">214</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>38326</offset><text>Higher prevalence of Crohn disease and ulcerative colitis among older people in Sydney</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1437</infon><infon key="issue">12</infon><infon key="lpage">1444</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wyant;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fedyk;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Abhyankar;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27252400</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>38413</offset><text>An overview of the mechanism of action of the monoclonal antibody vedolizumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">79</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">80</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kobayashi;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hibi;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36635556</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>38491</offset><text>Improving IBD outcomes in the era of many treatment options</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2482</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">2490</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Battat;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dulai;given-names:PS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jairath;given-names:V</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30897022</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Hum Vaccin Immunother</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>38551</offset><text>A product review of vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">699</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">710</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Feagan;given-names:BG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rutgeerts;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sands;given-names:BE</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23964932</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">369</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>38613</offset><text>Vedolizumab as induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sandborn;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Baert;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Danese;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">158</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>38685</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of vedolizumab subcutaneous formulation in a randomized controlled trial of patients with ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">711</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">721</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sandborn;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Feagan;given-names:BG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rutgeerts;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23964933</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">369</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>38814</offset><text>Vedolizumab as induction and maintenance therapy for Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">27</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">38</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vermiere;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:D’Haens;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Baert;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34402887</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>38885</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of subcutaneous vedolizumab in patients with moderately to severely active Crohn’s disease: results from the VISIBLE 2 randomized trial</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">430</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">435</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nassar;given-names:IO</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cheesbrough;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Quraishi;given-names:MN</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36051956</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontline Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>39043</offset><text>Proposed pathway for therapeutic drug monitoring and dose escalation of vedolizumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1037</infon><infon key="issue">11–12</infon><infon key="lpage">1053</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mitrev;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vande Casteele;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Seow;given-names:CH</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29027257</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>39127</offset><text>Review article: consensus statements on therapeutic drug monitoring of anti-tumour necrosis factor therapy in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1291</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1299</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vermiere;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dreesen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Papamichael;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31589978</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>39264</offset><text>How, when, and for whom should we perform therapeutic drug monitoring?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">522</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">552</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rodríguez-Moranta;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Argüelles-Arias;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Del Val;given-names:JH</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38311005</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">47</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>39335</offset><text>Therapeutic drug monitoring in inflammatory bowel diseases. Position statement of the Spanish Working Group on Crohn’s Disease and Ulcerative Colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Papamichael;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cheifetz;given-names:AS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Melmed;given-names:GY</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>39487</offset><text>Appropriate therapeutic drug monitoring of biologic agents for patients with inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Colombel;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Adedokun;given-names:OJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gasink;given-names:C</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>39592</offset><text>Combination therapy with infliximab and azathioprine improves infliximab pharmacokinetic features and efficacy: a post-hoc analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">accessed 02 February 2025</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wells;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shea;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:O’Connell;given-names:D</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>39724</offset><text>The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">921</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">929</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rosario;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:French;given-names:JL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dirks;given-names:NL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28333288</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>39825</offset><text>Exposure–efficacy relationships for vedolizumab induction therapy in patients with ulcerative colitis or Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">408</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">418</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osterman;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rosario;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lasch;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30663076</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>39950</offset><text>Vedolizumab exposure levels and clinical outcomes in ulcerative colitis: determining the potential for dose optimization</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">689</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">699</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hanzel;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dreesen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Vermiere;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>40071</offset><text>Pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic model of vedolizumab for targeting endoscopic remission in patients with Crohn disease: posthoc analysis of the LOVE-CD study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">95</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">105</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Okamoto;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dirks;given-names:NL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rosario;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32635680</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Intest Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>40229</offset><text>Population pharmacokinetics of vedolizumab in Asian and non-Asian patients with ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">188</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">202</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rosario;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dirks;given-names:NL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gastonguay;given-names:MR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25996351</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>40350</offset><text>Population pharmacokinetics-pharmacodynamics of vedolizumab in patients with ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">Suppl. 1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dreesen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Verstockt;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Vermiere;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>40468</offset><text>A population pharmacokinetic model to support therapeutic drug monitoring during vedolizumab therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2299</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">2308</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Paramsothy;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kariyawasam;given-names:V</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38729400</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>40569</offset><text>Effects of thiopurine withdrawal on vedolizumab-treated patients with ulcerative colitis: a randomized controlled trial</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">101292</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chaemsupaphan;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lin;given-names:H-Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39811508</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>40689</offset><text>Vedolizumab serum trough concentrations with and without thiopurines in ulcerative colitis: the prospective VIEWS pharmacokinetics study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2908</infon><infon key="issue">11</infon><infon key="lpage">2917</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yarur;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McGovern;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Abreu;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36280102</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>40826</offset><text>Combination therapy with immunomodulators improves the pharmacokinetics of infliximab but not vedolizumab or Ustekinumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1059</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1067</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schwartz;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Peyrin-Biroulet;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lasch;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34597729</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>40947</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of 2 Vedolizumab intravenous regimens for perianal fistulizing Crohn’s disease: ENTERPRISE study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">63</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="lpage">71</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Outtier;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wauters;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rahier;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">GastroHep</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>41066</offset><text>Effect of vedolizumab dose intensification on serum drug concentrations and regain of response in inflammatory bowel disease patients with secondary loss of response</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">838</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">846</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Peyrin-Biroulet;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Danese;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Argollo;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29935327</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>41232</offset><text>Loss of response to vedolizumab and ability of dose intensification to restore response in patients with Crohn’s disease or ulcerative colitis: a systematic review and meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1077</infon><infon key="issue">5</infon><infon key="lpage">1086</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jairath;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yarur;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Osterman;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37951560</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>41416</offset><text>ENTERPRET: a randomized controlled trial of vedolizumab dose optimization in patients with ulcerative colitis who have early nonresponse</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">963</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">969</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ungaro;given-names:RC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yarur;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jossen;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31087100</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>41553</offset><text>Higher trough vedolizumab concentrations during maintenance therapy are associated with corticosteroid-free remission in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1189</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">1197</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Guidi;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pugliese;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tonucci;given-names:TP</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">United European Gastroenterol J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>41701</offset><text>Early vedolizumab trough levels predict treatment persistence over the first year in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">478</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">485</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liefferinckx;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Minsart;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cremer;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30672828</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">31</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>41813</offset><text>Early vedolizumab trough levels at induction in inflammatory bowel disease patients with treatment failure during maintenance</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">463</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">476</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vande Casteele;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sandborn;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Feagan;given-names:BG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35474325</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>41939</offset><text>Real-world multicentre observational study including population pharmacokinetic modelling to evaluate the exposure–response relationship of vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease: ERELATE study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1088</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1098</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Steenholdt;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lorentsen;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Petersen;given-names:PN</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38380724</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>42138</offset><text>Therapeutic drug monitoring of vedolizumab therapy in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">580</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">586</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Al-Bawardy;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ramos;given-names:GP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Willrich;given-names:MAV</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30165638</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>42219</offset><text>Vedolizumab drug level correlation with clinical remission, biomarker normalization, and mucosal healing in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">972</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sivridaş;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Creemers;given-names:RH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wong;given-names:DR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36986833</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pharmaceutics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>42354</offset><text>Therapeutic drug monitoring of vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease patients during maintenance treatment-TUMMY study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">906</infon><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="lpage">912</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yacoub;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Williet;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pouillon;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29384209</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">47</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>42477</offset><text>Early vedolizumab trough levels predict mucosal healing in inflammatory bowel disease: a multicentre prospective observational study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1651</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1659</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yarur;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bruss;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Naik;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30835029</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Dis Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">64</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>42610</offset><text>Vedolizumab concentrations are associated with long-term endoscopic remission in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3563</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">3569</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yarur;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Deepak;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Vande Casteele;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33089483</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Dis Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>42733</offset><text>Association between vedolizumab levels, anti-vedolizumab antibodies, and endoscopic healing index in a large population of patients with inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">970</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">975</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pouillon;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rousseau;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Busby-Venner;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30698684</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>42898</offset><text>Vedolizumab trough levels and histological healing during maintenance therapy in ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">12</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dreesen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Verstockt;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bian;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>42998</offset><text>Evidence to support monitoring of vedolizumab trough concentrations in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">848</infon><infon key="issue">8</infon><infon key="lpage">857</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Singh;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dulai;given-names:PS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Vande Casteele;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31483522</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>43111</offset><text>Systematic review with meta-analysis: association between vedolizumab trough concentration and clinical outcomes in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">403</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">412</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:D’Haens;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rosario;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Polhamus;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38441048</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>43269</offset><text>Exposure–efficacy relationship of vedolizumab subcutaneous and intravenous formulations in Crohn’s disease and ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1383</infon><infon key="lpage">1395</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Colombel;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sandborn;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Reinisch;given-names:W</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20393175</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">362</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>43403</offset><text>Infliximab, azathioprine or combination therapy for Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2879</infon><infon key="issue">12</infon><infon key="lpage">2885</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shelton;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Allegretti;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stevens;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26288002</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>43473</offset><text>Efficacy of vedolizumab as induction therapy in refractory IBD patients: a multicenter cohort</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1299</infon><infon key="issue">12</infon><infon key="lpage">1304</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lenti;given-names:MV</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Levison;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Eliadou;given-names:E</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30077465</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Liver Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>43567</offset><text>A real-world, long-term experience on effectiveness and safety of vedolizumab in adult patients with inflammatory bowel disease: the Cross Pennine study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1199</infon><infon key="issue">11–12</infon><infon key="lpage">1212</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stallmach;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Langbein;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Atreya;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27714831</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>43720</offset><text>Vedolizumab provides clinical benefit over 1 year in patients with active inflammatory bowel disease – a prospective multicenter observational study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1090</infon><infon key="issue">10</infon><infon key="lpage">1102</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Baumgart;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bokemayer;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drabik;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27038247</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>43873</offset><text>Vedolizumab induction therapy for inflammatory bowel disease in clinical practice – a nationwide consecutive German cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">404</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">408</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kopylov;given-names:U</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ron;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Avni-Biron;given-names:I</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28178003</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>44004</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of vedolizumab for induction of remission in inflammatory bowel disease – the Israeli real-world experience</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">196</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">202</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Samaan;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pavlidis;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Johnston;given-names:E</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28839909</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontline Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>44134</offset><text>Vedolizumab: early experience and medium-term outcomes from two UK tertiary IBD centres</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">722</infon><infon key="issue">6–7</infon><infon key="lpage">729</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eriksson;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Marsal;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bergemalm;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28362144</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Scand J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">52</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>44222</offset><text>Long-term effectiveness of vedolizumab in inflammatory bowel disease: a national study based on the Swedish National Quality Registry for Inflammatory Bowel Disease (SWIBERG)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1590</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="lpage">1596</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Allegreti;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Barnes;given-names:EL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stevens;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28357697</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Dis Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>44397</offset><text>Predictors of clinical response and remission at 1 year among a multicenter cohort of patients with inflammatory bowel disease treated with vedolizumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">310</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="lpage">321</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Amiot;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Serrero;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Peyrin-Biroulet;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28593685</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>44551</offset><text>One-year effectiveness and safety of vedolizumab therapy for inflammatory bowel disease: a prospective multicenter cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hu;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kotze;given-names:PG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Burgevin;given-names:A</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>44679</offset><text>Combination therapy does not improve rate of clinical or endoscopic remission in patients with inflammatory bowel disease treated with vedolizumab or ustekinumab</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1781</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="lpage">1789</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kirchgesner;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Desai;given-names:RJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schneeweiss;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35387877</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">71</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>44841</offset><text>Decreased risk of treatment failure with vedolizumab and thiopurines combined compared with vedolizumab monotherapy in Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">81</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="lpage">88</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Naganuma;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Watanabe;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Motoya;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34409654</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>44978</offset><text>Potential benefits of immunomodulator use with vedolizumab for maintenance of remission in ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">430</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">436</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jeffrey;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Picardo;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Menon;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37396006</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>45088</offset><text>Combination therapy is not associated with improved rates of clinical or endoscopic remission in patients with inflammatory bowel disease treated with ustekinumab or vedolizumab: a retrospective study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1307</infon><infon key="issue">7</infon><infon key="lpage">1343</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Singh;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Loftus;given-names:EV;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Limketkai;given-names:BN</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39572132</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">167</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>45289</offset><text>AGA living clinical practice guideline on pharmacological management of moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ko;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Paramsothy;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ther Adv Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>45399</offset><text>Vedolizumab has longer persistence than infliximab as a first-line biological agent but not as a second-line biological agent in moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis: real-world registry data from the Persistence Australian National IBD Cohort (PANIC) study</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">Suppl. 1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hudesman;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chang;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shashi;given-names:P</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>45658</offset><text>Impact of concomitant immunomodulator use on vedolizumab effectiveness: a multicentre consortium propensity score-matched analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">Suppl. 1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Colombel;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Loftus;given-names:EV;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Siegel;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>45789</offset><text>Efficacy of vedolizumab with concomitant corticosteroid or immunomodulator use in patients with ulcerative colitis from GEMINI 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">Suppl. 1</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Colombel;given-names:J-F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Loftus;given-names:EV;suffix:Jr</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Siegel;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>45918</offset><text>Efficacy of vedolizumab with concomitant corticosteroid or immunomodulator use in patients with Crohn’s disease from GEMINI 2</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Feagan;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Siegel;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Melmed;given-names:G</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">110</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>46046</offset><text>Efficacy of vedolizumab maintenance therapy with and without combined immunosuppressant use in GEMINI 1 and GEMINI 2</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">668</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="lpage">679</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yzet;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Diouf;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Singh;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32629124</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>46163</offset><text>No benefit of concomitant immunomodulator therapy on efficacy of biologics that are not tumor necrosis factor antagonists in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pudipeddi;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Paramsothy;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Leong;given-names:RW.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>46346</offset><text>Combination therapy of immunomodulators with non-anti-tumor necrosis factor agents in inflammatory bowel disease: need more evidence?</text></passage></document>
</collection>