<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260212</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12850869</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC-ND</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1016/j.igie.2025.07.005</infon><infon key="article-id_pii">S2949-7086(25)00081-0</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12850869</infon><infon key="def">Crohn’s disease inflammatory bowel disease ulcerative colitis</infon><infon key="fpage">355</infon><infon key="issue">4</infon><infon key="license">This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</infon><infon key="lpage">358</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:Shanshan</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shen;given-names:Bo</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="term">CD IBD UC</infon><infon key="title">Abbreviations</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Resolution of severe ulcerative colitis–associated benign stricture with combined vedolizumab and endoscopic stricturotomy: a case report</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>140</offset><text>Ulcerative colitis (UC)-associated strictures, although infrequent, are complex to treat and often prompt surgical resection as a result of concerns about underlying malignancy. However, benign strictures resulting from the inflammation-induced fibrosis represent an important and underaddressed clinical scenario. Although endoscopic stricture therapy is well-established in Crohn’s disease–associated strictures, its use in UC has not been described in the literature, to our knowledge. We report a case of a benign colonic stricture in a UC patient after a severe flare who achieved clinical remission with vedolizumab. Endoscopic stricturotomy was performed, resulting in sustained luminal patency over a 2-year follow-up period. Serial biopsies showed no dysplasia. The patient remained in clinical and endoscopic remission. This case suggests that combined medical and endoscopic therapy may promote the resolution of UC-associated benign strictures.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1101</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1114</offset><text>Colonic strictures in patients with ulcerative colitis (UC) are uncommon (1%-11%) compared with patients with Crohn’s disease (CD), in which one-third develop stricturing disease within a decade. Managing UC-associated strictures, whether benign or malignant, is challenging. Historically, surgery has been the primary approach, especially when malignancy was suspected. With the advent of biologic therapies, benign UC-associated strictures are increasingly encountered, with the most common sites being the anorectal ring and rectosigmoid junctions, suggesting that factors other than inflammation contribute to stricture formation. The efficacy of biologics and small molecules for benign UC-associated strictures remains unclear. The endoscopic approach has been extensively explored in CD-associated strictures. Both endoscopic balloon dilation and endoscopic stricturotomy are routinely used for primary or anastomotic strictures. Endoscopic stricturotomy demonstrated a technical success rate of 100%, with subsequent surgery required in 15.4% of cases involving primary strictures and 11.3% for anastomotic strictures. However, the therapeutic role of endoscopic stricturotomy in UC-associated strictures is yet undefined. We report a case of longstanding UC with a mixed inflammatory and fibrotic colonic stricture successfully treated with vedolizumab and endoscopic stricturotomy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CASE</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2508</offset><text>Case description</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CASE</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2525</offset><text>A 20-year-old woman with no relevant medical, family, or social history was diagnosed with ulcerative pancolitis at the age of 9 years. She was referred to our institution for evaluation of a colonic stricture. There was no first-degree family history of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) or colorectal cancer. Her previous treatments included sulfasalazine, corticosteroids, and infliximab, the latter of which was discontinued because of drug-induced psoriasis. She started vedolizumab infusion every 8 weeks in 2018 and initially responded but had a steroid-refractory flare in 2020, with colonoscopy revealing severe activity. In response, the vedolizumab dose was escalated to every 4 weeks, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy was added. The patient gradually experienced clinical improvement. Tofacitinib had been briefly added to taper corticosteroids. Colonoscopy in 2021 showed endoscopic response with moderate left-sided colitis and mild rectal inflammation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>3489</offset><text>Computed tomography scan in 2021. Luminal narrowing (black arrow) in the descending colon.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CASE</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3580</offset><text>Despite the patient achieving clinical remission, fecal calprotectin levels were elevated at 2390 μg/g (normal &lt;50 μg/g), although C-reactive protein levels were undetectable. She reported no obstructive symptoms. Findings on physical examination were unremarkable. In 2022, a new colonoscopy examination identified a nontraversable stricture in the descending colon 40 cm from the anal verge with moderate inflammation and postinflammatory polyps. Biopsies showed chronic, moderately active colitis without dysplasia. Computed tomography confirmed the stricture location and segmental wall thickening in the left side of the colon without prestenotic luminal dilation or malignancy (Fig. 1).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr2.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4275</offset><text>A benign-appearing, intrinsic, nonulcerated, mixed inflammatory and fibrotic primary stricture (5 mm in inner diameter, 20 mm in length) in the descending colon.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr3.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4437</offset><text>Endoscopic stricturotomy with insulated-tip knife cut in a circumferential fashion (dashed black circle).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr4.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4543</offset><text>Colonic stricture after endoscopic stricturotomy, traversable with pediatric colonoscope.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr5.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4633</offset><text>Previously treated stricture 2 years later in chromoendoscopy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr6.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig6</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4696</offset><text>Widely patent treated stricture, mucosal scars (arrows), and small postinflammatory polyps (arrowheads) seen on follow-up colonoscopy at 2 years.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gr7.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig7</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>4842</offset><text>Surveillance colonoscopy 2 years later with narrow-band imaging. Normal pit pattern and vascular structure were observed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CASE</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4964</offset><text>Two months later, a repeat colonoscopy at our center revealed a benign-appearing and mixed inflammatory-fibrotic stricture that was not traversable with a pediatric colonoscope (PCF-H190DL; Olympus America, Center Valley, Pa, USA). Endoscopic stricturotomy was successfully performed using an insulated-tip knife (Olympus America) in a radial fashion at 0-, 3-, 6-, and 9-o'clock orientation to avoid a large area of delayed ulcers. Afterward, the colonoscope passed without resistance (Figure 2, Figure 3, Figure 4). Segmental biopsies, including those from the stricture site, showed no dysplasia. No postprocedure adverse events, including bleeding and perforation, were reported. Annual colonoscopies through 2025 demonstrated disease remission, with the previous stricture site remaining widely patent (Figure 5, Figure 6, Figure 7). Chromoendoscopy and extensive biopsies continued to show no evidence of dysplasia. During follow-up, the patient remained asymptomatic on vedolizumab infusions and expressed satisfaction with the minimally invasive approach.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>6028</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6039</offset><text>Strictures in UC are relatively infrequent, and their presence raises concerns about neoplastic transformation, with malignancy reported in approximately 3.5%. Diagnosing dysplasia or cancer in UC-associated strictures is challenging, as their absence on biopsy does not entirely exclude cancer. Historically, UC strictures are considered malignant unless proven otherwise, necessitating serial endoscopic surveillance with deep biopsies. However, benign UC-associated strictures are increasingly recognized, and their management is yet undefined.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6587</offset><text>The pathophysiology of colonic fibrosis is complex. Inflammation-induced fibrosis may persist after inflammation resolves. Although UC was traditionally thought to be confined to the mucosa, recent studies revealed submucosal fibrosis and muscularis mucosae thickening, which may explain clinical manifestations such as motility abnormalities, anorectal dysfunction, rectal urgency, and incontinence.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6988</offset><text>IBD-related strictures are classified as inflammatory or fibrotic. Inflammatory strictures often respond to medical therapies, but fibrotic strictures usually require endoscopic or surgical intervention. In clinical practice, most strictures exhibit mixed features. No antifibrotic agents are currently approved for IBD. In studies such as A Crohn's Disease Clinical Trial Evaluating Infliximab in a New Long-Term Treatment Regimen (ACCENT I) and the evaluation of adalimumab in patients with Crohn's disease and symptomatic small-bowel stricture (CREOLE study), investigators have evaluated the efficacy in fibrostenosing CD. In contrast, the therapeutic role of biological agents and endoscopic stricturotomy for UC strictures remains underexplored. A case report described the resolution of a UC-associated stricture with ustekinumab. To date, to our knowledge, no literature has evaluated the impact of vedolizumab on IBD-associated strictures. Our case is the first to report a UC-associated stricture successfully reversed through a combination of medical and interventional therapies, with sustained resolution over 2.3 years of follow-up, to our knowledge. These findings provide valuable insights into the management of benign UC-related strictures and suggest that surgical resection may be avoidable in select cases, provided malignancy is carefully excluded. Radiologic evaluation, such as computed tomography enterography, magnetic resonance enterography, or intestinal ultrasound, might aid in differentiating inflammatory from fibrotic components—an approach widely validated in CD-related strictures, with few data reported in UC-associated strictures. The authors' group used the functional luminal imaging probe to assess lower gastrointestinal strictures, given that the distensibility measurements may reflect the degree of fibrosis. Endoscopic stricturotomy was delivered, despite the patient being asymptomatic, to evaluate the colon proximal to the stricture and to prevent potential obstruction, as the consensus guideline from the Global Interventional IBD Group recommended. Although the relative contribution of each treatment modality to the stricture resolution is unclear, we believe that endoscopic stricturotomy played a main role in reducing luminal narrowing and modifying both inflammatory and fibrotic components of the stricture. With adequate inflammatory control of the bowel from vedolizumab, this combined approach ultimately led to stricture resolution. However, as this represents a single case, further case series or case-control studies are warranted to confirm our findings.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9612</offset><text>In summary, we report a case of sustained resolution of a colonic stricture treated with vedolizumab and endoscopic stricturotomy, suggesting an alternative approach for UC-associated benign strictures.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>9815</offset><text>Patient consent</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9831</offset><text>The patient in this article has given written informed consent to publication of their case details.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>9932</offset><text>Disclosure</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9943</offset><text>The following authors disclosed financial relationships: B. Shen: Consultant for and research and education grants from Janssen and research/education grants from AbbVie, Takeda, and GIE Medical. The other author disclosed no financial relationships.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>10194</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2198</infon><infon key="lpage">2206</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gordon;given-names:I.O.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Agrawal;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Goldblum;given-names:J.R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24892966</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>10205</offset><text>Fibrosis in ulcerative colitis: mechanisms, features, and consequences of a neglected problem</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2194</infon><infon key="lpage">2213</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bharadwaj;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fleshner;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shen;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25985249</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>10299</offset><text>Therapeutic armamentarium for stricturing Crohnʼs disease: medical versus endoscopic versus surgical approaches</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">295</infon><infon key="lpage">314</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shen;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Abreu;given-names:M.T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cohen;given-names:E.R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39425706</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastrointest Endosc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">101</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>10412</offset><text>Endoscopic diagnosis and management of adult inflammatory bowel disease: a consensus document from the American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy IBD Endoscopy Consensus Panel</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1770</infon><infon key="lpage">1775</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fumery;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pineton De Chambrun;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stefanescu;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26001338</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>10593</offset><text>Detection of dysplasia or cancer in 3.5% of patients with inflammatory bowel disease and colonic strictures</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">922</infon><infon key="lpage">939</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gordon;given-names:I.O.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Agrawal;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Willis;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29411405</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">47</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>10701</offset><text>Fibrosis in ulcerative colitis is directly linked to severity and chronicity of mucosal inflammation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1030</infon><infon key="lpage">1038</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lichtenstein;given-names:G.R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Olson;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Travers;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16606351</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">101</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>10802</offset><text>Factors associated with the development of intestinal strictures or obstructions in patients with Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">53</infon><infon key="lpage">60</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bouhnik;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carbonnel;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Laharie;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28119352</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>10918</offset><text>Efficacy of adalimumab in patients with Crohn’s disease and symptomatic small bowel stricture: a multicentre, prospective, observational cohort (CREOLE) study</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Guo;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Liu;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Medicine (Baltimore)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">101</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>11079</offset><text>Ustekinumab is effective against ulcerative colitis with intestinal stenosis: a case report</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Choy;given-names:A.M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pomenti;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Katzka;given-names:D.A.</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ACG Case Rep J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>11171</offset><text>Novel use of EndoFLIP to characterize Kock pouch stricture before and after endoscopic intervention</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">393</infon><infon key="lpage">405</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shen;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kochhar;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Navaneethan;given-names:U.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31954438</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>11271</offset><text>Practical guidelines on endoscopic treatment for Crohn’s disease strictures: a consensus statement from the Global Interventional Inflammatory Bowel Disease Group</text></passage></document>
</collection>