<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260212</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12884852</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1093/jcag/gwaf030</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12884852</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">gwaf030</infon><infon key="fpage">24</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="kwd">inflammatory bowel disease Crohn’s disease ulcerative colitis telemedicine COVID-19</infon><infon key="license">This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/), which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site—for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</infon><infon key="lpage">29</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nguyen;given-names:Luke J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:Vivian</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Habashi;given-names:Peter</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gao;given-names:Yiding</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Tandon;given-names:Parul</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Patterns of specialist healthcare delivery among inflammatory bowel disease patients in response to the COVID-19 pandemic in Ontario: a population-based study</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>159</offset><text>Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>168</offset><text>Background</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>179</offset><text>Access to inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD) specialist care is a predictor of health outcomes. We sought to characterize the impact of the pandemic on patterns of IBD healthcare delivery and whether it compromised overall access to care.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>417</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>425</offset><text>We identified adults with an IBD diagnosis residing in Ontario between 2016 and 2021 using administrative data at ICES. We determined quarterly rates of in-person and virtual IBD specialist visits and stratified that by regions with high and low access to IBD specialists. We stratified our analyses into 3 periods: pre-COVID, immediate COVID, and maintenance COVID. We performed interrupted time series analysis to assess for time trends.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>865</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>873</offset><text>During the immediate COVID phase, there was a 69% relative quarterly decline in in-person IBD specialist visits with a concurrent 591% relative quarterly rise in rates of virtual visits. Entering the COVID maintenance phase, there was a 7% quarterly relative decline in the rate of in-person visits, and a 7% and 4% quarterly relative increases in the rates of virtual and total IBD specialist visits, respectively. Pre-pandemic, IBD patients residing in regions with high specialist access had a 16% higher rate of visits than those in low-access regions. During the COVID maintenance phase, the disparity was reduced to 12%.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1500</offset><text>Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1512</offset><text>During the COVID-19 pandemic, the rapid transition from in-person to virtual IBD specialist care led to a slight increase in overall IBD visits. There was also a small decrease in the gap in rates of IBD specialist visits between high- and low-access regions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1772</offset><text>Graphical Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1791</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1804</offset><text>The inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD), which include Crohn’s disease (CD) and ulcerative colitis (UC), are chronic and relapsing gastrointestinal conditions arising from dysregulation of the gut immune system. Specialist care early in the disease course has been shown to improve patient outcomes. Moreover, access to specialist care is an important social determinant of IBD health. Geographic disparities in availability of gastroenterologists have been well-documented in Ontario and have been associated with outcomes such as increased emergency department visits. A province-wide pilot program has shown that virtual care can shorten wait times and improve access to specialist care. Virtual delivery of healthcare was, however, administered through the Ontario Telemedicine Network (OTN) and subject to provider restrictions that limited its scope. During the COVID-19 pandemic, severe restrictions to in-person physician visits prompted relaxation of criteria for the delivery of virtual care, allowing reimbursement to all licensed physicians for virtual care services regardless of the format (phone or video) and software platform. These changes enabled the rapid and widespread deployment of virtual care services.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3032</offset><text>The aims of our study were to characterize time trends in delivery of in-person and virtual care for IBD patients in Ontario before and after the COVID-19 pandemic. We assessed whether COVID-19 impacted access to IBD specialist care, especially in remote geographic regions of Ontario that were already known to be underserved by gastroenterologists.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>3383</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>3391</offset><text>Data sources</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3404</offset><text>We accessed routinely collected health administrative data collected and maintained by ICES. These datasets contain health records from more than 99% of Ontario’s 13.4 million residents. The specific databases used for his analysis include: the Ontario Health Insurance Plan (OHIP), the Registered Person’s Database (RPDB), the Canadian Institute for Health Information Discharge Abstract Database (CIHI-DAD), the National Ambulatory Care Reporting Service (NACRS), and the ICES Physician Database (IPDB). These databases have been previously described and are linked together by a unique encoded identifier.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4017</offset><text>Study population</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4034</offset><text>The study cohort consisted of all prevalent cases of IBD between April 1, 2016 and March 31, 2021, who were 18 years and older as identified in the Ontario Crohn’s and Colitis Cohort (OCCC). The OCCC is a regularly updated database of IBD patients created using a validated algorithm based on IBD diagnosis codes identified in ICES databases. The algorithm requires 5 physician contacts or hospitalizations for IBD-specific codes within 4 years and has a sensitivity of 92%, specificity of 99%, and positive predictive value of 81%. The OCCC is considered a population-based cohort that includes all individuals in Ontario diagnosed with IBD. It provides an accurate representation of IBD care and outcomes across the entire province, including both urban and rural populations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4819</offset><text>Predictor variables</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4839</offset><text>The main predictor variable was calendar time divided into 24 quarters (ie, 3-month periods) between April 1, 2016, and March 31, 2021. The ascertainment period was further divided into the following periods pre-COVID (March 31, 2016–December 31, 2019), immediate COVID (January 1, 2020–September 30, 2020), and maintenance COVID (October 1, 2020–March 31, 2021).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5209</offset><text>Each individual in the study cohort was linked to one of Ontario’s 14 geographic regions, called local health integration networks (LHINs) based on linkage to their residential address in the RPDB. Individuals were categorized as residing in geographic areas with low specialist access if they resided in LHINs 1, 12, 13, and 14 as described in our previous study. All other subjects were categorized as residing in high-access regions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5648</offset><text>Outcome variables</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5666</offset><text>The outcomes for this study were rates of in-person, virtual, and total IBD specialist visits. An IBD specialist visit was identified as any ambulatory clinic visit with a diagnosis code of 555 or 556 in OHIP with a gastroenterologist. We excluded IBD-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits identified by OHIP codes associated with those types of visits. Gastroenterology specialist designation was ascertained by linkage to the IPDB and identified by the specialty code for gastroenterology (41) or internal medicine (13) if the provider performed more than 50 colonoscopies per year. Inflammatory bowel disease specialist visits were further categorized as in-person or virtual based on if the primary service code had an associated code for virtual care (B100, B200, B203, K081, K082, K083, K300, K301).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>6491</offset><text>Statistical analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6512</offset><text>Aggregate rates of IBD specialist visits were determined by analysts at ICES. For each LHIN, the number of total, in-person, and virtual IBD specialist visits was divided by the total number of adult individuals with IBD living in that specific region for every quarter of calendar time during the study period. Rates of IBD specialist visits were also determined for low and high regions of specialist access.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6923</offset><text>Interrupted time series analysis was performed to determine time trends in rates of total, in-person, and virtual visits in the pre-COVID, immediate COVID, and maintenance COVID periods. Because Poisson regression demonstrated overdispersion, generalized negative binomial regression was used to determine a relative change in incidence rate per quarter as expressed by the incidence rate ratio with 95% confidence intervals. Covariates in the model included time (measured in quarters) and regional access to care (high vs. low). Interaction terms were constructed between time (measured in quarters) and time period (pre-COVID, immediate COVID, and maintenance COVID) and between regional access and time period. Robust variance estimators were used to account for clustering and for autocorrelation of time.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7734</offset><text>Ethics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7741</offset><text>ICES is a prescribed entity under section 45 of Ontario’s Personal Health Information Protection Act. Section 45 authorizes ICES to collect personal health information, without consent, for the purpose of analysis or compiling statistical information with respect to the management, evaluation or monitoring of the allocation of resources to the government-funded health system. Projects conducted under section 45, by definition, do not require review by a Research Ethics Board. This project was conducted under section 45 and approved by ICES’ Privacy and Compliance Office.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>8323</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8331</offset><text>There were 92 090 individuals in the IBD cohort at the beginning of the study period in 2016. The mean age (±SD) of the IBD cohort was 50.9 (16.4) years, and 52% were female. Forty-4% of the cohort had a diagnosis of CD and 55% had a diagnosis of UC. The mean age at diagnosis (±SD) was 38.2 (±15.9) years. Eleven percent of those in the cohort resided in rural regions, and 17% lived in geographic regions with low access to specialists. Twenty-four percent of the cohort resided within neighborhoods that were in the top income quintile, while 16% resided in neighborhoods in the bottom quintile. During the Pre-COVID period, the vast majority of IBD specialist visits (&gt;95%) were in-person.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9028</offset><text>Time trends</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9040</offset><text>At the beginning of the study period in 2016, the number of in-person IBD specialist visits per quarter was 292 visits per 1000 IBD capita. The rate of virtual IBD specialist visits per quarter was 0.6 per 1000 IBD capita. During the pre-COVID period, there was a gradual quarterly 0.07% relative decrease in in-person visits and a 0.06% relative decline in total IBD specialist visits (Figure 1). There was a 14% relative increase in rates of virtual IBD specialist visits per quarter (Table 1). At the onset of COVID-19, there was an abrupt change in the first three quarters of 2020. There was a rapid 69% relative decline in rates of in-person IBD specialist visits per quarter during the immediate COVID period. There was a coinciding 591% relative quarterly increase in rates of virtual IBD specialist visits. The total number of IBD specialist visits, including both in-person and virtual visits, increased by 3%, relatively, each quarter in the immediate COVID phase. Entering the COVID maintenance phase, there was a 7% quarterly relative decline in the rate of in-person IBD specialist visits (incidence rate ratio [IRR], 0.93; 95% CI, 0.87-0.99). The rates of virtual and total IBD specialist visits increased by 7% (IRR, 1.07; 95% CI, 1.05-1.09) and 4% (IRR, 1.04; 95% CI, 1.02-1.04), respectively, each quarter. By the end of the COVID maintenance phase in the final quarter of 2020, the rate of in-person IBD specialist visits was 61 per 1000 IBD capita, while that for virtual IBD specialist visits was 233 per 1000 IBD capita.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf030f1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf030-F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>10583</offset><text>Time trends in utilization of IBD specialist care by type (in-person vs. virtual) and level of regional access (high vs. low) during the pre-COVID, immediate COVID, and maintenance COVID phases.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf030-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf030-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>10778</offset><text>Time series analysis of relative incidence rate for IBD specialist visits.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf030-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf030-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;3&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Incidence rate ratio (95% CI)&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Type of IBD specialist visit&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Pre-COVID&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Immediate COVID-19 Response&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Maintenance COVID-19 period&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Apr 1, 2016-Dec 30, 2019&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Jan 1, 2020-Sep 30, 2020&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Oct 1, 2020-March 31, 2021&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;In-person visits&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Quarterly time trend&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.993 (0.988-0.999)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.306 (0.175-0.534)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.927 (0.865-0.994)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Regional access&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  Low&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  High&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.18 (1.13-1.23)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.17 (0.51-2.66)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.10 (0.97-1.25)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Virtual visits&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Quarterly time trend&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.14 (1.10-1.17)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.91 (4.58-10.41)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.07 (1.05-1.09)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Regional access&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  Low&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  High&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.14 (0.11-0.17)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.07 (1.05-1.09)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.13 (1.10-1.16)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;All visits&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Quarterly time trend&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.994 (0.989-0.999)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.032 (1.004-1.061)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.037 (1.024-1.051)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Regional access&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  Low&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ref&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;  High&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.16 (1.11-1.21)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.12 (1.05-1.19)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.12 (1.09-1.16)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>10853</offset><text>	Incidence rate ratio (95% CI)	 	Type of IBD specialist visit	Pre-COVID	Immediate COVID-19 Response	Maintenance COVID-19 period	 		Apr 1, 2016-Dec 30, 2019	Jan 1, 2020-Sep 30, 2020	Oct 1, 2020-March 31, 2021	 	In-person visits				 	 Quarterly time trend	0.993 (0.988-0.999)	0.306 (0.175-0.534)	0.927 (0.865-0.994)	 	 Regional access				 	  Low	Ref	Ref	Ref	 	  High	1.18 (1.13-1.23)	1.17 (0.51-2.66)	1.10 (0.97-1.25)	 	Virtual visits				 	 Quarterly time trend	1.14 (1.10-1.17)	6.91 (4.58-10.41)	1.07 (1.05-1.09)	 	 Regional access				 	  Low	Ref	Ref	Ref	 	  High	0.14 (0.11-0.17)	1.07 (1.05-1.09)	1.13 (1.10-1.16)	 	All visits				 	 Quarterly time trend	0.994 (0.989-0.999)	1.032 (1.004-1.061)	1.037 (1.024-1.051)	 	 Regional access				 	  Low	Ref	Ref	Ref	 	  High	1.16 (1.11-1.21)	1.12 (1.05-1.19)	1.12 (1.09-1.16)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11708</offset><text>Geographic access to specialist care</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11745</offset><text>In the pre-COVID period, crude rate of total IBD specialist visits (either in-person or virtual) was 255 per 1000 IBD capita in regions of low specialist access and 300 per 1000 IBD capita in regions of high access. Those residing in regions with high access to specialists were 16% more likely to have an IBD specialist visit (either virtual or in-person) than someone residing in a low-access region (IRR, 1.16; 95% CI, 1.11-1.21). Their rates of in-person IBD specialist visits were 18% relatively higher than those residing in regions of lower access. They, however, were 86% less likely than those from low-access regions to receive a virtual IBD specialist visit (IRR, 0.14; 95% CI, 0.11-0.17). In the COVID maintenance period, there was a slight narrowing of the gap in access to IBD specialist care. Those in high access regions had a 12% higher relative rate of any IBD specialist visits compared to those from lower access regions (IRR, 1.12; 95% CI, 1.09-1.16). By the final quarter of 2020, the rate of total IBD specialist visits in high-access regions remained the same at 300 per 1000 IBD capita. In low specialist access regions, the total rate of IBD specialist visits increased to 265 per 1000 IBD capita.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>12969</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12980</offset><text>Restrictions during the COVID-19 pandemic triggered an abrupt shift in the delivery of IBD specialist care from predominantly in-person visits to virtual visits. This transition was facilitated by reimbursement codes for both phone and video visits and by relaxed requirements for virtual visits. The flexibility of these changes allowed Ontario’s health system to not only sustain but slightly increase total IBD specialist care, which had been gradually declining before the pandemic. Building on the infrastructure of the Ontario Telemedicine Network (OTN) program, Crohn’s and Colitis Canada launched the Promoting Access and Care through Centres of Excellence (PACE) program in 2016 to expand virtual access to IBD specialists across underserved regions. Even before the pandemic, our data showed a gradual rise in virtual IBD specialist visits, particularly in low-access areas, suggesting that the groundwork for virtual expansion was already in place before COVID-19 accelerated its widespread adoption.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13996</offset><text>Preserving access to IBD specialists during the pandemic was particularly important because of previous research linking specialist care to improved patient outcomes. Nguyen et al demonstrated that among newly diagnosed CD patients, being under the care of a gastroenterologist within the first 2 years of diagnosis was associated with nearly a third decrease in risk of IBD-related surgery. Following surgery, CD patients who resided in regions with higher use specialists exhibited lower rates of late postoperative hospitalizations. In another population-based study, hospitalized UC patients who were under the care of a gastroenterologist had lower in-hospital and 1-year mortality. Specialist care may improve IBD outcomes because it is associated with higher use of appropriate biologics, combination therapy, and endoscopy and imaging. European population-based studies suggest that closer geographic distance to specialists was also associated with higher use of IBD medical therapies such as biologics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15009</offset><text>Our study showed that geographic disparities in access to IBD specialist care manifested in higher rates of specialist visits among those residing in higher access regions before the pandemic. Residing in regions of moderate or high access to specialists has been shown to be associated with lower rates of IBD-related emergency department utilization compared with those living in low-access regions. This disparity was slightly mitigated during the COVID-19 pandemic while not compromising the total delivery of IBD specialist services. Exponential expansion of virtual care modestly increased total IBD specialist care and reduced geographic disparities in access. Additional benefits of widespread integration of virtual care may be to reduce carbon footprint. A large Ontario population-based study demonstrated a substantial reduction in carbon footprint with the implementation of virtual care during the COVID-19 pandemic. A smaller cross-sectional study has also reported a similar reduction in carbon emissions attributable to virtual care delivered in a large gastroenterology clinic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16105</offset><text>While we observed a modest ∼7% relative increase in the total rate of IBD specialist visits during the pandemic, that increase likely reflects more than just “catch-up” care or substitution of in-person visits with virtual ones. One possibility is that virtual care removed nongeographic barriers to access even for patients outside rural regions. For example, patients may have been more willing to schedule an appointment when they did not have to take so much time off work, arrange childcare, or face travel and parking expenses. Telemedicine use is known to reduce travel burden, time costs, and missed-appointment rates in various settings. Virtual visits may reduce additional barriers for those with mobility issues or provide greater flexibility for those with tight schedules. In addition, reduced no-shows with telehealth could directly increase overall visits. Finally, some of the increase may reflect pent-up demand from patients postponing visits during early lockdowns, blending into the later phases of the pandemic.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17145</offset><text>Our finding of even modestly improved access to IBD specialist care during the pandemic has potential implications for health policy. The rapid expansion of virtual care demonstrated that digital platforms bridge long-standing geographic barriers and support equitable access to specialist services. Sustaining this progress will require policies that recognize virtual care as an essential component of healthcare delivery rather than a temporary emergency measure. Recent reductions in remuneration for virtual visits may discourage providers from offering this mode of care, particularly in regions already facing specialist shortages. Policymakers should consider maintaining fair compensation and infrastructure support for virtual care to preserve the gains achieved during the pandemic and to continue addressing disparities in access to specialist care across Ontario.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18022</offset><text>Among the limitations of our study is the short follow-up period after the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic. With resumption of in-person visits alongside the continued allowance of virtual visits, we do not have data on the sustainability of enhanced specialist care several years post-COVID, especially given the 15% reduction in compensation for phone visits relative to virtual visits. An additional limitation is that our study does not contain data on disease severity, so we could not assess its impact on triage of specialist services during the pandemic. Despite the use of validated algorithms, there may also be misclassification of IBD cases and virtual care visits. A higher proportion of our IBD cohort, when compared to the general population, reside in neighborhoods in the top income quintile, which is a surrogate for socioeconomic status (SES). An Australian study suggests that higher area SES was associated with increased use of virtual emergency services. It is possible that this may confer educational and financial advantages that facilitate adaptation to virtual care, and our findings may not be generalizable to the entire Ontario or Canadian population.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19210</offset><text>Our retrospective analysis of Ontario population-based study showed that virtual care compensated for the sharp decrease in in-person specialist visits due to restrictions during the COVID-19 pandemic. Before the pandemic, even limited use of virtual care was making inroads to increasing access to specialist care. Though the pandemic is over, it has led to sweeping changes in policy enabling the widespread use of healthcare delivery, which may provide ongoing access to IBD specialists in remote, underserved regions. We require longer-duration studies to assess the impact on long-term outcomes. Furthermore, initiatives that reduce the barriers to virtual care, such as internet access in rural areas and reimbursements that are commensurate with in-person visits, can maintain the momentum gained during the pandemic and improve IBD healthcare delivery.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20071</offset><text>Authorship contributions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20096</offset><text>L.J.N.: Study conception; data analysis; drafting of manuscript. V.W.H: Study conception, review of manuscript. P.H.: Study conception, review of manuscript. Y.G.: Study conception; data analysis; review of manuscript. P.T.: Study conception; data analysis; review of manuscript.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20376</offset><text>Funding</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20384</offset><text>This study was supported by ICES, which is funded by an annual grant from the Ontario Ministry of Health (MOH) and the Ministry of Long-Term Care (MLTC). This study also received funding from Crohn’s and Colitis Canada. This document used data adapted from the Statistics Canada Postal CodeOM Conversion File, which is based on data licensed from Canada Post Corporation, and/or data adapted from the Ontario Ministry of Health Postal Code Conversion File, which contains data copied under license from ©Canada Post Corporation and Statistics Canada. Parts of this material are based on data and/or information compiled and provided by CIHI and the Ontario Ministry of Health. The analyses, conclusions, opinions, and statements expressed herein are solely those of the authors and do not reflect those of the funding or data sources; no endorsement is intended or should be inferred.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>21272</offset><text>Author disclosures</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21291</offset><text>L.J.N.: None. V.W.H.: speaker fees from Abbvie, Amgen, Celltrion, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Janssen, Lupin, Organon, Pfizer, Takeda, and moderator fees from Abbvie, Celltrion, Janssen, Takeda. P.H.: None declared. Y.G.: None declared. P.T.: speaker fees from Takeda and Janssen and moderator fees from Abbvie.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>21600</offset><text>Data availability</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21618</offset><text>The dataset from this study is held securely in coded form at ICES. While legal data sharing agreements between ICES and data providers (e.g., healthcare organizations and government) prohibit ICES from making the dataset publicly available, access may be granted to those who meet pre-specified criteria for confidential access, available at www.ices.on.ca/DAS (email: das@ices.on.ca). The full dataset creation plan and underlying analytic code are available from the authors upon request, understanding that the computer programs may rely upon coding templates or macros that are unique to ICES and are therefore either inaccessible or may require modification.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>22283</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">90</infon><infon key="lpage">97</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21458455</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">141</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>22294</offset><text>Outcomes of patients with Crohn’s disease improved from 1988 to 2008 and were associated with increased specialist care</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1467</infon><infon key="lpage">1474</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37703380</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>22416</offset><text>Racial and ethnic disparities in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: an online survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">330</infon><infon key="lpage">336</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30312376</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>22508</offset><text>Access to specialists and emergency department visits in inflammatory bowel disease: a population-based study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">186</infon><infon key="lpage">194</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31616860</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Can Assoc Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>22618</offset><text>Transforming access to specialist care for inflammatory bowel disease: the PACE telemedicine program</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1135</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32935037</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int J Popul Data Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>22719</offset><text>ICES: data, discovery, better health</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1761</infon><infon key="lpage">1769</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25159453</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>22756</offset><text>Changing age demographics of inflammatory bowel disease in Ontario, Canada: a population-based cohort study of epidemiology trends</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">887</infon><infon key="lpage">896</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24774473</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Epidemiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>22887</offset><text>Validation of international algorithms to identify adults with inflammatory bowel disease in health administrative data from Ontario, Canada</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1613</infon><infon key="lpage">1626</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30519110</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Epidemiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>23028</offset><text>Rural and urban disparities in the care of Canadian patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a population-based study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0267218</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35468168</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>23147</offset><text>Virtual care use during the COVID-19 pandemic and its impact on healthcare utilization in patients with chronic disease: a population-based repeated cross-sectional study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">473</infon><infon key="lpage">479</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26544163</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Telemed J E Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>23318</offset><text>Clinical telemedicine utilization in Ontario over the Ontario telemedicine network</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2149</infon><infon key="lpage">2157</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27482978</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>23401</offset><text>Impact of specialized inpatient IBD care on outcomes of IBD hospitalizations: a cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1522</infon><infon key="lpage">1529</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22850430</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">107</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>23494</offset><text>Postoperative health-care utilization in Crohn’s disease: the impact of specialist care</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1410</infon><infon key="lpage">1416</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22684482</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>23584</offset><text>Impact of gastroenterologist care on health outcomes of hospitalised ulcerative colitis patients</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2475</infon><infon key="lpage">2486.e14</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38844254</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>23681</offset><text>Provider specialization in inflammatory bowel diseases: quality of care and outcomes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1756284819895217</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Therap Adv Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>23766</offset><text>Effect of distance to specialist care for the diagnosis and disease outcome of inflammatory bowel disease in the Swiss inflammatory bowel disease cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e2237545</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36264577</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">JAMA Netw Open</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>23925</offset><text>Association of virtual care expansion with environmental sustainability and reduced patient costs during the COVID-19 pandemic in Ontario, Canada</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7</infon><infon key="lpage">12</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39906278</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Can Assoc Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>24071</offset><text>Sustainable practice in gastroenterology: travel-related CO(2) emissions for gastroenterology clinic appointments in Canada</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">101629</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34976682</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Prev Med Rep</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>24195</offset><text>Associations of telemedicine vs. in-person ambulatory visits and cancellation rates and 30-day follow-up hospitalizations and emergency department visits</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">217</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39164391</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">NPJ Digit Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>24349</offset><text>Closing the gap: addressing telehealth disparities across specialties in the sustained pandemic era</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e55996</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38618307</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cureus</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>24449</offset><text>A comprehensive review on exploring the impact of telemedicine on healthcare accessibility</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">E976</infon><infon key="lpage">e986</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40983382</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">CMAJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">197</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>24540</offset><text>Changes in driving distance to specialist physicians in the era of virtual care: a population-based cohort study in Ontario, Canada</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e70011</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39950229</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Emerg Med Australas</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>24672</offset><text>Impact of socioeconomic status on utilisation of a virtual emergency department: an exploratory analysis</text></passage></document>
</collection>