<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260207</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12853473</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2025-105579</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12853473</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">41577348</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">bmjopen-2025-105579</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e105579</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="kwd">Irritable Bowel Syndrome Meta-Analysis Systematic Review</infon><infon key="license">This is an open access article distributed in accordance with the Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial (CC BY-NC 4.0) license, which permits others to distribute, remix, adapt, build upon this work non-commercially, and license their derivative works on different terms, provided the original work is properly cited, appropriate credit is given, any changes made indicated, and the use is non-commercial. See: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:Yongjian</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yan;given-names:Xiumei</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Jiang;given-names:Fan</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:Jiahui</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:Di</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Fang;given-names:Yuan</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Huang;given-names:Jia</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Zhu;given-names:Meiyi</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Li;given-names:Lun</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Zhang;given-names:Tian</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Zhang;given-names:Qinhong</infon><infon key="notes">The funders have no role in study design, data collection, analysis, interpretation or manuscript preparation.</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2026</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of non-pharmacological therapies for irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea: protocol for systematic review and network meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>155</offset><text> Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>165</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>178</offset><text>Irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea (IBS-D) significantly impairs patients’ quality of life. Although various non-pharmacological interventions show promise, evidence on their comparative effectiveness remains limited. This protocol outlines a systematic review and network meta-analysis designed to comprehensively evaluate and rank the efficacy and safety of guideline-recommended non-pharmacological therapies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>598</offset><text>Methods and analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>619</offset><text>We will systematically search PubMed, Cochrane Library, Web of Science, Embase, China National Knowledge Infrastructure, Chinese Biomedical Database, Wanfang Data and VIP Database from inception to January 2025. Eligible studies will include randomised controlled trials assessing guideline-recommended non-pharmacological interventions, probiotics, acupuncture, cognitive–behavioural therapy, dietary modifications and faecal microbiota transplantation in adults diagnosed with IBS-D based on Rome III or IV criteria. The primary outcome is the Irritable Bowel Syndrome Symptom Severity Score. Secondary outcomes include the Irritable Bowel Syndrome Quality of Life Scale and Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. Two independent reviewers will screen studies, extract data and evaluate risk of bias using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2.0 tool. Network meta-analysis will be performed using frequentist methods with Stata and R software. Transitivity, heterogeneity, consistency and publication bias will be assessed. Certainty of evidence will be graded using the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluations methodology, supplemented with trial sequential analysis to determine the required information size.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1854</offset><text>Ethics and dissemination</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1879</offset><text>Ethical approval is not required for this secondary analysis as it uses published data. The results will be disseminated via peer-reviewed journals and conference presentations to inform clinical practice and guideline development.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>2111</offset><text>Registration</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>2124</offset><text>INPLASY202470112.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_caption</infon><offset>2142</offset><text>STRENGTHS AND LIMITATIONS OF THIS STUDY</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2182</offset><text>Comprehensive search strategy including both English and Chinese databases to minimise publication bias.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2287</offset><text>Application of trial sequential analysis and Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluations methodology enhances evidence reliability and clinical interpretability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2473</offset><text>Focus on guideline-recommended therapies ensures clinical relevance and practical applicability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2570</offset><text>Rigorous assessment of transitivity assumptions and comprehensive sensitivity analyses strengthen network meta-analysis validity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2700</offset><text>Language restriction to English and Chinese publications may exclude relevant studies from other regions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2806</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2819</offset><text> Irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea (IBS-D) is a prevalent chronic functional gastrointestinal disorder characterised by recurrent abdominal pain, bloating and diarrhoea, affecting approximately 40% of all patients with IBS. The global prevalence of IBS-D ranges from 1.5% to 4.5%, displaying significant geographical and demographic variability. Current pharmacological treatments, although effective in symptom relief, often carry significant adverse effects, including ischaemic colitis (alosetron), severe constipation (loperamide) and cardiovascular symptoms (eluxadoline). These adverse effects, combined with patient preferences for non-drug therapies, have driven growing interest in alternative, non-pharmacological interventions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3564</offset><text>Despite the widespread use of these non-pharmacological therapies, their comparative effectiveness remains uncertain. Recent systematic reviews have yielded inconsistent findings, with some interventions demonstrating significant benefits while others show minimal effects. Individual trials frequently lack sufficient statistical power to detect clinically meaningful differences, and direct comparisons among various non-pharmacological interventions are scarce. A 2020 network meta-analysis by Dai et al evaluated several non-pharmacological therapies but was restricted to literature published before 2019. Since then, numerous high-quality trials have emerged, particularly focusing on emerging treatments such as faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) and advanced probiotic formulations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4360</offset><text>Current international guidelines show considerable variation in their recommendations for non-pharmacological therapies, reflecting the uncertainty in the evidence base (table 1). The 2021 American College of Gastroenterology guidelines provide conditional recommendations for several interventions, while the British Society of Gastroenterology guidelines emphasise dietary modifications as first-line therapy. In contrast, the Romanian Society of Gastroenterology recommends a wider range of therapies, including acupuncture. Such heterogeneity underscores the need for robust, comparative effectiveness evidence to inform clinical decision-making effectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>5023</offset><text>International guideline recommendations for non-pharmacological therapies in IBS-D</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Guideline&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Probiotics&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Acupuncture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CBT&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Diet&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th valign=&quot;bottom&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;FMT&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;ACG 2021&lt;xref rid=&quot;R1&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Conditional&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Conditional&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strong&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Conditional&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Not recommended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BSG 2021&lt;xref rid=&quot;R15&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Weak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strong&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Strong (low FODMAP)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Insufficient evidence&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Romanian 2021&lt;xref rid=&quot;R16&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Recommended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Under investigation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>5106</offset><text>Guideline	Probiotics	Acupuncture	CBT	Diet	FMT	 	ACG 2021	Conditional	Conditional	Strong	Conditional	Not recommended	 	BSG 2021	Weak	Weak	Strong	Strong (low FODMAP)	Insufficient evidence	 	Romanian 2021	Recommended	Recommended	Recommended	Recommended	Under investigation	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>5379</offset><text>In this context, a ‘Conditional’ recommendation indicates moderate or low certainty of supporting evidence, suggesting that the balance between benefits and harms may vary among individuals. Clinicians are therefore advised to tailor decisions according to patient preferences and clinical circumstances.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>5688</offset><text>ACG, American College of Gastroenterology; BSG, British Society of Gastroenterology; CBT, cognitive–behavioural therapy; FMT, faecal microbiota transplantation; FODMAP, fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides and polyols; IBS-D, irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5981</offset><text>The primary objectives of this systematic review and network meta-analysis are to: (1) comprehensively assess and rank the comparative effectiveness and safety of guideline-recommended non-pharmacological therapies for IBS-D based on current evidence; (2) identify specific patient subgroups most likely to benefit from particular interventions through detailed subgroup analyses; and (3) generate robust evidence accompanied by clear certainty assessments to inform clinical decision-making and future guideline development.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>6507</offset><text>Materials and methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>6529</offset><text>Study registration</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6548</offset><text>This protocol adheres to the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis Protocols (PRISMA-P) guidelines (online supplemental file 2 contains the completed PRISMA-P checklist). The protocol was prospectively registered on 1 July 2024 in the International Platform of Registered Systematic Review and Meta-analysis Protocols (INPLASY) database (registration number: INPLASY202470112). Any amendments to this protocol, including the date and rationale, will be documented in the final review. The review will follow the guidelines of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions (version 6.5, 2024).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7185</offset><text>Eligibility criteria</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>7206</offset><text>Inclusion criteria</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7225</offset><text>Participants: adults (≥18 years) diagnosed with IBS-D according to Rome III or IV criteria. Studies reporting mixed IBS subtypes will be excluded unless IBS-D data can be extracted separately. No restrictions will be applied regarding disease duration, severity or previous treatment history.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7520</offset><text>Interventions: guideline-recommended non-pharmacological therapies selected based on inclusion in at least two major international guidelines. These include:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7678</offset><text>Probiotics (defined as live microorganisms administered orally; considered non-pharmacological as they modulate gut microbiota rather than acting through direct pharmacological mechanisms).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7868</offset><text>Acupuncture (manual or electroacupuncture, with or without moxibustion).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7941</offset><text>Cognitive–behavioural therapy (CBT; individual or group based, including internet-delivered CBT).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8041</offset><text>Dietary modifications (analysed both as a combined category and separately as low fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides and polyols diet, gluten-free diet and traditional dietary advice).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8252</offset><text>FMT (via any route of administration).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8291</offset><text> Combinations of above interventions. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8330</offset><text>Comparators: placebo, no treatment, usual care, waiting list control or other non-pharmacological interventions listed above.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8456</offset><text>Outcomes: studies must report at least one of the following:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8517</offset><text>Primary outcome: Irritable Bowel Syndrome Symptom Severity Score (IBS-SSS).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8593</offset><text>Secondary outcomes: Irritable Bowel Syndrome Quality of Life Scale (IBS-QOL), Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) and adverse events.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8736</offset><text>Study design: randomised controlled trials with a minimum intervention duration of 4 weeks and any follow-up length.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>8853</offset><text>Exclusion criteria</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8872</offset><text>Non-randomised studies, protocols without results, conference abstracts, reviews, case reports and observational studies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8994</offset><text>Studies including other IBS subtypes without separate IBS-D data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9060</offset><text>Non-guideline-recommended interventions (eg, homeopathy, herbal medicines not recognised in major guidelines, hypnotherapy).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9185</offset><text>Fibre supplementation (considered pharmacological due to standardised dosing and mechanism of action similar to bulking agents).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9314</offset><text>Yoga and other physical therapies (not consistently recommended in major guidelines).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9400</offset><text>Studies with insufficient outcome data for meta-analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9458</offset><text>Duplicate publications (only the most complete report will be included).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9531</offset><text>Information sources and search strategy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9571</offset><text>Literature searches will be conducted from database inception to 31 January 2025. Electronic databases include:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9683</offset><text>English databases: PubMed/MEDLINE, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), Web of Science Core Collection, Embase.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9816</offset><text>Chinese databases: China National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI), Chinese Biomedical Literature Database (CBM), Wanfang Data, VIP Database (a major Chinese academic database covering biomedical and scientific literature).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10039</offset><text>Additional sources include:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10067</offset><text>Trial registries: ClinicalTrials.gov, WHO International Clinical Trials Registry Platform, Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (ChiCTR), including the ITMCTR section.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10230</offset><text>Grey literature: ProQuest Dissertations &amp; Theses Global.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10287</offset><text>Reference lists of included studies and relevant systematic reviews.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10356</offset><text>Study author contact for unpublished data when necessary.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10414</offset><text>Full search strategies for all databases, including Chinese search terms, are provided in online supplemental file 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10532</offset><text>Study records</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>10546</offset><text>Data management</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10562</offset><text>Search results will be imported into EndNote V.20 (Clarivate Analytics, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA) for reference management.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>10693</offset><text>Selection process</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10711</offset><text>Two reviewers (YL, XY) will independently screen titles and abstracts against the eligibility criteria. Potentially eligible studies will undergo independent full-text evaluation. Disagreements will be resolved through discussion or by consulting a third reviewer (FJ). Reasons for exclusions at the full-text stage will be recorded. The selection process will be presented using a PRISMA flow diagram (figure 1; numbers to be updated on study selection completion).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">bmjopen-16-1-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>11178</offset><text>PRISMA flow diagram (numbers will be updated on completion of study selection). CBM, Chinese Biomedical Literature Database; CNKI, China National Knowledge Infrastructure; IBS-D, irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea; PRISMA, Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses; RCT, randomised controlled trial.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>11508</offset><text>Data collection process</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11532</offset><text>Two reviewers (JY, DZ) will independently extract data using a standardised, piloted extraction form developed in Microsoft Excel. Disagreements will be resolved through discussion or third reviewer consultation. If necessary, study authors will be contacted to obtain missing or unclear data, with a maximum of three email attempts over 4 weeks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11879</offset><text>Data items</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11890</offset><text>The following data will be extracted:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11928</offset><text>Study characteristics: first author, year of publication, country, study setting (primary/secondary/tertiary care), sample size, trial registration number, duration of intervention and follow-up, funding source.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12140</offset><text>Population details: age (mean and SD), gender distribution, diagnostic criteria used, baseline IBS-SSS scores, disease duration, previous treatments, exclusion of organic disease method.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12327</offset><text>Intervention details:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12349</offset><text>For probiotics: strain(s), dose, colony-forming units, frequency, duration.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12425</offset><text>For acupuncture: type, point selection, frequency, number of sessions, practitioner qualifications.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12525</offset><text>For CBT: format, number of sessions, duration, therapist qualifications.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12598</offset><text>For dietary interventions: specific diet type, dietitian involvement, adherence monitoring.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12690</offset><text>For FMT: donor screening, route of administration, dose, frequency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12758</offset><text>Comparator details: type, duration, cointerventions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12811</offset><text>Outcomes:</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12821</offset><text>For continuous outcomes: means, SDs, SEs, 95% CIs, change scores or final values, analysed sample size.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12925</offset><text>For dichotomous outcomes: number of events, number analysed per group.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12996</offset><text> Time points of assessment. </text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13025</offset><text>Adverse events: type, frequency, severity (mild/moderate/severe), relationship to intervention, discontinuations due to adverse events. To ensure comparability across studies, adverse events will be categorised using predefined classifications (eg, gastrointestinal, neurological, psychological). Where available, severity grading (mild, moderate, severe) will be extracted separately. Serious adverse events, as defined by original trial authors, will also be recorded independently. If multiple time points are reported, data will be extracted at both the end of treatment and the longest available follow-up.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13637</offset><text>Risk of bias assessment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13661</offset><text>Two independent reviewers (YF, JH) will assess risk of bias using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2.0 tool. This tool evaluates five domains of bias: bias arising from the randomisation process, bias due to deviations from intended interventions, bias due to missing outcome data, bias in outcome measurement and bias in selection of the reported result.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14010</offset><text>Each domain will be rated as ‘low risk’, ‘some concerns’ or ‘high risk’. Overall risk of bias will be determined by the highest risk level in any domain. Studies with a high risk of bias in ≥3 domains will undergo sensitivity analysis to assess their impact on results. Disagreements will be resolved through discussion or third reviewer consultation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>14376</offset><text>Data synthesis and analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>14404</offset><text>Transitivity evaluation</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14428</offset><text>Transitivity, which assumes that patients could be randomised to any intervention within the network, will be evaluated by comparing the distribution of potential effect modifiers across treatment comparisons. Potential effect modifiers include age (mean and range), baseline symptom severity (IBS-SSS scores), disease duration, geographical region (Western vs Asian populations) and diagnostic criteria (Rome III vs Rome IV). Significant imbalances will be addressed through sensitivity analyses excluding problematic comparisons, and through meta-regression to adjust for imbalanced covariates. Visual inspection of similarity will be complemented by statistical tests assessing differences in effect modifiers across comparisons.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>15161</offset><text>Statistical analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15182</offset><text>Statistical analyses will be performed using Stata V.17.0 (StataCorp, College Station, Texas, USA) and R V.4.3.0 (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria) with the netmeta and gemtc packages. Pairwise meta-analyses will use random-effects models based on the DerSimonian-Laird method. Network meta-analysis will follow a frequentist framework using graph-theoretical methods. For effect sizes, standardised mean differences will be applied for continuous outcomes and risk ratios (RRs) for binary outcomes, both reported with 95% CIs. Treatment ranking will be evaluated using surface under the cumulative ranking curve values and mean ranks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>15841</offset><text>Assessment of heterogeneity and consistency</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15885</offset><text>Heterogeneity in pairwise comparisons will be assessed using the χ2 statistic and I2, with the between-study variance assumed to be common across all comparisons. I2 values will be interpreted according to established thresholds: low (&lt;40%), moderate (40–60%), substantial (60–75%) and considerable (&gt;75%). Consistency between direct and indirect evidence will be examined globally using the design-by-treatment interaction model and locally using node-splitting analysis (p&gt;0.05 indicates consistency). When inconsistency is identified, potential sources will be explored and sensitivity analyses will be conducted.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>16507</offset><text>Subgroup and meta-regression analyses</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16545</offset><text>Seven prespecified moderators will be examined to investigate sources of heterogeneity and variation in treatment effects. These include geographical region (Western vs Asian populations), baseline severity (mild/moderate (IBS-SSS &lt;300) vs severe (IBS-SSS ≥300)), disease duration (&lt;5 years vs ≥5 years), gender predominance (&gt;70% female vs gender balanced), diagnostic criteria (Rome III vs Rome IV), intervention duration (&lt;8 weeks vs ≥8 weeks) and risk of bias (low vs some concerns/high). Meta-regression will be performed when ≥10 studies are available per covariate to formally evaluate whether these effect modifiers account for observed heterogeneity or inconsistency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>17230</offset><text>Sensitivity analyses</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17251</offset><text>The robustness of the primary findings will be evaluated through several preplanned sensitivity analyses, including: excluding studies with high risk of bias; excluding studies with fewer than 50 participants per arm; using alternative effect measures (eg, mean difference for IBS-SSS); restricting analyses to English language publications; applying a Bayesian network meta-analysis framework; and excluding studies published before 2010.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>17691</offset><text>Publication bias assessment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17719</offset><text>Publication bias will be assessed through funnel plots and Egger’s and Begg’s tests in pairwise meta-analyses, provided there are at least 10 eligible studies. For network meta-analyses, we will employ comparison-adjusted funnel plots to evaluate potential publication bias across interventions. If evidence of publication bias emerges, we will perform trim-and-fill analyses to assess its impact on our findings and conclusions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>18153</offset><text>Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluations assessment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18232</offset><text>We will assess the quality of evidence using the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluations (GRADE) framework, specifically adapted for network meta-analysis . Evidence will be evaluated based on five key domains: risk of bias, inconsistency, indirectness, imprecision and publication bias. Evidence will be downgraded under specific conditions, including if more than 50% of studies exhibit a high or unclear risk of bias; if there is substantial heterogeneity (I2 &gt;50%) or significant inconsistency identified through node-splitting analyses (p&lt;0.05); if the evidence is entirely indirect or significant differences exist in populations or interventions; if the 95% CIs cross the null effect or the established minimal clinically important difference (MCID) of 50 points on the IBS Severity Scoring System (IBS-SSS); or if asymmetry in funnel plots suggests publication bias (p&lt;0.05 on Egger’s test). Evidence will subsequently be categorised as high, moderate, low or very low quality, and summary tables will be generated using GRADEpro GDT software to provide clear, accessible insights into our findings.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>19370</offset><text>Trial sequential analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19396</offset><text>Trial sequential analysis (TSA) will determine whether accumulated evidence is sufficient for conclusive findings. The analysis parameters include a predefined MCID of 50 points on the IBS-SSS, a two-sided type I error of 5%, a type II error of 20% (equating to 80% statistical power), an anticipated intervention effect derived from preliminary analyses and a diversity adjustment based on observed heterogeneity within the meta-analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19836</offset><text>TSA will calculate required information size and construct monitoring boundaries using TSA software (Copenhagen Trial Unit, Denmark).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>19970</offset><text>Adverse event analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19993</offset><text>For safety outcomes, the incidence of total adverse events and serious adverse events will be synthesised using RR with corresponding 95% CIs. To ensure comparability across studies, adverse events will be harmonised according to predefined categories described in the Data items section. In cases where adverse event data are sparse or unavailable, we will apply continuity corrections or conduct a narrative synthesis, whichever is most appropriate. Safety analyses will be conducted independently from efficacy analyses to clearly delineate the evaluation of therapeutic benefits from potential risks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20598</offset><text>Study timeline</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20613</offset><text>Protocol registration: July 2024 (completed).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20659</offset><text>Literature search: January–February 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20703</offset><text>Study screening: February–March 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20743</offset><text>Data extraction: March–April 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20780</offset><text>Risk of bias assessment: April 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20817</offset><text>Data analysis: May–June 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20849</offset><text>Manuscript preparation: June–July 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20891</offset><text>Planned submission: July 2025.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20922</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20933</offset><text>This network meta-analysis addresses critical gaps in IBS-D management by providing the first comprehensive comparative evaluation of guideline-recommended non-pharmacological therapies based on current evidence. The strengths of this protocol include its rigorous methodological design, comprehensive multilingual search strategy and use of advanced analytical approaches, such as TSA and GRADE assessments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21342</offset><text>The IBS-SSS was chosen as the primary outcome because it provides a comprehensive evaluation of IBS symptoms (pain, distension, bowel dysfunction and impact on quality of life) and has an established MCID of 50 points, facilitating clinically meaningful interpretation. Secondary outcomes (IBS-QOL and HADS) capture broader effects of treatments on quality of life and psychological well-being, thereby acknowledging the biopsychosocial complexity of IBS-D.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21800</offset><text>Our emphasis on guideline-endorsed therapies ensures clinical applicability without compromising methodological rigour. By excluding interventions not recommended by major guidelines, we aim to generate actionable evidence for clinical practice. Including both Western and Chinese databases mitigates potential publication bias and recognises that intervention effectiveness may differ between populations due to cultural, dietary and genetic factors.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>22252</offset><text>Anticipated challenges and mitigation strategies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22301</offset><text>Several methodological challenges are anticipated in conducting this systematic review and network meta-analysis. Heterogeneity in intervention protocols, such as variations in probiotic strains, acupuncture point selection and CBT formats, could impact treatment effects. This issue will be addressed by performing detailed subgroup analyses based on specific characteristics of the interventions. Additionally, differences in outcome measurement time points across studies will be managed by analysing outcomes at predefined intervals (4, 8 and 12 weeks), supplemented by sensitivity analyses to assess the impact of timing variations. Potential violations of the transitivity assumption, arising from diverse patient populations, will be thoroughly evaluated through sensitivity analyses. Given the inherent difficulty in fully blinding behavioural interventions, the associated risk of bias will be assessed rigorously in the risk of bias evaluations and further explored via sensitivity analyses. Finally, limited direct evidence for certain treatment comparisons may restrict the precision of some network estimates; hence, confidence in indirect comparisons will be critically assessed and uncertainties will be transparently communicated.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>23548</offset><text>Clinical and research implications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23583</offset><text>This review will provide clinicians with evidence-based rankings of non-pharmacological therapies, enabling personalised treatment decisions according to patient characteristics, preferences and local availability. By identifying the most effective interventions and specific patient subgroups most likely to benefit, these findings will inform clinical guidelines and healthcare policy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23971</offset><text>For researchers, this review will highlight gaps in the existing evidence base that necessitate future trials, particularly head-to-head comparisons of promising interventions. The comprehensive evaluation of sources of heterogeneity will also guide the design of future studies, particularly regarding patient selection criteria and standardisation of outcome measures.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>24342</offset><text>Strengths and limitations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24368</offset><text>This study has several methodological strengths that bolster the robustness and applicability of its findings. We will employ a comprehensive search strategy that encompasses major bibliographic databases in both English and Chinese, alongside trial registries and grey literature sources, minimising the risk of publication bias and ensuring extensive coverage of relevant evidence. Furthermore, incorporating TSA and the GRADE framework will enhance the interpretability and clarity of cumulative evidence, offering explicit certainty ratings for network estimates. By focusing on guideline-recommended non-pharmacological therapies, our findings will provide direct relevance to clinical practice and guideline development. Additionally, extensive sensitivity and subgroup analyses will be performed to rigorously test the assumptions underlying the network meta-analysis, including assessments of transitivity and inconsistency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25301</offset><text>However, several limitations must be acknowledged. Restricting studies to publications in English and Chinese might lead to omission of potentially relevant evidence published in other languages. Variability in intervention characteristics, including probiotic strains and dosages, acupuncture protocols (eg, points selected, stimulation modes) and psychological therapy formats, may introduce significant heterogeneity, despite subgroup analyses. The inherent challenges of fully blinding participants in behavioural interventions could increase performance or detection bias for certain outcomes. Moreover, the paucity of direct head-to-head comparisons for specific interventions may result in reliance on indirect evidence, necessitating cautious interpretation and transparent reporting of uncertainties in the findings.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26127</offset><text>Patient and public involvement</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26158</offset><text>Patients or members of the public were not involved in the design, conduct, reporting or dissemination of this study.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>26276</offset><text>Supplementary material</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>26299</offset><text>Funding: This work is supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No 82360973), Natural Science Foundation of Jiangxi Province (Grant No 20224BAB216093), Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education Science and Technology Program (Grant No GJJ2200982) and Jiangxi University of Chinese Medicine’s ‘Open Bidding for Selecting the Best Candidates’ Project for the First-Class Undergraduate Program Construction in Acupuncture and Tuina (Grant No 2024ZT-JBGS03).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>26788</offset><text>Prepublication history and additional supplemental material for this paper are available online. To view these files, please visit the journal online (https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2025-105579).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>26985</offset><text>Provenance and peer review: Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>27057</offset><text>Patient consent for publication: Not applicable.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>27106</offset><text>Patient and public involvement: Patients and/or the public were not involved in the design, or conduct, or reporting, or dissemination plans of this research.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>27265</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">17</infon><infon key="lpage">44</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lacy;given-names:BE</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pimentel;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Brenner;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000001036</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33315591</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">116</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>27276</offset><text>ACG Clinical Guideline: Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">99</infon><infon key="lpage">114</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sperber;given-names:AD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bangdiwala;given-names:SI</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drossman;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2020.04.014</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32294476</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">160</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>27339</offset><text>Worldwide Prevalence and Burden of Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders, Results of Rome Foundation Global Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">908</infon><infon key="lpage">17</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Oka;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Parr;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Barberio;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(20)30217-X</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32702295</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>27453</offset><text>Global prevalence of irritable bowel syndrome according to Rome III or IV criteria: a systematic review and meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1149</infon><infon key="lpage">72</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lembo;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sultan;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2014.09.002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25224525</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">147</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>27575</offset><text>American Gastroenterological Association Institute Technical Review on the pharmacological management of irritable bowel syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">242</infon><infon key="lpage">53</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lembo;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lacy;given-names:BE</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zuckerman;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1505180</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26789872</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">374</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>27705</offset><text>Eluxadoline for Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Diarrhea</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">22</infon><infon key="lpage">32</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pimentel;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lembo;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chey;given-names:WD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1004409</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21208106</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">364</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>27760</offset><text>Rifaximin therapy for patients with irritable bowel syndrome without constipation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">18</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ford;given-names:AC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Moayyedi;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chey;given-names:WD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41395-018-0084-x</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">113</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>27842</offset><text>American College of Gastroenterology Monograph on Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1441</infon><infon key="lpage">51</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Black;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Thakur;given-names:ER</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Houghton;given-names:LA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2020-321191</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32276950</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>27931</offset><text>Efficacy of psychological therapies for irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and network meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3505</infon><infon key="lpage">22</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:van Lanen;given-names:A-S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:de Bree;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Greyling;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00394-020-02473-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33585949</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">60</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>28041</offset><text>Efficacy of a low-FODMAP diet in adult irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">e13951</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dimidi;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Whelan;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/nmo.13951</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32697018</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Neurogastroenterol Motil</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>28144</offset><text>Food supplements and diet as treatment options in irritable bowel syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">6488-6509</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dai;given-names:YK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wu;given-names:YB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:RL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3748/wjg.v26.i41.6488</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33244207</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J Gastroenterol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26(41)</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>28219</offset><text>Efficacy and safety of non-pharmacological interventions for irritable bowel syndrome in adults</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">859</infon><infon key="lpage">67</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:El-Salhy;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hatlebakk;given-names:JG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gilja;given-names:OH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2019-319630</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31852769</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>28315</offset><text>Efficacy of faecal microbiota transplantation for patients with irritable bowel syndrome in a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">457</infon><infon key="lpage">67</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1159/000540420</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39084197</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Digestion</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">105</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>28460</offset><text>Efficacy of Donor-Recipient-Matched Faecal Microbiota Transplantation in Patients with IBS-D: A Single-Centre, Randomized, Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">62</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Guo;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12876-016-0470-z</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27296254</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>28621</offset><text>Effects of probiotic type, dose and treatment duration on irritable bowel syndrome diagnosed by Rome III criteria: a meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1214</infon><infon key="lpage">40</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vasant;given-names:DH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Paine;given-names:PA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Black;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2021-324598</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33903147</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>28752</offset><text>British Society of Gastroenterology guidelines on the management of irritable bowel syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">291</infon><infon key="lpage">306</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dumitrascu;given-names:DL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Baban;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bancila;given-names:I</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.15403/jgld-3581</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33951120</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gastrointestin Liver Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>28845</offset><text>Romanian Guidelines for Nonpharmacological Therapy of IBS</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">g7647</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shamseer;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Moher;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Clarke;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmj.g7647</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25555855</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">350</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>28903</offset><text>Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Higgins;given-names:JPT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Thomas;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chandler;given-names:J</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.5</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>29024</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1393</infon><infon key="lpage">407</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mearin;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lacy;given-names:BE</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chang;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.031</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">150</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>29025</offset><text>Bowel Disorders</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">533</infon><infon key="lpage">53</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Guarner;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sanders;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Szajewska;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/MCG.0000000000002002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38885083</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">58</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>29041</offset><text>World Gastroenterology Organisation Global Guidelines: Probiotics and Prebiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">l4898</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sterne;given-names:JAC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Savović;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Page;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31462531</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMJ</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">366</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>29122</offset><text>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">36</infon><infon key="lpage">44</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brignardello-Petersen;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bonner;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Alexander;given-names:PE</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.10.005</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29051107</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Epidemiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">93</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>29192</offset><text>Advances in the GRADE approach to rate the certainty in estimates from a network meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">39</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wetterslev;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jakobsen;given-names:JC</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gluud;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12874-017-0315-7</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28264661</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Med Res Methodol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>29287</offset><text>Trial Sequential Analysis in systematic reviews with meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">395</infon><infon key="lpage">402</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Francis;given-names:CY</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Morris;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Whorwell;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1046/j.1365-2036.1997.142318000.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9146781</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>29354</offset><text>The irritable bowel severity scoring system: a simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>29471</offset><text>Review Process File</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29491</offset><text>2026</text></passage></document>
</collection>