<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260212</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12884850</id><infon key="license">CC BY-NC</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1093/jcag/gwaf036</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12884850</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">gwaf036</infon><infon key="fpage">38</infon><infon key="issue">1</infon><infon key="kwd">bowel urgency Crohn’s disease ulcerative colitis</infon><infon key="license">This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/), which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site—for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</infon><infon key="lpage">48</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jairath;given-names:Vipul</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bessissow;given-names:Talat</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Glass;given-names:Jennifer</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Braun;given-names:Marta</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gibble;given-names:Theresa Hunter</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Movsessian;given-names:Taline</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Atkinson;given-names:Christian</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Ellis;given-names:Hilary</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Dewar;given-names:Thomas</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Panaccione;given-names:Remo</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2026</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Communicating Needs and Features of IBD Experiences study: Canadian individuals and healthcare professional perceptions of the experience and impact of symptoms of moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>224</offset><text>Abstract</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>233</offset><text>Background</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>244</offset><text>Crohn’s disease (CD) and ulcerative colitis (UC) are chronic inflammatory conditions of the gastrointestinal tract associated with impaired quality of life. The Communicating Needs and Features of IBD Experiences (CONFIDE) study aimed to assess the impact of CD/UC symptoms on the lives of people with IBD and elucidate any communication gaps between healthcare professionals (HCPs) and people with IBD. The current Canadian study replicates the CONFIDE study previously conducted in the United States, Europe, and Japan.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>768</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>776</offset><text>Online cross-sectional surveys were conducted between February and April 2023 among people with moderate-to-severe CD/UC and prescribing HCPs. Disease severity was defined using criteria based on previous treatment, steroid use, and/or hospitalization. Data were presented using descriptive analyses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1077</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1085</offset><text>Surveys were completed by 107 individuals with CD, 82 individuals with UC, and 53 HCPs. Bowel urgency was the second most common symptom reported by individuals, following diarrhoea, and it was the most frequently reported symptom leading to declining participation in work/school, social events, and physical exercise. HCP-perceived symptoms with the greatest impact on people with IBD and their treatment decisions were diarrhoea and blood in stool. While most HCPs reported proactive discussion of bowel urgency with their patients, more than a third of those experiencing this symptom reported discussing it infrequently during HCP appointments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1735</offset><text>Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1747</offset><text>The results indicate that CD/UC symptoms have a substantial impact on the daily lives of people with IBD, even among those receiving advanced therapies. Although both HCPs and individuals with IBD reported a substantial symptom burden, their perceptions regarding the most impactful symptoms differed. Bowel urgency was identified as a common yet overlooked symptom and should be incorporated into regular IBD assessments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2170</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2183</offset><text>Crohn’s disease (CD) and ulcerative colitis (UC) are the 2 primary forms of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), a chronic, systemic condition characterized by inflammation of the gastrointestinal tract. Typical symptoms of CD and UC include diarrhoea, abdominal pain, blood in stool, and bowel urgency. People with IBD often experience cycles of flare-ups, followed by remitting periods, leading to a range of physical, emotional, and social impacts that diminish their quality of life (QoL).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2676</offset><text>Although IBD is prevalent worldwide, Canada has one of the highest rates of IBD prevalence and incidence in the world. As of 2023, the prevalence stands at 0.8% and is forecasted to increase by 2.4% annually over the next decade. This upward trajectory poses significant public health challenges, placing enormous financial strain on the Canadian healthcare system while also negatively impacting workforce productivity, as individuals often face periods of disability or diminished work performance.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3177</offset><text>Core disease assessment measures for CD and UC primarily focus on objective indicators, such as endoscopic and biomarker-based evaluations. Subjective symptoms such as bowel urgency and abdominal pain, which individuals consistently rank as most important when prioritizing disease control are often underappreciated. Evolving evidence suggests that bowel urgency is closely correlated with disease activity, including findings from a Canadian IBD cohort study. Given its significant impact on individuals’ QoL, recent IBD guidelines have included resolution of bowel urgency as a key goal in treating patient-reported symptoms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3808</offset><text>This growing recognition reflects a broader movement toward incorporating both patient and healthcare professional (HCP) perspectives in IBD management. Previous qualitative and survey-based studies have aimed to understand CD and UC from the perspective of people with IBD and HCPs and have highlighted misalignments and communication gaps concerning symptom burden, disease impact, and treatment priorities. However, research specific to the Canadian population is limited, indicating a gap in understanding how these challenges are perceived and managed within the Canadian context.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4394</offset><text>The Communicating Needs and Features of IBD Experiences (CONFIDE) study aimed to evaluate the experience and impact of CD and UC on the lives of people with IBD and elucidate gaps in communication between them and HCPs. Previous analyses from the global CONFIDE surveys have provided valuable insights into patient and HCP perspectives in the United States, Europe, and Japan. The current study includes data from the CONFIDE surveys conducted among Canadian individuals with CD or UC and prescribing HCPs, with an emphasis on understanding the impact and burden of bowel urgency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>4975</offset><text>Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4983</offset><text>The CONFIDE study comprised 2 online, quantitative, cross-sectional surveys conducted between February and April 2023: one for individuals with moderate-to-severe CD or UC and another for prescribing HCPs managing CD and UC (Appendix S1). This survey was conducted in Canada as a replication of the CONFIDE survey that was conducted in the United States, Europe, and Japan. The survey was available in both English and French. Previously published studies from the CONFIDE survey conducted in the United States, Europe, and Japan include details on survey development, content, and data collection.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5582</offset><text>Study population</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5599</offset><text>Individuals with IBD and prescribing HCPs were recruited via independent, existing online panels and screened online to ensure that only eligible participants completed the survey (convenience sampling). Panel coordinators informed members about the details of the study via an email containing a link to the screener. Subsequently, if the individual/HCP was eligible, a link to the survey could also be accessed. Prior to screening, they also provided informed consent for their participation. Receiving the link to the survey did not imply consent or agreement to participate; respondents were required to actively choose to participate by clicking the link, providing informed consent, and meeting the screening criteria. All participants who completed the survey were provided with an honorarium.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6400</offset><text>Adults with self-reported, HCP-diagnosed, moderate-to-severe, active CD or UC were included. Active disease of at least moderate severity was defined using criteria from previously published CONFIDE studies (received anti-tumour necrosis factor [TNF], anti-integrin, Janus kinase [JAK] inhibitor, anti-interleukin-12/23 [IL-12/23], or immunomodulator treatment in the last 12 months, and/or received steroid treatment for at least 1 month out of the last 12 months, and/or were hospitalized for at least 4 consecutive weeks in the last 5 years). Individuals were excluded if they had undergone a colectomy. Individuals with a diagnosis of concomitant irritable bowel syndrome were no more than 20% of the total population. HCPs were included if they were gastroenterologists and were responsible for making prescribing decisions for at least 10 individuals with CD or UC, of which at least 5 were diagnosed with moderate-to-severe UC and/or CD per month and spent at least 50% of working time actively seeing patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7423</offset><text>Survey information and content</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7454</offset><text>The surveys were designed and conducted by Adelphi Real World in partnership with Eli Lilly and Company. They were co-developed with individuals with CD or UC and an advisory panel of gastroenterologist thought leaders from various countries, with expertise in clinical IBD, IBD patient-reported outcomes (PROs), and IBD survey design. Independent of these panels, Adelphi Real World also piloted the materials to further validate them prior to use. Additional information on the survey co-creation has been included in Appendix S1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7987</offset><text>Data were collected via 30-minute, structured online surveys designed to be completed in one sitting. The surveys were conducted through the “Confirmit” platform, supplied by FORSTA. To prevent duplicate participation, single-use links were distributed within a closed network of participants, ensuring that each respondent received a unique survey link. Non-response error was addressed by ensuring the survey was concise, accessible only via mobile, desktop, and laptop devices, and available exclusively online, so that participants could complete it without needing to visit a clinic or similar location.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8600</offset><text>The categories of data collected included demographic information, questions that examined the impact and burden of symptoms on QoL, productivity, and psychological and social health, and barriers in HCP-patient communication. Severity of bowel urgency over the last 3 days was rated using the Urgency Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) (scores ranging from 0 to 10, in which 0 indicated no urgency and 10 indicated the worst possible urgency). The survey questions included in this study are provided in Appendix S1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9110</offset><text>Statistical analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9131</offset><text>As this was a descriptive study, formal sample size estimations were not performed. A target of approximately 40 HCPs and 120 individuals with IBD (70 with CD and 50 with UC) was set to allow descriptive analysis at the regional level. Categorical variables were presented as frequencies and percentages. Continuous variables (eg age, time since diagnosis, and questions with numeric rating scale [NRS] responses) were presented as number of observations, means, and standard deviations. No direct comparisons between data from individuals with IBD with CD and UC were made. All analyses were conducted via Survey Reporter v7.5.1</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9761</offset><text>Ethical considerations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9784</offset><text>The protocol and surveys including consent language were approved by the Western Institutional Review Board. The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and was consistent with Good Pharmacoepidemiology Practices and applicable laws and regulations of Canada. For the completion of the survey, all participants were provided with a nominal honorarium.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>10189</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10197</offset><text>Demographics and clinical characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10239</offset><text>Overall, 400 individuals with CD and 373 individuals with UC were contacted, of which 107 with CD and 82 with UC completed the survey (26.8% and 22.0% response rates, respectively; Table S1). The mean [standard deviation (SD)] age of individuals with CD and UC was 45.1 [14.8] years and 43.5 [12.6] years, respectively; and 71.0% and 64.6% of individuals, respectively, were male. The mean [SD] time since diagnosis was 10.2 [10.2] years for those with CD and 6.3 [7.6] years for those with UC. At the time of survey completion, 78.5% of individuals with CD and 73.2% of individuals with UC were receiving advanced therapies (biologic therapy, biosimilars, or JAK inhibitors). Key demographics and characteristics for individuals with CD and UC are reported in Table 1.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>11009</offset><text>Demographics and characteristics of Canadian individuals with CD or UC and prescribing HCPs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col valign=&quot;top&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Individuals&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;CD (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; = 107)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;UC (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; = 82)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Mean age, years (SD)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;45.1 (14.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;43.5 (12.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Sex, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Male&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;76 (71.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;53 (64.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Female&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;31 (29.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;29 (35.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Ethnicity, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; White&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;96 (89.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;73 (89.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; South or Central American Native&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (3.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0 (0.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Asian-Indian subcontinent&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (2.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (1.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Black African or Caribbean&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (1.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2 (2.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; East or Southeast Asian&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (0.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (3.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Other&lt;xref rid=&quot;tblfn1&quot; ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (0.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3 (3.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Mean time since diagnosis of CD, years (SD)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;10.2 (10.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6.3 (7.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Individuals currently receiving advanced therapies&lt;xref rid=&quot;tblfn2&quot; ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;b&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;84 (78.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;60 (73.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Treatments prescribed for CD in the last 12 months, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Corticosteroids&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;61 (57.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;49 (59.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; 5-ASA&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;44 (41.1)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;36 (43.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Immunomodulator&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50 (46.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;29 (35.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Anti-TNF biologic therapy (TNF inhibitor)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;56 (52.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;26 (31.7)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Anti-integrin biologic therapy&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18 (16.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27 (32.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; JAK inhibitor&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;27 (25.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;29 (35.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Anti-IL-12/Anti-IL-23&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;33 (30.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13 (15.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Non-pharmacologic treatment&lt;xref rid=&quot;tblfn3&quot; ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;c&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (5.6)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;4 (4.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Other (not specified)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (0.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (1.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;HCPs&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Canada (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;N&lt;/italic&gt; = 53)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Sex, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Male&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;41 (77.4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Female&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11 (20.8)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Prefer not to say&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1 (1.9)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Primary specialty, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Gastroenterologist&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;53 (100)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;Practice Region, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;n&lt;/italic&gt; (%)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt;The Atlantic Provinces (Newfoundland/Labrador, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, or Prince Edward Island)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (17.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Quebec&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;6 (11.3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; Ontario&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16 (30.2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; The Prairie Provinces (Manitoba, Saskatchewan, or Alberta)&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9 (17.0)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;bold&gt; British Columbia&lt;/bold&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13 (24.5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>11102</offset><text>Individuals	CD (N = 107)	UC (N = 82)	 	Mean age, years (SD)	45.1 (14.8)	43.5 (12.6)	 	Sex, n (%)		 	 Male	76 (71.0)	53 (64.6)	 	 Female	31 (29.0)	29 (35.4)	 	Ethnicity, n (%)		 	 White	96 (89.7)	73 (89.0)	 	 South or Central American Native	4 (3.7)	0 (0.0)	 	 Asian-Indian subcontinent	3 (2.8)	1 (1.2)	 	 Black African or Caribbean	2 (1.9)	2 (2.4)	 	 East or Southeast Asian	1 (0.9)	3 (3.7)	 	 Othera	1 (0.9)	3 (3.7)	 	Mean time since diagnosis of CD, years (SD)	10.2 (10.2)	6.3 (7.6)	 	Individuals currently receiving advanced therapiesb, n (%)	84 (78.5)	60 (73.2)	 	Treatments prescribed for CD in the last 12 months, n (%)		 	 Corticosteroids	61 (57.0)	49 (59.8)	 	 5-ASA	44 (41.1)	36 (43.9)	 	 Immunomodulator	50 (46.7)	29 (35.4)	 	 Anti-TNF biologic therapy (TNF inhibitor)	56 (52.3)	26 (31.7)	 	 Anti-integrin biologic therapy	18 (16.8)	27 (32.9)	 	 JAK inhibitor	27 (25.2)	29 (35.4)	 	 Anti-IL-12/Anti-IL-23	33 (30.8)	13 (15.9)	 	 Non-pharmacologic treatmentc	6 (5.6)	4 (4.9)	 	 Other (not specified)	1 (0.9)	1 (1.2)	 	HCPs	Canada (N = 53)	 	Sex, n (%)	 	 Male	41 (77.4)	 	 Female	11 (20.8)	 	 Prefer not to say	1 (1.9)	 	Primary specialty, n (%)	 	 Gastroenterologist	53 (100)	 	Practice Region, n (%)	 	The Atlantic Provinces (Newfoundland/Labrador, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, or Prince Edward Island)	9 (17.0)	 	 Quebec	6 (11.3)	 	 Ontario	16 (30.2)	 	 The Prairie Provinces (Manitoba, Saskatchewan, or Alberta)	9 (17.0)	 	 British Columbia	13 (24.5)	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>12631</offset><text>Other comprises American Indian, Indigenous American, or Alaska Native (n = 1) for individuals with CD and First Nations, Inuit, or Métis (n = 2), and Other (n = 1) for individuals with UC.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>12834</offset><text>Adalimumab (including biosimilars), infliximab (including biosimilars), golimumab, certolizumab pegol, vedolizumab, natalizumab, ustekinumab, and tofacitinib.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>12993</offset><text>For example, dietary changes or homeopathic treatments.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036-T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>13049</offset><text>Abbreviations: 5-ASA: 5-aminosalicylic acid; CD: Crohn’s disease; HCP: healthcare professional; IL: interleukin; JAK: Janus kinase; N: number of participants; n: number of participants in the subgroup; SD: standard deviation; TNF: tumour necrosis factor; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13330</offset><text>A total of 70 Canadian gastroenterologists were contacted, of which 53 completed the surveys (75.7% response rate). Most HCPs were male (77.4%) and primarily practiced in Ontario or British Columbia (54.7%). Table 1 displays key HCP demographics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13577</offset><text>Patient and HCP perceptions on CD and UC symptoms</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13627</offset><text>Diarrhoea (48.6%), bowel urgency (43.9%), and loud stomach gurgling/rumbling (40.2%) were the top 3 symptoms most commonly experienced by individuals with CD in the past month. Among individuals with UC, diarrhoea (39.0%), bowel urgency (30.5%), and fatigue/tiredness (29.3%) were the most commonly experienced symptoms in the past month (Figure 1A). The top 3 symptoms ever experienced by individuals with CD and UC were diarrhoea (70.1% and 62.2%), bowel urgency (67.3% and 56.1%), and increased stool frequency (59.8% and 51.2%), respectively (Figure 1A). Similar results were observed among those receiving advanced therapies ­(Figure 1B). More than a third of individuals receiving advanced therapies experienced diarrhoea in the past month. Additionally, over a quarter of the population reported experiencing bowel urgency during the same period.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036f1.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>14482</offset><text>Individual and HCP perceptions on CD and UC symptoms. (A) Top 3 symptoms ever or currently experienced by individuals with CD or UC at the time of survey completion. Symptoms were selected from a list of 30 options. Individuals were asked which symptoms they have ever suffered from and currently suffer from (ie, in the past month). (B) Top 3 symptoms ever or currently experienced by individuals with CD or UC receiving advanced therapies*. (C) Top 3 HCP-perceived most common symptoms reported by individuals. HCPs were asked to rank the top 3 symptoms most reported by individuals with CD or UC. (D) Top 5 patient-reported symptoms with the greatest impact (of symptoms ever experienced). Individuals were asked to rank the top 5 symptoms that have the greatest impact. (E) Top 5 HCP-perceived symptoms with the greatest impact on their patients. HCPs were asked to rank the top 5 symptoms with the greatest impact on patients. *Advanced therapy included adalimumab (including biosimilars), infliximab (including biosimilars), golimumab, certolizumab pegol, vedolizumab, natalizumab, ustekinumab, and tofacitinib. Abbreviations: CD: Crohn’s disease; HCP, healthcare professional; N: number of patients; n: number of participants in the sub-population; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15764</offset><text>When HCPs were asked to rank the symptoms most reported by individuals with CD or UC, the top 3 CD symptoms were diarrhoea (62.3%), persistent abdominal pain (45.3%), and blood in stool (39.6%). Bowel urgency was ranked among the top 3 most reported symptoms by only 17.0% of HCPs. For individuals with UC, the top 3 HCP-ranked common symptoms were diarrhoea (64.2%), blood in stool (49.1%), and bowel urgency (45.3%) (Figure 1C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16195</offset><text>According to individuals with CD, the top 5 most impactful symptoms were diarrhoea (68.0%), bowel urgency (66.7%), bowel movement accidents (56.1%), fatigue/tiredness (51.1%), and bowel urgency-related accidents (51.0%). For those with UC, these were bowel movement accidents (72.4%), bowel urgency (71.7%), blood in stool (70.3%), diarrhoea (68.6%), and increased stool frequency (61.9%) (Figure 1D). Similar to individuals with CD or UC, HCPs also reported the most impactful symptoms: diarrhoea (67.9%), persistent abdominal pain (49.1%), blood in stool (41.5%), increased stool frequency (41.5%), and bowel urgency-related accidents (39.6%) for those with CD; diarrhoea (73.6%), blood in stool (67.9%), bowel urgency (56.6%), bowel urgency-related accidents (49.1%), and increased stool frequency (41.5%) for those with UC (Figure 1E).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17035</offset><text>Experience and impact of CD and UC symptoms</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17079</offset><text>When asked about deferral time (a measure of urgency individuals experience before bowel movements) in the last 3 days, 47.7% of individuals with CD and 28.1% of individuals with UC reported that they could not defer defaecation for more than 5 minutes (Figure 2A). Among those who reported currently experiencing bowel urgency, 40.4% of individuals with CD and 48.0% of individuals with UC rated its severity as at least 8 out of 10 using the 11-point Urgency NRS (range 0 [no urgency] to 10 [worst possible urgency]) scale (Figure 2B). Mean [SD] Urgency NRS scores for individuals with CD and UC were reported as 6.8 [2.4] and 6.8 [1.6], respectively. When individuals who reported experiencing bowel urgency were asked about their bowel urgency frequency, a majority reported experiencing it at least once a week in the past 3 months (CD: 61.1%; UC: 47.8%; Figure 2C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036f2.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-F2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>17951</offset><text>Individual experience of bowel urgency. (A) Individuals’ deferral time in the last 3 days. All individuals were asked how much urgency they experienced before bowel movements over the last 3 days. (B) Urgency Numeric Rating Scale (NRS). Individuals who reported experiencing bowel urgency in the past month rated their urgency (sudden or immediate need) to have a bowel movement in the last 3 days (from 0 [no urgency] to 10 [worst possible urgency]). (C) Frequency of bowel urgency in the past 3 months among individuals who reported ever experiencing bowel urgency. Abbreviations: CD: Crohn’s disease; N: number of participants; n: number of participants in the sub-population; SD: standard deviation; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18683</offset><text>Overall, 59.8% of Canadian individuals with CD and 68.3% of those with UC reported wearing a diaper/pad/protection at least once during the past 3 months due to fear or anticipation of bowel urgency-related accidents (Figure 3A). Of those with CD and UC receiving advanced therapies, 57.1% and 73.3%, respectively, reported using these protective undergarments at least once a month. As a consequence of bowel urgency, 37.5% of individuals with CD and 47.8% of individuals with UC who had ever experienced bowel urgency, reported having worked fewer hours (Figure 3B). Moreover, bowel urgency was reported by individuals as the most common reason for declining participation in work/school (CD: 31.8%; UC: 26.8%), social events (CD: 36.4%; UC: 23.2%), and sports/physical exercise (CD: 37.4%; UC: 20.7%) in the last 3 months (Figure 3C). Among those experiencing bowel urgency in the past month, most individuals with CD or UC also reported a high emotional impact (scores &gt;4 on a scale of 1 [does not interfere at all] to 7 [interferes a great deal]) across various emotional parameters (Figure 3D).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036f3.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-F3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>19784</offset><text>Impact of bowel urgency on the daily lives of individuals with CD or UC. (A) Frequency of diaper/pad/other protection use in the past 3 months due to fear/anticipation of bowel urgency-related accidents. (B) Impact of bowel urgency on work/school (among those who ever experienced bowel urgency). (C) Individuals who declined participation in work/school-related, social, or physical activities due to bowel urgency or bowel urgency-related accidents. (D) Impact of bowel urgency on emotional well-being. Individuals who reported experiencing bowel urgency in the past month rated the extent to which bowel urgency interferes with various emotional parameters, on a scale of 1 (does not interfere at all) to 7 (interferes a great deal). Abbreviations: CD: Crohn’s disease; N: number of participants; n: number of participants in the sub-population; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20659</offset><text>HCP-patient communication</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20685</offset><text>Among individuals with CD or UC who reported experiencing bowel urgency in the past month, 61.7% of those with CD and 64.0% of those with UC reported discussing bowel urgency with their HCPs frequently or at every appointment (Figure 4A). Of those who did not discuss this symptom at every HCP appointment, most (CD: 72.2%; UC: 87.5%) reported that they would like to discuss it more frequently. Among those who had ever experienced bowel urgency, 16.7% of individuals with CD and 21.7% of individuals with UC did not feel comfortable discussing bowel urgency with their HCPs (scores ≤4 on a scale of 1 [not at all comfortable] to 10 [completely comfortable]) (Figure 4B). The most common reason cited by individuals with CD for feeling uncomfortable reporting bowel urgency to their HCPs was the difficulty in explaining this symptom (41.7%). Individuals with UC cited embarrassment as the most common reason (60.0%) (Figure 4C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036f4.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-F4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>21618</offset><text>Patient communication with HCPs regarding bowel urgency. (A) Frequency of patient discussion of bowel urgency with HCPs (among those currently experiencing bowel urgency). (B) Patient comfort levels when discussing bowel urgency with their HCP, on a scale of 1 (not at all comfortable) to 7 (completely comfortable), among individuals who ever experienced bowel urgency. (C) Reasons for individuals feeling uncomfortable reporting bowel urgency to HCPs. Abbreviations: CD: Crohn’s disease; N: number of participants; n: number of participants in the sub-population; HCP: healthcare professional; SD: standard deviation; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22264</offset><text>The top 4 symptoms proactively discussed by HCPs at a routine appointment were diarrhoea (CD: 96.2%; UC: 92.5%), blood in stool (CD: 90.6%; UC: 94.3%), increased stool frequency (CD: 92.5%; UC: 88.7%), and bowel urgency (CD: 66.0%; UC: 84.9%) (Figure 5A). Of the HCPs who did not proactively discuss bowel urgency at a routine appointment, a majority expected their patients to bring this up if it were an issue (CD: 44.4%; UC: 62.5%) (Figure 5B). Moreover, a majority of HCPs believed that their patients were comfortable reporting bowel urgency to them (scores &gt;4 on a scale of 1 [not at all comfortable] to 10 [completely comfortable]; CD: 83.1%; UC: 73.6%) (Figure 5C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">gwaf036f5.jpg</infon><infon key="id">gwaf036-F5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22938</offset><text>HCP-patient communication. (A) HCP-reported symptoms proactively discussed at a routine appointment. (B) Reasons for HCPs not proactively discussing bowel urgency in routine appointments. (C) HCP-perceived individual comfort levels when reporting bowel urgency, on a scale of 1 (not at all comfortable) to 7 (completely comfortable). (D) HCP-perceived most impactful symptoms on treatment decisions. HCPs were asked to choose from a list of possible symptoms the top 3 most impactful on treatment decisions. Abbreviations: CD: Crohn’s disease; N: number of participants; n: number of participants in the sub-population; HCP: healthcare professional; SD: standard deviation; UC: ulcerative colitis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23638</offset><text>HCPs were also asked to rank the top 3 most impactful symptoms on their treatment decisions for their patients with CD or UC (Figure 5D). For individuals with CD, HCPs ranked diarrhoea (56.6%), blood in stool (47.2%), and persistent abdominal pain (35.8%) as most impactful. For individuals with UC, blood in stool (69.8%), diarrhoea (62.3%), and bowel urgency (34.0%) were ranked as most impactful.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>24038</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24049</offset><text>This study provided important real-world perspectives on the experience and symptom burden of CD and UC among individuals in Canada. The results suggest a substantial impact of these symptoms on individuals’ daily lives, even though more than 70% of the population reported receiving advanced therapies. The study also examined HCP perspectives on CD and UC-related symptoms and highlighted communication gaps in both disease states. Although both HCPs and individuals with IBD reported a considerable symptom burden, their perceptions regarding the most impactful symptoms differed. To our knowledge, this is the first real-world study in Canada to compare the perceptions and views of individuals with IBD and prescribing HCPs regarding CD- and UC-related symptoms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24819</offset><text>Diarrhoea and bowel urgency were identified as the most common symptoms among Canadian individuals with CD or UC. Additionally, bowel urgency was reported as one of the most impactful symptoms experienced, consistent with previous global studies as well as the CONFIDE survey conducted in the United States, Europe, and Japan. A substantial proportion of individuals indicated an inability to defer defaecation for more than 5 minutes (CD: 47.7%; UC: 28.1%), and more than half of the CD/UC population reported using diapers/pads/other protection at least once a month due to fear or anticipation of bowel urgency-related accidents. Considering the young mean age of the study population and the high proportion of individuals receiving advanced therapies, the frequent use of protective undergarments underscores the severe impact of bowel urgency on individuals, as also evidenced by most individuals rating its severity as 6 out of 10 or higher on the Urgency NRS scale. Consequently, individuals reported that bowel urgency adversely affected their daily lives, limiting their participation in social and physical activities, and negatively affecting their work hours. Emotional distress, including feelings of anger, resentment, embarrassment, and panic were commonly reported, contributing to an increased psychological burden. These findings align with previous studies that highlight bowel urgency as a particularly troublesome symptom among the various symptoms experienced by individuals with CD or UC, significantly impacting their overall QoL. Despite the clinical differences between CD and UC, similar findings were observed in both CD and UC study populations, emphasizing the comparable burden and experience of bowel urgency in both disease states. This highlights an unmet need for treatment options that effectively address impactful symptoms such as diarrhoea diarrhoeal urgency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26719</offset><text>Although bowel urgency was noted as an impactful symptom by individuals with CD and UC, HCPs regarded it as a more significant concern in UC than in CD. According to HCPs in Canada, the most common and impactful symptoms affecting individuals with CD and influencing treatment decisions were diarrhoea, persistent abdominal pain, and blood in stool—all of which are commonly associated with the diagnosis of CD. In contrast, for UC, the most common and impactful HCP-perceived symptoms were diarrhoea, blood in stool, and bowel urgency. This misalignment indicates an underappreciation of bowel urgency in CD. HCPs often link bowel urgency to rectal or perirectal inflammation, which is more common in UC, potentially underestimating its role in CD, where inflammation is less localized. Further efforts are required to develop a more holistic approach to symptom management in IBD, where bowel urgency and incontinence is routinely asked in clinical encounters for people with CD and UC.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27710</offset><text>Most HCPs reported proactively discussing bowel urgency with their patients with CD or UC, but approximately 40% of individuals with CD or UC experiencing this symptom reported discussing it infrequently with their HCPs. Notably, HCPs were also more likely to engage in these discussions with individuals with UC compared to those with CD. However, for other common symptoms such as diarrhoea, blood in stool, and increased stool frequency, about 90% of HCPs reported engaging in proactive discussions with both individuals with CD and UC, reinforcing the notion that bowel urgency is commonly underestimated in CD. Furthermore, while over 70% of HCPs believe their patients feel comfortable discussing bowel urgency, many individuals also expressed difficulty in explaining this symptom or felt embarrassed to talk about it. This difference in perception highlights a significant communication gap between individuals with IBD and HCPs. Previous studies support this finding, showing that people often avoid discussing sensitive symptoms like bowel urgency due to feelings of shame and fear of not being taken seriously, which is largely driven by the social stigma associated with bowel-related symptoms. Proactive communication between HCPs and individuals with IBD in clinical settings is therefore essential for improving health outcomes. In addition to clinical assessments, HCPs should aim to understand how bothersome symptoms affect patients’ daily functioning, emotional well-being, and overall QoL. This patient-centred approach could support shared decision-making and help tailor treatment strategies to individual needs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29347</offset><text>This study was subject to a number of limitations. First, participant eligibility, diagnosis of concomitant irritable bowel syndrome, and survey responses were self-reported, which could potentially lead to recall bias and impact data reliability negatively. However, since most survey questions referred to a specific, recent time frame (eg the past month), this likely mitigated the impact of recall bias. Additionally, the sampling frame may not be representative of the general IBD population as those who volunteer for these surveys may represent a specific population, especially those who are more proactive in managing their disease and communicating with HCPs. While the survey was available in both English and French, it was not translated into other languages, which could have led to participation mainly from non-immigrant individuals. In fact, respondents were mainly Caucasian in both CD and UC cohorts, which could limit the generalizability of the findings. Additionally, the limited geographic distribution of HCP respondents may have also impacted the generalizability of the results.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>30452</offset><text>Conclusions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30464</offset><text>The findings from this study provide important insights into the experience and symptom burden of CD and UC on individuals in Canada which could influence payers’ decision-making on drug coverage. Despite the introduction of several advanced therapies, a substantial proportion of individuals indicated experiencing symptoms that affected their QoL. Notably, bowel urgency was identified as a common and impactful symptom for individuals with CD and UC. Differences between perceptions among individuals with IBD and HCPs regarding the most impactful symptoms were also noted, underscoring the need for improved communication. In general, the findings in the current analysis were consistent with those of the CONFIDE study conducted in the United States, Europe, and Japan. These results emphasize the importance of a comprehensive strategy for managing CD and UC in Canada to improve therapeutic decision-making.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31381</offset><text>Supplementary Material</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31404</offset><text>Author contributions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31425</offset><text>Conception or design of the work: V.J., T.B., J.G., T.H.G., M.B., T.M., C.A., H.E., T.D., R.P. Acquisition of data: C.A., H.E., T.D. Analysis of data: T.B., J.G., M.B., C.A., H.E., T.D. Interpretation of data: V.J., T.B., J.G., M.B., T.H.G., T.M., C.A., H.E., T.D., R.P. Drafting and/or critical review of the work: V.J., T.B., J.G., M.B., T.H.G., T.M., C.A., H.E., T.D., R.P.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31802</offset><text>Supplementary material</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31825</offset><text> Supplementary material is available at Journal of the Canadian Association of Gastroenterology online.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>31929</offset><text>Funding</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ACK_FUND</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31937</offset><text>This study and the journal’s article processing fee are funded by Eli Lilly and Company. Medical writing assistance, funded by Eli Lilly and Company, was provided by Mythili Ananth of Eli Lilly and Company.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>32146</offset><text>Conflicts of interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32168</offset><text>Vipul Jairath: Consultant: AbbVie, Alimentiv, Anaptyis Bio, Arena pharmaceuticals, Asahi Kasei Pharma, Asieris, Astra Zeneca, Boehringer Ingelmein, Bristol Myers Squibb, Calluna, Celltrion, Eli Lilly, Endpoint Health, Enthera, Ensho, Exceliom, Ferring Ventures, Flagship Pioneering, Fresenius Kabi, Galapagos, GlaxoSmithKline, Genentech, Gilead, Granite Bio, Innomar, JAMP, Janssen, Merck, Metacrine, Mylan, MRM Health, Nxera, OSE therapeutics, Pandion, Pendopharm, Pfizer, Protagonist, Prometheus Biosciences, Reistone Biopharma, Roche, Roivant, Sandoz, Second Genome, Shattuck Labs, Sorriso, Spyre, Synedgen, Takeda, Teva, Ventus, Ventyx, Vividion, and Xencor. Payment or honoraria: AbbVie, Ferring, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Fresenius Kabi, Janssen, Pfizer, Shire, Takeda, and Tillotts. Advisory board: AbbVie, Alimentiv, Anaptyis Bio, Arena pharmaceuticals, Asahi Kasei Pharma, Asieris, Astra Zeneca, Boehringer Ingelmein, Bristol Myers Squibb, Calluna, Celltrion, Eli Lilly, Endpoint Health, Enthera, Ensho, Exceliom, Ferring Ventures, Flagship Pioneering, Fresenius Kabi, Galapagos, GlaxoSmithKline, Genentech, Gilead, Granite Bio, Innomar, JAMP, Janssen, Merck, Metacrine, Mylan, MRM Health, Nxera, OSE therapeutics, Pandion, Pendopharm, Pfizer, Protagonist, Prometheus Biosciences, Reistone Biopharma, Roche, Roivant, Sandoz, Second Genome, Shattuck Labs, Sorriso, Spyre, Synedgen, Takeda, Teva, Ventus, Ventyx, Vividion, and Xencor.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33617</offset><text>Talat Bessissow: Speaker, consultant and research support: Abbvie, Alimentiv, Bristol-Myers Squibb, CSF Vifor, Celltrion, Eli Lilly, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Gilead, Iterative scope, Johnson and Johnson, Merck, Mirium, Pendopharm, Pentax, Pfizer, Roche, Sandoz, Sanofi, Takeda, and Viatris.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33908</offset><text>Jennifer Glass, Marta Braun, Theresa Hunter Gibble, and Taline Movsessian: Employees and shareholders of Eli Lilly and Company.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34036</offset><text>Remo Panaccione: Consultant: Abbott, AbbVie, Abbivax, Alimentiv (formerly Robarts), Amgen, AnaptysBio, Arena Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Celltrion, Cosmos Pharmaceuticals, Eisai, Elan, Eli Lilly, Ferring, Galapagos, Fresenius Kabi, Genentech, Gilead Sciences, Glaxo-Smith Kline, JAMP Bio, Janssen, Merck, Mylan, Novartis, Oppilan Pharma, Organon, Pandion Pharma, Pendopharm, Pfizer, Progenity, Prometheus Biosciences, Protagonist Therapeutics, Roche, Sandoz, Satisfai Health, Shire, Sublimity Therapeutics, Spyre Therapeutics, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Theravance Biopharma, Trellus, Union Biopharma, Viatris, Ventyx, and UCB. Speaker: AbbVie, Amgen, Arena Pharmaceuticals, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Gilead Sciences, Janssen, Merck, Organon, Pfizer, Roche, Sandoz, Shire, and Takeda Pharmaceuticals. Advisory Board: AbbVie, Alimentiv (formerly Robarts), Amgen, Arena Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Genentech, Gilead Sciences, Glaxo-Smith Kline, JAMP Bio, Janssen, Merck, Mylan, Novartis, Oppilan Pharma, Organon, Pandion Pharma, Pfizer, ­Progenity, Protagonist Therapeutics, Roche, SandozShire, Sublimity Therapeutics, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, and Ventyx.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35390</offset><text>Christian Atkinson, Hilary Ellis, Thomas Dewar: Employees of Adelphi Real World.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35471</offset><text>Conflict of interest disclosure forms (ICMJE) have been collected for all co-authors and can be accessed as supplementary material.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>35603</offset><text>Data availability</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">SUPPL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35621</offset><text>The datasets analyzed during the current study are not publicly available due to proprietary reasons and are intellectual properties of Eli Lilly and Company.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>35780</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">17</infon><infon key="lpage">30</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(19)30333-4</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31648971</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>35791</offset><text>The global, regional, and national burden of inflammatory bowel disease in 195 countries and territories, 1990–2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">416</infon><infon key="lpage">423</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37738497</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">S D Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">76</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>35976</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease: a concise review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">643</infon><infon key="lpage">654</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/s2468-1253(19)30173-6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31171484</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>36021</offset><text>Comorbidities in inflammatory bowel disease: a call for action</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1741</infon><infon key="lpage">1755</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)31711-1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27914655</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">389</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>36084</offset><text>Crohn’s ­disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1756</infon><infon key="lpage">1770</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)32126-2</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27914657</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Lancet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">389</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>36104</offset><text>Ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">862</infon><infon key="lpage">869</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ibd/izab192</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34347048</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>36123</offset><text>What is a flare? The Manitoba Living with IBD Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">989</infon><infon key="lpage">1005</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/21642850.2021.2007098</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34868738</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Health Psychol Behav Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>36175</offset><text>Quality of life in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: the role of positive psychological factors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">S9</infon><infon key="lpage">S15</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/jcag/gwad004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37674492</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Can Assoc Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>36279</offset><text>The 2023 impact of inflammatory bowel disease in Canada: epidemiology of IBD</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">811</infon><infon key="lpage">817</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1155/2012/984575</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23166905</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Can J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>36356</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease: a Canadian burden of illness review</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>36420</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">742</infon><infon key="lpage">751</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ibd/izx100</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29562277</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>36421</offset><text>Quality of life in inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta-analyses—part I</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e594</infon><infon key="lpage">e602</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/meg.0000000000002178</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34014623</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">33</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>36515</offset><text>Work productivity loss is determined by fatigue and reduced quality of life in employed inflammatory bowel disease patients: a prospective multicentre cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">17562848241251600</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1177/17562848241251600</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Therap Adv Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>36679</offset><text>Biomarkers in inflammatory bowel disease: a practical guide</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">152</infon><infon key="lpage">156</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.dld.2016.09.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27717791</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Liver Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>36739</offset><text>Patient preferences for inflammatory bowel disease treatment objectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">otab046</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/crocol/otab046</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36776663</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crohn’s Colitis 360</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>36811</offset><text>Prevalence and factors associated with fecal urgency among patients with ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease in the study of a prospective adult research cohort with inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1570</infon><infon key="lpage">1580</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/apt.17241</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36225106</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment Pharmacol Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>37009</offset><text>Urgency for bowel movements is a highly discriminatory symptom of active disease in persons with IBD (the Manitoba Living with IBD Study)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">95</infon><infon key="lpage">100</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36866112</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterol Hepatol (N Y)</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>37147</offset><text>Why studying urgency is urgent</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>37178</offset></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>37179</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">384</infon><infon key="lpage">413</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000000152</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30840605</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">114</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>37180</offset><text>ACG clinical guideline: ulcerative colitis in adults</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1942</infon><infon key="lpage">1953</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ibd/izab006</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33512475</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">27</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>37233</offset><text>International perspectives on management of inflammatory bowel disease: opinion differences and similarities between patients and physicians from the IBD GAPPS survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">108</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1471-230X-12-108</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22894661</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>37400</offset><text>Perception gaps between patients with ulcerative colitis and healthcare professionals: an online survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">317</infon><infon key="lpage">325</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s40271-019-00407-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31997116</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Patient</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>37504</offset><text>A qualitative research for defining meaningful attributes for the treatment of inflammatory bowel disease from the patient perspective</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1831</infon><infon key="lpage">1842</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ibd/izae044</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38513272</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>37639</offset><text>Patient perspectives of bowel urgency and bowel urgency-related accidents in ­ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">otaa033</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/crocol/otaa033</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36777302</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crohns Colitis 360</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>37759</offset><text>Patient’s perspective on disease burden, remission definition, and symptoms associated with treatment seeking: a qualitative study in adult and adolescent patients with Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">263</infon><infon key="lpage">278</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2147/ceg.S206970</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31354328</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Exp Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>37948</offset><text>Patient and physician preferences for ulcerative colitis treatments in the United States</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2333</infon><infon key="lpage">2344</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s10620-024-08434-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38700629</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Dig Dis Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>38037</offset><text>Patient and health care professional perceptions of the experience and impact of symptoms of moderate-to-severe Crohn’s disease in US and Europe: results from the cross-sectional CONFIDE study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">939</infon><infon key="lpage">949</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ibd/izad142</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37603837</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Bowel Dis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">30</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>38232</offset><text>The Communicating Needs and Features of IBD Experiences (CONFIDE) study: US and European patient and health care professional perceptions of the experience and impact of symptoms of moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1834</infon><infon key="lpage">1859</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s12325-024-03078-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40016440</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>38452</offset><text>Patient and health care professional perspectives on the burden and daily life impact of ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease: results from the Japanese CONFIDE study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">otab050</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/crocol/otab050</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36776662</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crohns Colitis 360</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>38623</offset><text>Novel approaches identifying relevant patient-reported outcomes in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases—LISTEN 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1056</infon><infon key="lpage">1064</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/meg.0000000000000658</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27286569</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>38743</offset><text>Perception of disease burden and treatment satisfaction in patients with ulcerative colitis from outpatient clinics in Spain: UC-LIFE survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1731</infon><infon key="lpage">1733.e2</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2023.12.019</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38151168</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>38884</offset><text>Fecal urgency in ulcerative colitis: impact on quality of life and psychological well-being in active and inactive disease states</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">431</infon><infon key="lpage">450</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s12325-023-02726-4</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37999831</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv Ther</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">41</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>39014</offset><text>Bowel urgency in patients with ulcerative colitis and Crohn’s disease: a cross-sectional real-world survey in Japan</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1365</infon><infon key="lpage">1375</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22230271</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am Fam Physician</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">84</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>39132</offset><text>Diagnosis and management of Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1940</infon><infon key="lpage">1953</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000002404</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37436151</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Gastroenterol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">118</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>39178</offset><text>Bowel urgency in ulcerative colitis: current perspectives and future directions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">113</infon><infon key="lpage">120</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2147/jir.S65979</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25075198</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Inflamm Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>39258</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease: clinical aspects and treatments</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">403</infon><infon key="lpage">412</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s40801-024-00434-1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38878264</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Drugs Real World Outcomes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>39318</offset><text>The clinical course of bowel urgency severity among patients with inflammatory bowel disease—a real-world study</text></passage></document>
</collection>