<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20260212</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC12865409</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.3389/fmicb.2025.1696524</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC12865409</infon><infon key="elocation-id">1696524</infon><infon key="kwd">inflammatory bowel disease engineered probiotics ulcerative colitis Crohn’s disease genetic engineering precision medicine gut microbiome biosafety</infon><infon key="license">This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:Xiaohua</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cheng;given-names:Yindi</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Huang;given-names:Jiahui</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Xu;given-names:Feixuan</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jiang;given-names:Jian</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Nalinratana;given-names:Nonthaneth</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Jin;given-names:Litong</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Xue;given-names:Ying</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Engineered probiotics for inflammatory bowel disease therapy: mechanisms, delivery strategies, and precision medicine</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>118</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), encompassing ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn’s disease (CD), is a prevalent chronic gastrointestinal disorder. Conventional therapies are often limited by adverse effects and suboptimal long-term efficacy. Probiotics have emerged as promising therapeutic alternatives for IBD because of their ability to modulate the gut microbiota, reinforce intestinal barrier integrity, and regulate immune responses. However, their clinical translation is hampered by challenges within the harsh gastrointestinal milieu, including low viability, poor colonization, and insufficient target specificity. This review focuses on the engineering of probiotics designed to overcome these limitations for IBD management. We outline the therapeutic potential and mechanisms of action of probiotics in IBD, with a critical emphasis on discrepancies between preclinical and clinical observations. We subsequently discuss the drawbacks of conventional probiotic therapies, highlighting gaps between in vitro efficacy and in vivo performance. We then highlight cutting-edge engineering strategies, encompassing advanced encapsulation techniques, genetic engineering approaches, novel delivery systems, and molecular-targeting modifications, with quantitative comparisons of their advantages, limitations, and translational potential. The application of these engineered probiotics specifically in UC and CD treatment is explored, with detailed analyses of preclinical models and clinical trials. We also address personalized interventions tailored to individual gut microbiome profiles. Despite significant promise, critical challenges remain, including long-term safety, stability, and accurate prediction of therapeutic responses for engineered probiotics in IBD. Nevertheless, with ongoing advancements in gene editing, synthetic biology, and microbial safety engineering, engineered probiotics represent a promising direction in IBD therapy that will enable more precise, effective, and personalized treatment modalities, provided that safety, reproducibility, and regulatory compliance are prioritized.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2239</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2252</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is a chronic, relapsing inflammatory disorder of the gastrointestinal tract with significant geographical variations in global distribution. Canada has the highest prevalence of IBD (approximately 0.7%), followed by the United States (0.3%) and Europe (0.2%). In the early 20th century, IBD primarily occurred in developed Western countries. However, with accelerated industrialization and urbanization and the adoption of Western lifestyles, the disease has rapidly spread to emerging industrialized regions (e.g., Asia, South America, and the Middle East), with sharp increases in its incidence and prevalence, making it a global public health concern.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>2940</offset><text>Literature search strategy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2967</offset><text>To ensure comprehensiveness and rigor, a structured literature retrieval process was implemented in this review. We searched the PubMed, Web of Science, and Scopus databases using the following keywords: (“engineered probiotics” OR “genetically modified probiotics” OR “encapsulated probiotics”) AND (“inflammatory bowel disease” OR “ulcerative colitis” OR “Crohn’s disease”) AND (“mechanism” OR “delivery” OR “precision medicine” OR “clinical trial” OR “biosafety”). The retrieval period was limited to 2010–2025 to focus on recent advancements, with additional inclusion of foundational studies (e.g.,) for context. We excluded preprint articles, conference abstracts, and studies with unclear methodologies or irrelevant endpoints. A total of 247 articles were initially screened, and 189 articles were included after full-text review—this narrative review integrates mechanistic, preclinical, clinical, and regulatory evidence to provide a balanced perspective.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>3983</offset><text>Current challenges in IBD management</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4020</offset><text>Currently, the clinical management of IBD primarily involves pharmaceutical therapies and surgical interventions. Commonly used drugs include aminosalicylates, corticosteroids, immunosuppressants, and biological agents. However, these drugs generally have problems such as low specificity, high toxicity and significant adverse reactions. Approximately 15% of IBD patients worldwide require surgical intervention because of poor drug efficacy, but surgery is associated with high risks and long-term disability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4532</offset><text>Rationale for engineered probiotics in IBD</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4575</offset><text>Intestinal microbial dysbiosis plays a key role in IBD pathogenesis (Figure 1). IBD patients usually have an imbalance in the composition of their intestinal microbiota, which is specifically manifested by a decrease in the number of beneficial bacteria and an increase in the number of harmful bacteria (Table 1). Probiotics can effectively inhibit the growth of pathogenic bacteria by competing for nutrients and adhesion sites. Moreover, the organic acids produced by probiotics can reduce the intestinal pH, thereby inhibiting the proliferation of pathogenic bacteria such as Escherichia coli (E. coli) and Salmonella. Probiotics can also increase the expression of tight junction proteins between intestinal epithelial cells and stimulate the secretion of mucin, thereby strengthening the physical, chemical and immune barriers and consolidating the microbial barrier (Figure 2). In terms of immune regulation, probiotics can promote the secretion of anti-inflammatory cytokines and inhibit that of proinflammatory factors, thereby alleviating the chronic inflammation caused by an excessive immune response. Therefore, through various mechanisms, such as regulating intestinal flora balance, enhancing intestinal barrier function and modulating the immune response, probiotics have shown great potential and broad prospects in the treatment of IBD.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>5930</offset><text>Intestinal microbial dysbiosis in IBD. (A) It is manifested primarily by a reduction in the abundance of beneficial bacteria (Firmicutes, Dorea, Faecalibacterium, Holdemanella, Catenibacterium, Roseburia, and Ruminococcus) and an increase in the abundance of harmful bacteria (AIEC, ETBF, Fusobacterium nucleatum, Eggerthella lenta, Campylobacter concisus, and sulfide producers). These changes disrupt the intestinal barrier, activate excessive immune responses, and exacerbate inflammation. AIEC: Adherent-invasive E. coli; ETBF: Enterotoxigenic Bacteroides fragilis; SCFAs: Short-chain fatty acids. (B) Heatmap of the relative abundance of gut bacterial changes in patients with CD and UC. It displays the relative abundance of gut bacterial species with increased (red) and decreased (blue) abundance [data from ]. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>6771</offset><text>Microbiota in inflammatory bowel disease: mechanisms of disease and therapeutic opportunities.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Bacteria&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Dysbiosis in IBD&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Mechanisms of pathogenesis/therapeutic benefit&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;References&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. coli&lt;/italic&gt; (adherent and invasive)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. coli&lt;/italic&gt; adheres to and invades intestinal epithelial cells with high affinity, thereby surviving continuously in cells and evading clearance, activating excessive immune responses, destroying the integrity of the intestinal barrier, and simultaneously achieving dominant colonization by taking advantage of microbial imbalance. These changes ultimately lead to the initiation, amplification, and persistence of intestinal inflammation.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref78&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Ott et al. (2008)&lt;/xref&gt; and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref83&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Qiu et al. (2022)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Klebsiella&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Klebsiella&lt;/italic&gt; may participate in the occurrence and development of intestinal inflammation by stimulating intestinal immune responses, disrupting the intestinal barrier, or synergizing with other pathogenic bacteria, although the specific mechanisms remain under intensive investigation.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref48&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Kharaghani et al. (2023)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bacterooides fragilis&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. fragilis&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;The change in the abundance of &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. fragilis&lt;/italic&gt; in the intestines of IBD patients affects the balance of the gut microbiota. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. fragilis&lt;/italic&gt; may damage the intestinal mucosal barrier through its metabolites, increasing the intestinal permeability. This allows harmful substances to easily enter the tissues, triggering an inflammatory response and promoting the development of IBD. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. fragilis&lt;/italic&gt; can regulate the immune response by secreting various substances, thus influencing the progression of IBD.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref98&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Tomkovich &amp;amp; Jobin (2015)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Ruminococcus gnavus&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. gnavus&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Excessive &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. gnavus&lt;/italic&gt; proliferation in the intestine may inhibit the production of IL-10 while promoting the release of pro-inflammatory factors such as IL-17, leading to the exacerbation of intestinal inflammation. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. gnavus&lt;/italic&gt; can also activate immune cells, which release a large number of inflammatory mediators, further recruiting more immune cells to the inflamed site and forming an inflammatory cascade reaction, resulting in the damage and destruction of intestinal tissues.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref15&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Buttimer et al. (2023)&lt;/xref&gt; and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref42&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Hong et al. (2024)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Clostridium perfringens&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. perfringens&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. perfringens&lt;/italic&gt; directly attacks intestinal epithelial cells by secreting a variety of toxins, leading to cell necrosis or apoptosis. For instance, the toxic effects of toxins such as alpha toxin and beta toxin on cells impair the structure and function of epithelial cells, disrupt the tight junction structure between intestinal epithelial cells, and increase intestinal permeability.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref51&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Kuo et al. (2024)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Clostridium tertium&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. tertium&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. tertium&lt;/italic&gt; may disrupt the integrity and tight junctions of epithelial cells by secreting toxins or directly interacting with intestinal epithelial cells. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. tertium&lt;/italic&gt; may compete with beneficial bacteria for ecological niches and nutrients, thereby inhibiting the growth and reproduction of beneficial bacteria.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref58&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Li et al. (2021)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Faecalibacterium Prausnitzii&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. prausnitzii&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. prausnitzii&lt;/italic&gt; can increase the number and activity of Tregs and promote Tregs to secrete anti-inflammatory cytokines such as IL-10. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. prausnitzii&lt;/italic&gt; may secrete certain bioactive substances to promote the proliferation and differentiation of intestinal epithelial cells, thereby accelerating the repair of damaged mucosa. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. prausnitzii&lt;/italic&gt; can alleviate colonic inflammation by inhibiting the NLRP3 inflammasome and its downstream effector molecules.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref102&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Varela et al. (2013)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref107&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Wang X. L. et al. (2025)&lt;/xref&gt;, and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref109&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Wang Z. Y. et al. (2025)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Roseburia intestinalis&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. intestinalis&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. intestinalis&lt;/italic&gt; can inhibit the development of IBD by increasing the differentiation of anti-inflammatory Tregs. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. intestinalis&lt;/italic&gt; may alleviate intestinal inflammation by regulating the immune microenvironment and inhibiting the aggregation and activation of these pro-inflammatory cells. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;R. intestinalis&lt;/italic&gt; may indirectly affect the disease progression of IBD through the production of short-chain fatty acids.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref5&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Alizadeh et al. (2025)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Supplementation with &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/italic&gt; can increase the number of beneficial bacteria in the intestine and improve the intestinal microecological environment. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/italic&gt; can exert anti-inflammatory effects by regulating the secretion of cytokines by immune cells. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/italic&gt; produces metabolites such as short-chain fatty acids, which promote the growth and repair of intestinal epithelial cells.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref55&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Li M. F. et al. (2024)&lt;/xref&gt; and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref56&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Li M. M. et al. (2024)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/italic&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/italic&gt; restores the Th1/Th2 balance to a normal state by regulating the secretion of cytokines, thereby alleviating inflammatory responses. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/italic&gt; may influence the distribution and function of tight junction proteins by regulating intracellular signaling pathways, thus enhancing the connections between intestinal epithelial cells. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/italic&gt; can produce metabolites such as SCFAs, which can provide energy for intestinal epithelial cells, regulate intestinal pH, and inhibit inflammatory responses, among other functions.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref57&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Li et al. (2023)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Akkermansia muciniphila&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;A. muciniphila&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;A. muciniphila&lt;/italic&gt; contributes to restoring and enhancing the integrity of the mucus layer by promoting the production of mucin, thereby exerting a protective effect on the intestine. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;A. muciniphila&lt;/italic&gt; may repair and strengthen the intestinal epithelial barrier by regulating the expression of tight junction proteins, thus alleviating inflammatory responses. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;A. muciniphila&lt;/italic&gt; maintains the integrity of the intestinal barrier by reducing the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines and the infiltration of inflammatory cells, as well as increasing the expression of anti-inflammatory cytokines and the differentiation of Tregs, thereby alleviating colonic damage and colitis.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref9020&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Aja et al., 2025&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref61&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Liu J. et al. (2022)&lt;/xref&gt;, and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref62&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Liu Y. J. et al. (2022)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Eubacterium rectale&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. rectale&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;A reduction in the abundance of bacteria such as &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. rectale&lt;/italic&gt; may impair the normal function of the intestinal mucus layer, weakening its ability to resist pathogens and thereby increasing the risk of intestinal inflammation. A decrease in the abundance of &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. rectale&lt;/italic&gt; may disrupt immune homeostasis, leading to excessive activation of Th1 immune responses and exacerbating intestinal inflammation. Changes in the quantity or function of &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. rectale&lt;/italic&gt; may result in insufficient production of butyrate, depriving the intestine of the protective effects of butyrate—such as the inhibitory effects on inflammation and protective effects on intestinal barrier function—thereby promoting the development of IBD.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref81&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Pittayanon et al. (2020)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Veillonellaceae&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Veillonella&lt;/italic&gt; may affect the expression and release of cytokines, leading to an imbalance between pro-inflammatory cytokines and anti-inflammatory cytokines. &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Veillonella&lt;/italic&gt; may impair the function of intestinal mucus-secreting cells or directly degrade mucin components in the mucus layer, resulting in thinning of the mucus layer and damage to its integrity.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref100&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Tursi et al. (2025)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Collinsella aerofaciens&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. aerofaciens&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;C. aerofaciens&lt;/italic&gt; may be involved in the pathogenesis and development of inflammatory bowel disease through multiple aspects, such as regulating the structure of intestinal flora, affecting intestinal barrier function, and interfering with host immune regulation and butyrate production.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref84&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Quagliariello et al. (2020)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/italic&gt; GG (LGG)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;LGG may influence the differentiation direction of Th cells by regulating the function of antigen-presenting cells such as dendritic cells, thereby correcting the Th1/Th2 imbalance and alleviating inflammatory responses. The ROS induced by LGG can oxidize the key regulatory enzyme Ubc12, inactivating it, thus inhibiting the phosphorylation of IκB, preventing NF-κB from entering the nucleus, reducing the transcription and expression of inflammatory factors, and further alleviating intestinal inflammation. Additionally, LGG can promote the secretion of mucin by intestinal epithelial cells, increasing the thickness and viscosity of the mucus layer and thereby enhancing the physical barrier function of the intestine.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref126&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Zocco et al. (2006)&lt;/xref&gt; and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref119&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Zhai et al. (2024)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Bacillus subtilis&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. subtilis&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. subtilis&lt;/italic&gt; can upregulate the expression of tight junction proteins and enhance intestinal barrier function. It may regulate the function of intestinal goblet cells, promote mucus secretion, increase the thickness of the mucus layer, and thereby strengthen the protection of intestinal epithelium. Additionally, &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;B. subtilis&lt;/italic&gt; can inhibit the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines and promote the production of anti-inflammatory cytokines, which helps balance the body’s immune response and alleviate intestinal inflammation.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref64&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Liu S. et al. (2021)&lt;/xref&gt; and &lt;xref rid=&quot;ref63&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Liu W. et al. (2021)&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Fusobacterium nucleatum&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;F. nucleatum&lt;/italic&gt; can promote the apoptosis of intestinal epithelial cells, destroy tight junction proteins, exacerbate intestinal inflammatory responses, and induce intestinal flora dysbiosis.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref24&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Chen et al. (2020)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;Enterococcus faecium&lt;/italic&gt; (&lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. faecium&lt;/italic&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Increased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;ROS produced by &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. faecium&lt;/italic&gt; cause cellular oxidative stress damage, disrupt the intestinal mucosal barrier, and trigger inflammatory responses. Abnormal proliferation of &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. faecium&lt;/italic&gt; or certain substances produced by it may affect intestinal barrier function. As a part of the intestinal flora, the abnormal interaction between &lt;italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;E. faecium&lt;/italic&gt; and the host immune system may lead to immune imbalance, thereby inducing or exacerbating inflammatory bowel disease.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref90&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Seishima et al. (2019)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Decreased&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Phylum Firmicutes influences the disease mechanisms of inflammatory bowel disease through multiple pathways such as intestinal barrier function, immune regulation, bile acid metabolism, production of short-chain fatty acids, and oxidative stress.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;xref rid=&quot;ref54&quot; ref-type=&quot;bibr&quot;&gt;Li et al. (2016)&lt;/xref&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>6866</offset><text>Bacteria	Dysbiosis in IBD	Mechanisms of pathogenesis/therapeutic benefit	References	 	E. coli (adherent and invasive)	Increased	E. coli adheres to and invades intestinal epithelial cells with high affinity, thereby surviving continuously in cells and evading clearance, activating excessive immune responses, destroying the integrity of the intestinal barrier, and simultaneously achieving dominant colonization by taking advantage of microbial imbalance. These changes ultimately lead to the initiation, amplification, and persistence of intestinal inflammation.	 and 	 	Klebsiella	Increased	Klebsiella may participate in the occurrence and development of intestinal inflammation by stimulating intestinal immune responses, disrupting the intestinal barrier, or synergizing with other pathogenic bacteria, although the specific mechanisms remain under intensive investigation.		 	Bacterooides fragilis (B. fragilis)	Increased	The change in the abundance of B. fragilis in the intestines of IBD patients affects the balance of the gut microbiota. B. fragilis may damage the intestinal mucosal barrier through its metabolites, increasing the intestinal permeability. This allows harmful substances to easily enter the tissues, triggering an inflammatory response and promoting the development of IBD. Additionally, B. fragilis can regulate the immune response by secreting various substances, thus influencing the progression of IBD.		 	Ruminococcus gnavus (R. gnavus)	Increased	Excessive R. gnavus proliferation in the intestine may inhibit the production of IL-10 while promoting the release of pro-inflammatory factors such as IL-17, leading to the exacerbation of intestinal inflammation. R. gnavus can also activate immune cells, which release a large number of inflammatory mediators, further recruiting more immune cells to the inflamed site and forming an inflammatory cascade reaction, resulting in the damage and destruction of intestinal tissues.	 and 	 	Clostridium perfringens (C. perfringens)	Increased	C. perfringens directly attacks intestinal epithelial cells by secreting a variety of toxins, leading to cell necrosis or apoptosis. For instance, the toxic effects of toxins such as alpha toxin and beta toxin on cells impair the structure and function of epithelial cells, disrupt the tight junction structure between intestinal epithelial cells, and increase intestinal permeability.		 	Clostridium tertium (C. tertium)	Increased	C. tertium may disrupt the integrity and tight junctions of epithelial cells by secreting toxins or directly interacting with intestinal epithelial cells. Additionally, C. tertium may compete with beneficial bacteria for ecological niches and nutrients, thereby inhibiting the growth and reproduction of beneficial bacteria.		 	Faecalibacterium Prausnitzii (F. prausnitzii)	Decreased	F. prausnitzii can increase the number and activity of Tregs and promote Tregs to secrete anti-inflammatory cytokines such as IL-10. F. prausnitzii may secrete certain bioactive substances to promote the proliferation and differentiation of intestinal epithelial cells, thereby accelerating the repair of damaged mucosa. Additionally, F. prausnitzii can alleviate colonic inflammation by inhibiting the NLRP3 inflammasome and its downstream effector molecules.	, and 	 	Roseburia intestinalis (R. intestinalis)	Decreased	R. intestinalis can inhibit the development of IBD by increasing the differentiation of anti-inflammatory Tregs. R. intestinalis may alleviate intestinal inflammation by regulating the immune microenvironment and inhibiting the aggregation and activation of these pro-inflammatory cells. Additionally, R. intestinalis may indirectly affect the disease progression of IBD through the production of short-chain fatty acids.		 	Bifidobacterium	Decreased	Supplementation with Bifidobacterium can increase the number of beneficial bacteria in the intestine and improve the intestinal microecological environment. Bifidobacterium can exert anti-inflammatory effects by regulating the secretion of cytokines by immune cells. Bifidobacterium produces metabolites such as short-chain fatty acids, which promote the growth and repair of intestinal epithelial cells.	 and 	 	Lactobacillus	Decreased	Lactobacillus restores the Th1/Th2 balance to a normal state by regulating the secretion of cytokines, thereby alleviating inflammatory responses. Lactobacillus may influence the distribution and function of tight junction proteins by regulating intracellular signaling pathways, thus enhancing the connections between intestinal epithelial cells. Additionally, Lactobacillus can produce metabolites such as SCFAs, which can provide energy for intestinal epithelial cells, regulate intestinal pH, and inhibit inflammatory responses, among other functions.		 	Akkermansia muciniphila (A. muciniphila)	Decreased	A. muciniphila contributes to restoring and enhancing the integrity of the mucus layer by promoting the production of mucin, thereby exerting a protective effect on the intestine. A. muciniphila may repair and strengthen the intestinal epithelial barrier by regulating the expression of tight junction proteins, thus alleviating inflammatory responses. A. muciniphila maintains the integrity of the intestinal barrier by reducing the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines and the infiltration of inflammatory cells, as well as increasing the expression of anti-inflammatory cytokines and the differentiation of Tregs, thereby alleviating colonic damage and colitis.	, and 	 	Eubacterium rectale (E. rectale)	Decreased	A reduction in the abundance of bacteria such as E. rectale may impair the normal function of the intestinal mucus layer, weakening its ability to resist pathogens and thereby increasing the risk of intestinal inflammation. A decrease in the abundance of E. rectale may disrupt immune homeostasis, leading to excessive activation of Th1 immune responses and exacerbating intestinal inflammation. Changes in the quantity or function of E. rectale may result in insufficient production of butyrate, depriving the intestine of the protective effects of butyrate—such as the inhibitory effects on inflammation and protective effects on intestinal barrier function—thereby promoting the development of IBD.		 	Veillonellaceae	Increased	Veillonella may affect the expression and release of cytokines, leading to an imbalance between pro-inflammatory cytokines and anti-inflammatory cytokines. Veillonella may impair the function of intestinal mucus-secreting cells or directly degrade mucin components in the mucus layer, resulting in thinning of the mucus layer and damage to its integrity.		 	Collinsella aerofaciens (C. aerofaciens)	Decreased	C. aerofaciens may be involved in the pathogenesis and development of inflammatory bowel disease through multiple aspects, such as regulating the structure of intestinal flora, affecting intestinal barrier function, and interfering with host immune regulation and butyrate production.		 	Lactobacillus GG (LGG)	Decreased	LGG may influence the differentiation direction of Th cells by regulating the function of antigen-presenting cells such as dendritic cells, thereby correcting the Th1/Th2 imbalance and alleviating inflammatory responses. The ROS induced by LGG can oxidize the key regulatory enzyme Ubc12, inactivating it, thus inhibiting the phosphorylation of IκB, preventing NF-κB from entering the nucleus, reducing the transcription and expression of inflammatory factors, and further alleviating intestinal inflammation. Additionally, LGG can promote the secretion of mucin by intestinal epithelial cells, increasing the thickness and viscosity of the mucus layer and thereby enhancing the physical barrier function of the intestine.	 and 	 	Bacillus subtilis (B. subtilis)	Decreased	B. subtilis can upregulate the expression of tight junction proteins and enhance intestinal barrier function. It may regulate the function of intestinal goblet cells, promote mucus secretion, increase the thickness of the mucus layer, and thereby strengthen the protection of intestinal epithelium. Additionally, B. subtilis can inhibit the expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines and promote the production of anti-inflammatory cytokines, which helps balance the body’s immune response and alleviate intestinal inflammation.	 and 	 	Fusobacterium nucleatum (F. nucleatum)	Increased	F. nucleatum can promote the apoptosis of intestinal epithelial cells, destroy tight junction proteins, exacerbate intestinal inflammatory responses, and induce intestinal flora dysbiosis.		 	Enterococcus faecium (E. faecium)	Increased	ROS produced by E. faecium cause cellular oxidative stress damage, disrupt the intestinal mucosal barrier, and trigger inflammatory responses. Abnormal proliferation of E. faecium or certain substances produced by it may affect intestinal barrier function. As a part of the intestinal flora, the abnormal interaction between E. faecium and the host immune system may lead to immune imbalance, thereby inducing or exacerbating inflammatory bowel disease.		 	Firmicutes	Decreased	Phylum Firmicutes influences the disease mechanisms of inflammatory bowel disease through multiple pathways such as intestinal barrier function, immune regulation, bile acid metabolism, production of short-chain fatty acids, and oxidative stress.		 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">tab1.xml</infon><infon key="id">tab1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_foot</infon><offset>16229</offset><text>Dysbiosis patterns may vary between UC and CD (e.g., F. nucleatum is more strongly associated with CD), and interindividual heterogeneity is common.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>16378</offset><text>Probiotics alleviate or treat IBD by repairing the intestinal barrier, regulating the balance of the intestinal microbiota, reducing oxidative stress, and modulating intestinal immune responses. Antioxidant axis: secreted factors inhibit oxidant generation and promote endogenous antioxidant (superoxide dismutase, SOD) generation via Nrf2 activation, lowering mucosal ROS. Intestinal barrier repair: bacterial products increase the expression of the tight junction proteins zonula occludens-1 (ZO-1), occludin, and claudin-1, restoring epithelial integrity. Pathogen exclusion and microbiota reshaping: targeted bacteriocin production inhibits pathobionts, while SCFA-mediated pH reduction and niche competition increase overall microbial diversity and abundance; probiotics orchestrate immunomodulatory circuits that bias immune cells toward an anti-inflammatory phenotype, selectively upregulating anti-inflammatory cytokine expression while downregulating proinflammatory mediator expression to re-establish and maintain immune homeostasis. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17445</offset><text>However, traditional probiotics still face many challenges in the treatment of IBD, such as low survival rate, poor colonization efficiency and insufficient targeting. To overcome these problems, increasing the survival rate and improving the colonization ability of probiotics through engineering modification and enhancing their ability to accurately recognize inflammatory signals and achieve targeted localization are highly important. This approach is expected to not only significantly strengthen the therapeutic effect, achieve precise treatment, and prevent disease recurrence but also promote the development of personalized medicine, offering comprehensive health benefits to several patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>18149</offset><text>Therapeutic effects of probiotics on IBD and the related molecular mechanisms</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>18227</offset><text>Strategies for restoring the gut microbiota equilibrium</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>18283</offset><text>Restoration of gut microbiota diversity</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18323</offset><text>In IBD patients, the diversity of the gut microbiota is generally reduced. Probiotics can reduce the abundance of harmful bacteria by competing for nutrients and spatial niches, thereby promoting the proliferation of beneficial bacteria and restoring microbiota diversity. For instance, species from the genus Bifidobacterium can utilize oligosaccharides and other gut substances to grow and reproduce, simultaneously producing organic acids that reduce the intestinal pH. This acidic environment suppresses the growth of pathogenic bacteria such as E. coli and promotes the growth of beneficial bacteria, including bifidobacteria and lactobacilli, ultimately reestablishing gut microbial diversity. Therefore, key probiotic strains that can enhance the diversity restoration effects of endogenous commensal microbiota should be screened, and prebiotic–probiotic combinations targeting IBD-specific microbial deficiencies should be developed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>19268</offset><text>Strategies for altering the microbiota structure</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19317</offset><text>The structure of the gut microbiota is altered in IBD patients, characterized by an imbalance in the ratio of Firmicutes to Bacteroidetes. Probiotics can reverse this imbalance. Probiotics can aid in the restoration of the microbiota structure through strain-specific targeting of microbial taxa, with recent research (2024–2025) revealing the mechanisms through which probiotics affect niche competition and metabolic crosstalk.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19749</offset><text>Recent studies on Lactobacillus-mediated Firmicutes enrichment highlight the following strategies: Bifidobacterium longum subsp. infantis BLI-02 increases its own fucosidase activity to utilize host-derived fucosylated mucins, outcompeting mucin-degrading Bacteroidetes (e.g., Bacteroides fragilis) and restoring the F/B ratio; and Enterococcus faecalis SF68 adheres to intestinal epithelial cells via adhesin efaA, blocking adhesion sites for pathogenic Proteobacteria while it secretes succinate to promote Firmicutes colonization. Notably, Lactobacillus plantarum WCFS1 modulates quorum sensing in pathobionts—its secreted autoinducer-2 (AI-2) analogs inhibit E. coli biofilm formation, reducing the abundance of Proteobacteria without disrupting that of commensal bacteria. These structural adjustments normalize microbial–epithelial crosstalk, alleviating IBD-associated dysbiosis. Therefore, future studies should perform the mapping of strain-specific effects on microbial metabolic networks to predict normalization of fecal/bacterial ratios and develop precision probiotics on the basis of baseline microbiome profiles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20882</offset><text>Strategies for fortifying the intestinal epithelial barrier</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>20942</offset><text>Promotion of mucus layer secretion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20977</offset><text>The intestinal mucus layer—primarily composed of MUC2 and glycosylated glycoproteins—forms a physical and chemical barrier that sequesters pathogens and limits antigen access to epithelial cells. In IBD, reduced MUC2 expression and aberrant glycosylation decrease the thickness of the mucus layer, exacerbating epithelial exposure to luminal insults. Probiotics enhance mucus barrier function through conserved and strain-specific signaling, with recent studies (2024–2025) clarifying the crosstalk mechanism.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21493</offset><text>In addition to Lactobacillus reuteri-mediated activation of epithelial pathways, diverse strains target goblet cell function: Bifidobacterium breve YIT 12272 engages TLR2 on goblet cells to activate the p38 MAPK pathway, increasing MUC2 transcription; Lactobacillus gasseri ATCC 33323 stimulates mucin glycosylation by upregulating galactosyltransferase (β4GalT1), enhancing mucus resistance to bacterial proteases. Probiotic-derived metabolites also play key roles: SCFAs from Clostridium butyricum inhibit histone deacetylase 1 (HDAC1) in goblet cells, relieving the transcriptional repression of MUC5AC (a minor but functionally critical mucin). Notably, the increase in mucus layer thickness by probiotics reciprocally supports microbiota balance—thicker mucus provides a niche for commensals, reinforcing a “barrier-microbiota” feed-forward loop. For instance, Lactobacillus reuteri can activate intracellular signaling pathways within epithelial cells, promoting the synthesis and secretion of mucin MUC2. This strengthening of the mucus layer effectively protects the intestinal mucosa and mitigates tissue damage in IBD patients (Figure 3). Therefore, future research directions include deciphering strain-specific regulatory mechanisms of mucin glycosylation to counteract the glycosylation defects associated with inflammatory bowel disease; exploring the interactions among probiotics, intestinal glial cells, and goblet cells; and developing mucin-mimetic prebiotics to synergize with probiotics to restore the mucus layer.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g003.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>23036</offset><text>Mechanism underlying the barrier-protective effect of probiotics in IBD. Probiotics enhance the integrity of the mucous barrier by upregulating protective mucin expression. Simultaneously, they reinforce the cellular barrier through effects on intestinal epithelial tight junctions and the expression levels of intracellular protective proteins. Additionally, probiotics maintain the intestinal immune barrier by modulating immune cell populations and the expression of inflammatory mediators. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>23552</offset><text>Strategies for strengthening epithelial tight junctions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23608</offset><text>Tight junctions (TJs)—composed of transmembrane proteins and cytoplasmic scaffolding proteins—regulate paracellular permeability. In IBD, reduced TJ protein expression/assembly increases permeability, enabling luminal antigens to trigger mucosal inflammation. Probiotics reinforce TJs through convergent signaling pathways, with recent studies (2024–2025) highlighting strain diversity and posttranslational regulation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24034</offset><text>In terms of Lactobacillus acidophilus-mediated PI3K/Akt activation, other strains act via complementary mechanisms: Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG (LGG) secretes the pili protein SpaC, which binds epithelial E-cadherin to activate AMPK, promoting the phosphorylation of occludin at Ser408 and its membrane localization, and Bifidobacterium lactis BB-12 downregulates the expression of miR-200c, a microRNA that targets claudin-1 mRNA, thereby increasing claudin-1 protein levels. Probiotic EVs also contribute—Streptococcus thermophilus EVs carry miR-148a, which inhibits the ubiquitin ligase β-TrCP, preventing ZO-2 degradation. These coordinated effects reduce permeability, limiting antigen influx and inflammation (Figure 3). Therefore, future research directions may include mapping cross-regulatory networks between tight junction regulatory pathways to identify master regulators that can be targeted by multistrain probiotics; genetically engineering probiotics to overexpress factors that stabilize tight junctions; and investigating how microbiota metabolites synergize with probiotics to maintain tight junction protein function.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>25174</offset><text>Immune reprogramming strategies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25206</offset><text>IBD is driven by immune dysregulation, hyperactivation of proinflammatory pathways and insufficient anti-inflammatory signals. Probiotics alleviate these pathological changes through strain-specific interactions with innate and adaptive immune cells, with recent studies (2024–2025) revealing their broad mechanisms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25525</offset><text>Beyond Bifidobacteria-mediated dendritic cell (DC) activation, diverse probiotics target multiple immune checkpoints: Lactobacillus plantarum WCFS1 activates NOD2 in macrophages to suppress NF-κB p65 translocation, reducing TNF-α/IL-6 secretion, and Bifidobacterium adolescentis induces DCs to secrete IL-27, which promotes Treg differentiation by upregulating Foxp3 and inhibiting RORγt (Th17 master regulator) expression. Additionally, probiotic-derived indole-3-pyruvate modulates mucosal-associated invariant T (MAIT) cells, shifting their cytokine profile from that of IFN-γ to that of IL-10.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>26139</offset><text>Limitations of traditional probiotics in IBD treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26194</offset><text>Low probiotic survival in the gastrointestinal microenvironment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>26258</offset><text>Acidic pH in the stomach</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26283</offset><text>The gastric environment is highly acidic, typically ranging from pH 1.5 to 3.5 (Figure 4). This extreme acidity significantly threatens the survival of probiotics. As environmentally sensitive microorganisms, probiotics are vulnerable to damage under acidic conditions, particularly with respect to their cell membrane integrity. When the cell membrane, as a critical barrier, is compromised, intracellular contents may leak, thereby disrupting normal metabolic activities. Additionally, essential enzyme systems responsible for energy metabolism can become denatured and dysfunctional in an acidic milieu, preventing cells from producing sufficient energy to sustain life. Furthermore, the acidic environment may induce structural alterations in probiotic DNA, adversely affecting gene expression and interfering with its growth, reproduction, and specific biological functions. Consequently, prolonged exposure to such highly acidic conditions leads to a sharp decline in the number of viable probiotic cells, resulting in substantial cell death before the cells reach the intestine and thus limiting their therapeutic efficacy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g004.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>27414</offset><text>Characterization of the digestive environments in four key segments of the human digestive system, namely, the oral cavity, stomach, small intestine, and colon, including their respective pH ranges, major digestive enzymes, and food transit times. The oral cavity has a pH range of approximately 5.5–7.9 and contains amylase, with a relatively short food transit time. The stomach is highly acidic, with a pH range of approximately 1.5–3.5, and is equipped with major digestive enzymes such as pepsin and trypsin. In the stomach, food is triturated and mixed with gastric acid and pepsin, undergoing preliminary digestion into “chyme.” The small intestine is weakly acidic to weakly alkaline (pH 6.0–8.0) and harbors a variety of digestive enzymes. As the primary site for digestion and absorption, the vast majority of nutrients are completely decomposed and absorbed here, with a digestion duration of 3–4 h. The colon is weakly acidic to neutral (pH 6.5–7.5), and the major enzymes involved in this process include glycosidase and azoreductase, which are secreted by the intestinal flora to decompose undigested substances. Food residues reside here for an extended period, completing the final metabolic processes and feces formation. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>28691</offset><text>Threat of bile salts in the small intestine</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28735</offset><text>Once probiotics manage to traverse the stomach, they encounter another significant challenge posed by bile salts within the small intestine. Bile salts, which are secreted by the liver and stored in the gallbladder, are essential for fat digestion and absorption in the small intestine. However, bile salts are a double-edged sword for probiotics. Their amphipathic structure, possessing both hydrophilic and hydrophobic ends, enables them to interact with the probiotic cell membrane, disrupting the lipid bilayer and increasing membrane permeability. In vitro studies revealed that 0.5% (w/v) bile salt increased the membrane permeability of L. rhamnosus GG by 72 ± 4.6%, as measured by propidium iodide (PI) staining, whereas L. casei 393 exhibited only a 28 ± 3.1% increase in membrane permeability because of increased bile salt hydrolase (BSH) activity. BSH-positive strains can deconjugate bile salts into less toxic forms, with L. casei 393 achieving a 52 ± 3.8% deconjugation rate within 4 h, compared with 17 ± 2.5% in BSH-deficient L. plantarum Δbsh. Enhanced membrane permeability disturbs the balance between intracellular and extracellular substances, leading to the loss of essential ions and small molecules while permitting harmful external substances to penetrate the cells, further compromising cellular functions. Additionally, bile salts can interfere with probiotic metabolic pathways, suppressing their growth and proliferation. In bile-containing environments, the probiotic growth rate significantly decreases, and cell division and proliferation are inhibited, thereby markedly decreasing the number of viable probiotic cells.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>30411</offset><text>Other adverse factors</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30433</offset><text>Apart from gastric acidity and the presence of bile salts in the small intestine, additional factors within the gastrointestinal tract adversely affect probiotic survival. For instance, digestive enzymes such as pepsin in the stomach and trypsin in the pancreas can damage the digestion of food by probiotics. These enzymes specifically recognize and hydrolyze proteins, and since probiotic cell walls and membranes contain substantial amounts of protein components, they are susceptible to enzymatic degradation, leading to cell death. The survival rate of B. bifidum Bb-02 was 78 ± 4.3% after 1 h of exposure to 0.8 mg/mL pepsin, whereas that of L. rhamnosus GR-1 was 58 ± 3.5% because of the presence of a thicker peptidoglycan layer. Furthermore, the complex microbial community within the gut is another critical factor. The intestine naturally harbors numerous symbiotic bacteria that have evolved to form relatively stable ecosystems. Upon entry into the intestine, exogenous probiotics must compete with these resident bacteria for nutrients and adhesion sites. Symbiotic bacteria may produce antimicrobial substances that hinder the growth and reproduction of probiotics, making it difficult for them to survive and colonize such a competitive environment and resulting in markedly reduced probiotic viability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>31767</offset><text>Suboptimal probiotic colonization efficacy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>31810</offset><text>Competition with the native gut microbiota for nutrients and adhesion sites</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31886</offset><text>From a nutritional perspective, the resources available in the gut—including carbon and nitrogen sources, vitamins, and minerals essential for growth—are highly contested. Over evolutionary timescales, the native gut microbiota has adapted specifically to the nutritional environment of the intestine, developing specialized mechanisms for nutrient uptake and metabolism. For example, certain native gut bacteria efficiently utilize specific polysaccharides as carbon sources by secreting enzymes that degrade these polysaccharides into absorbable monosaccharides, thereby gaining a competitive advantage in nutrient acquisition. In contrast, they struggle to compete effectively for nutrients against colonization and proliferation within the intestine.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32645</offset><text>In terms of competition for adhesion sites, the intestinal mucosal surface provides limited adhesion spaces that are critical for microbial colonization in the gut. Many members of the natural gut microbiota occupy these sites by strongly binding to specific receptors on the surface of intestinal epithelial cells via specialized surface adhesion factors such as pili, capsules, and similar structures. Such robust binding enables stable colonization despite intestinal peristalsis and the flushing effect of digestive fluids while also facilitating nutrient acquisition and resistance to external interference. When conventional probiotics attempt to colonize the intestinal mucosa, they must compete with the native microbiota that has already occupied these adhesion sites. Conventional probiotics often lack sufficient adhesion factors that are highly compatible with these sites or possess weaker adhesive capacities, making stable attachment to the intestinal mucosal surface challenging. Even probiotics that can achieve temporary adhesion may frequently be displaced by competition with the native microbiota, preventing them from establishing stable populations within the gut. This dual competition for both nutrients and adhesion sites significantly hinders the establishment of a stable microbial community by conventional probiotics in the intestine, markedly reducing their colonization efficiency. Eubacterium rectale binds to MUC2 via its surface lectin EreA, achieving an adhesion rate of 4.2 × 105 CFU/cm2, whereas conventional probiotics such as L. bulgaricus 11,842 exhibit an adhesion rate of only 8.3 × 103 CFU/cm2.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>34298</offset><text>Lack of specific colonization factors for some probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34356</offset><text>Specific colonization factors are crucial for the long-term survival and functionality of probiotics within the gut. Certain probiotics possess specific surface proteins that recognize and bind specific receptors on the surface of intestinal epithelial cells, enabling strong adhesion between probiotics and epithelial cells. This adhesion not only helps probiotics resist flushing by digestive fluids and intestinal peristalsis but also promotes effective interactions with host cells, thereby modulating the host immune response and intestinal barrier function. For example, the SpaC protein of L. rhamnosus GG mediates binding to MUC2, increasing resistance to intestinal peristalsis and digestive fluid flushing—its retention time in the colon is 3.2 ± 0.3 days, whereas it is 1.1 ± 0.1 days for SpaC-deficient mutants. Additionally, some colonization factors enable probiotics to form protective biofilms within the gut. Biofilms offer probiotics a relatively stable microenvironment, shielding them from harmful external factors and facilitating intercellular communication and synergistic effects among probiotics. Bifidobacterium longum expresses the surface protein BlcA, which induces biofilm formation with a coverage rate of 65 ± 4.2% on intestinal epithelial cells, protecting the bacteria against bile salts and ROS.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35708</offset><text>However, certain conventional probiotics lack these specific colonization factors, resulting in numerous challenges in the gut. These probiotics tend to reside only transiently within the intestinal tract and are quickly expelled because of intestinal peristalsis and digestion. This phenomenon is due to the absence of an effective adhesion mechanism that enables them to attach firmly to the intestinal mucosal surface, making them vulnerable to removal by digestive fluids. Furthermore, their inability to form stable biofilms renders them especially susceptible to harmful gastrointestinal conditions, such as stomach acid, bile salts, and reactive oxygen species. This transient colonization severely limits their ability to continuously modulate the gut microbiota and improve intestinal barrier function, significantly reducing their therapeutic efficacy in the treatment of IBD.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>36595</offset><text>Insufficient targeting of probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36632</offset><text>The inflamed intestinal regions in IBD patients exhibit unique pathological microenvironments, such as elevated levels of reactive oxygen species due to inflammation and alterations in the microbial community structure. However, conventional probiotics lack the mechanisms required to recognize and respond to these specific microenvironmental signals. Upon entering the gastrointestinal tract, they are distributed randomly such that they are unable to actively locate and concentrate in inflamed regions. This nonspecific distribution leads to a significant number of probiotics failing to reach the inflamed regions where their effects are most needed. Instead, they often remain in healthy areas of the intestine, yet they exert minimal therapeutic effects on immune dysregulation and impaired barrier function at the inflamed regions. Owing to this insufficient localization, conventional probiotics struggle to effectively regulate the intestinal immune response, repair the damaged intestinal barrier, and mitigate gut microbiota dysbiosis. Nontargeted delivery may also result in unintended off-target effects. When probiotics are widely distributed across noninflamed regions, they can disrupt the normal physiological functions of the intestine. For example, excess probiotics could alter the microbial community balance in healthy intestinal areas, negatively affecting the interactions among symbiotic microorganisms. Such disturbances may trigger a series of adverse consequences, such as intestinal dysfunction, leading to symptoms such as abdominal pain and diarrhea in patients. Additionally, unnecessary interactions with normal intestinal tissues may provoke an excessive immune response against probiotics, increasing the risk of immune-related adverse reactions. In the long term, these off-target effects may not only fail to treat IBD effectively but could impose additional risks and adverse impacts on the patient’s intestinal health.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>38593</offset><text>Probiotic engineering strategies for IBD treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>38644</offset><text>Encapsulation technology</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38669</offset><text>Encapsulation technology serves as a core strategy to improve probiotic survival during oral administration. Probiotics face severe survival challenges from gastric acid and bile, which drastically reduce their viability before they reach the intestine. Encapsulation provides a protective barrier, enabling probiotics to safely transit the stomach and exert beneficial effects in the intestine (Figure 5).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g005.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>39076</offset><text>Encapsulation technology enhances the efficacy of probiotics in alleviating or treating IBD. (A) Probiotics encapsulated with polymeric materials such as tannic acid, sodium alginate, and chitosan can increase their tolerance to gastric acid and bile salts after oral administration, improve their intestinal colonization capacity, and increase their efficacy in alleviating or treating intestinal inflammation. (B) EcN, TA@EcN, LGG, Cdots@LGG, FeMn@EcN, and CaFeMn@EcN were exposed to simulated gastric fluid for 30 min, respectively. The survival rate of probiotics encapsulated with different nanomaterials was determined using the plate counting method. EcN: E. coli Nissel 1917; TA: tannic acid; Cdots@LGG: carbon dots are applied to modify Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG; FeMn@EcN: manganese chloride (MnCl2) was introduced before ferric chloride (FeCl3) into the EcN suspension, allowing a balanced electrostatic adsorption of both Mn2+ and Fe3+ ions onto the negatively charged bacterial surface. CaFeMn@EcN: FeMn@EcN was dispersed in a solution of polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP) and calcium chloride (CaCl2), allowing Ca2+ ions to be adsorbed onto the bacterial surface (termed Ca2+FeMn@EcN) as the deposited PVP could capture Ca2+ ions by the complexation with the pyrrolidone pendant groups [data from, and ]. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40413</offset><text>Two primary approaches are microencapsulation and nanoparticle encapsulation, which use polymer materials to enclose probiotics in tiny capsules or particles. These materials include natural polymers and synthetic polymers. The sodium alginate–chitosan double-layer encapsulation method has been demonstrated to significantly increase the survival rate of probiotics, and Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG encapsulation via this technique markedly increases its survival rate in simulated gastrointestinal fluids. This method leverages the gelation properties of sodium alginate and the biocompatibility of chitosan to form a protective film that minimizes probiotic exposure to gastric acid and bile.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41110</offset><text>Another promising approach is the deployable physical containment strategy (DEPCOS), an alginate-based hydrogel encapsulation technology. It enhances probiotic survival in acidic environments (pH 4) and prolongs intestinal residence time, thereby improving therapeutic efficacy. Its unique hydrogel structure remains stable in gastric acid and gradually releases probiotics in the intestine.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41502</offset><text>Compared with genetic engineering, encapsulation offers a nongenetically modified (non-GMO) route, avoiding safety concerns and regulatory barriers associated with transgenic microorganisms, which is critical for clinical translation in regions with strict GMO oversight. It reliably protects probiotics from gastrointestinal stressors with well-documented in vitro/in vivo improvements in probiotic survival, outperforming unmodified probiotics and early delivery systems in terms of transit stability. Its broad compatibility with natural and synthetic polymers allows for the customization of strain-specific needs and clinical goals. Additionally, encapsulation integrates seamlessly with delivery systems to synergistically increase survival and targeting, offering flexibility that is lacking in standalone genetic engineering.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42336</offset><text>Unlike genetic engineering, encapsulation cannot tailor the intrinsic functions of probiotics—its role is passive protection rather than functional enhancement. Balancing high encapsulation efficiency with precise controlled release remains a bottleneck; overly dense coatings may preserve viability but hinder intestinal release, while porous structures compromise stress resistance. Compared with advanced responsive delivery systems, traditional encapsulation has lower targeting precision, often resulting in nonspecific release across the intestine rather than focusing on inflamed lesions. Potential material-induced immune responses and scalability limitations for large-scale production further constrain its utility, especially compared with the scalable fermentation of engineered probiotics.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>43141</offset><text>Novel delivery systems</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>43164</offset><text>Surface modification and targeting enhancement</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43211</offset><text>Probiotic colonization efficiency depends on the ability of the bacteria to adhere to the intestinal mucosa. Surface modification techniques improve targeting and adhesion (Figure 6). Polydopamine combined with chitosan significantly increases probiotic colonization by promoting intestinal mucosa adhesion. Probiotics modified with these materials show increased intestinal abundance and prolonged residence time, strengthening therapeutic effects.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g006.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig6</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>43661</offset><text>Surface modification technology significantly enhances the colonization capacity of probiotics. Probiotics are surface-modified with materials such as polydopamine, sodium alginate, and chitosan to increase their targeting specificity and adhesion capacity, thereby strengthening the ability of probiotics to alleviate or treat IBD. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44016</offset><text>Genetic modification also enhances targeting. Engineering probiotics to express specific adhesion molecules facilitates colon-specific colonization. Genetically modified strains expressing mucosa-binding adhesion proteins exhibit increased colon colonization, reducing loss in nontarget regions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>44312</offset><text>Responsive delivery systems</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44340</offset><text>pH-responsive and enzyme-responsive delivery systems enable targeted probiotic release at specific gastrointestinal sites, improving colonization efficiency (Figure 7). pH-responsive microcapsules remain stable in acidic stomach/small intestine environments and degrade at neutral colonic pH, releasing probiotics precisely in the colon. Enzyme-responsive systems use polymer materials sensitive to gut enzymes to release probiotics in designated regions, leveraging localized enzymatic activity for precise delivery.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">fmicb-16-1696524-g007.jpg</infon><infon key="id">fig7</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>44858</offset><text>pH-responsive (A) and enzyme-responsive (B) delivery systems are important strategies for improving the colonization efficiency of probiotics. (C) The number of EcN released from microencapsulated EcN during 120 min incubation in Na-citrate buffer. The release kinetics models. (D) Zero-order kinetics model; (E) first-order kinetics model. (F) Viable L. plantarum counts when free L. plantarum and wood scroll encapsulated L. plantarum samples subjected to SGF for 2 h, revealing the protective capabilities of the wood scroll structure. (G) Cumulative amounts released when exposed to SIF for 9 h [data from and ]. Created by Biorender.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45503</offset><text>Novel delivery systems outperform encapsulation in targeting precision, enabling site-specific release in the colon or inflamed lesions—addressing encapsulation’s limitation of broad, nonspecific protection. Compared with the effects of standalone encapsulation or unmodified probiotics, the synergistic effects of surface modification and responsive release yield higher colonization efficiency. Compared with genetic engineering, delivery systems avoid GMO-related safety and regulatory burdens, accelerating clinical translation. Their modular design supports integration with diverse probiotics and therapeutic agents, offering greater flexibility than strain-specific genome modification does. Furthermore, responsive systems adapt to dynamic gastrointestinal microenvironments (pH fluctuations, enzyme gradients)—a capability that genetic engineering can only replicate with complex, resource-intensive gene circuit design.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46439</offset><text>Unlike genetic engineering, delivery systems do not enhance the intrinsic functions of probiotics—they optimize delivery but not performance. Limited responsiveness to mild microenvironmental changes means that they often require robust signals to trigger release, potentially missing the signals necessary for release in subclinical lesions. Compared with encapsulation, delivery systems face more severe material–probiotic compatibility issues; some responsive polymers may exhibit cytotoxicity or disrupt probiotic metabolism. The complexity of manufacturing multilayered microcapsules or enzyme-sensitive nanoparticles also increases production costs and scalability challenges, which are less prominent in encapsulation or genetic engineering.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>47192</offset><text>Engineered probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>47214</offset><text>Gene editing and synthetic biology modifications</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47263</offset><text>Advancements in gene editing (e.g., CRISPR) and synthetic biology have enabled precise probiotic genome optimization to enhance stress resistance. The GroESL molecular chaperone system promotes protein folding and increases cell survival under stress. Engineered Lactobacillus paracasei overexpressing GroESL shows enhanced stress resistance and broader environmental adaptability. Other strategies (gene knockout/overexpression) modulate metabolic pathways to improve intestinal adaptability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47757</offset><text>Recent advances in CRISPR-based strain engineering have transcended traditional Cas9-mediated double-strand breaks (DSBs), with precision tools such as base editors (BEs) and prime editors (PEs) revolutionizing probiotic modification. Cytosine and adenine base editors enable single-nucleotide substitutions without inducing DSBs, drastically reducing off-target effects and genomic rearrangements—key limitations of early CRISPR systems. For example, compared to traditional CRISPR editing, BE-mediated modification of the glutamate decarboxylase (GAD) gene significantly increased γ-aminobutyric acid (GABA) production by Lactobacillus plantarum. Prime editors further increase this precision by enabling targeted insertions, deletions, and substitutions of up to 40 bp, facilitating seamless integration of therapeutic cassettes without homologous recombination templates. These tools expand the scope of CRISPR from stress resistance to the de novo synthesis of IBD-tailored bioactive molecules.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>48762</offset><text>Synthetic biology involves advanced probiotic engineering through modular, orthogonal genetic circuits that enable programmable, tunable functions. Modular design allows the assembly of sensing, signal transduction, and output modules from diverse microbial sources, minimizing crosstalk with endogenous probiotic pathways. For instance, a quorum-sensing (QS)-regulated circuit in Bifidobacterium breve induces IL-10 expression only when colonization density thresholds are met, ensuring therapeutic release in inflamed colons. Synthetic oscillators and toggle switches further enable temporal control of therapeutic genes, aligning probiotic function with IBD progression —addressing the static nature of traditional probiotic therapies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49503</offset><text>Smart biosensor probiotics, a product of combined synthetic biology and CRISPR engineering techniques, can detect complex, multisignal IBD-related cues. Beyond single-signal sensing, modern designs integrate sensors for inflammatory mediators (TNF-α and IL-6), reactive oxygen/nitrogen species (ROS/RNS), and gut barrier markers (zonulin). An engineered E. coli Nissle 1917 strain with a dual-sensor circuit releases anti-TNF nanobodies only in the presence of two inflammatory signals, minimizing off-target effects. Enhanced sensor sensitivity now enables the detection of subclinical inflammation, addressing an unmet need for early IBD intervention.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>50161</offset><text>Probiotic integration—a rational combination of engineered strains with complementary functions—addresses the multifactorial pathogenesis of IBD. This strategy deploys strains tailored for distinct tasks: one sensing inflammation and releasing anti-inflammatory agents, another promoting intestinal epithelial cell (IEC) proliferation, and a third inhibiting pathogens. Compared with single-strain therapy, a combinatorial cocktail of CRISPR-edited Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG (anti-inflammatory), Bifidobacterium adolescentis (mucosal repair), and engineered E. coli Nissle 1917 (pathogen inhibition) reduced colon shortening and decreased proinflammatory cytokine levels more effectively in DSS-induced colitis model mice. Success relies on interstrain compatibility and coordinated function, which are addressed via synthetic biology tools such as QS-based intercellular communication modules.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>51061</offset><text>Smart targeting via genetic circuits</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51098</offset><text>Genetic engineering transforms probiotics into “smart” microorganisms with precise targeting. Programmed genetic circuits allow probiotics to sense environmental signals and respond accordingly. For example, engineered E. coli Nissle 1917 survives even when the L-lactate concentration exceeds 5 mM and releases payloads on demand. In IBD treatment, these strains detect inflammatory signals and release anti-inflammatory agents or antioxidants at lesion sites, alleviating inflammation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51592</offset><text>Genetic engineering offers unparalleled molecular precision and functional customization compared with encapsulation and delivery systems, enabling probiotics to perform IBD-specific tasks that are impossible with passive protection or targeted delivery alone. Smart biosensor probiotics dynamically respond to gut microenvironmental cues, providing specificity that delivery systems cannot match. Probiotic integration enables synergistic multistrain therapy for complex IBD phenotypes, outperforming single-strain encapsulation and delivery systems. Additionally, genetic modifications enhance the intrinsic survival of probiotics, reducing their reliance on external protection or delivery vehicles.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52295</offset><text>Unlike encapsulation and delivery systems, genetic engineering has significant GMO safety risks, including horizontal gene transfer to gut commensals or unintended mutations—risks negligible in non-GMO strategies. Regulatory hurdles are far more stringent, with extensive preclinical/clinical data required to demonstrate safety, delaying translation compared with non-GMO approaches. The long-term stability of engineered functions in complex gut environments is another critical issue; engineered probiotics must maintain modified traits amid microbiota competition, nutrient limitations, and host immune responses—challenges that encapsulation and delivery systems mitigate via physical protection or controlled release. Furthermore, gene circuit design and genome modification require specialized expertise and resources, making genetic engineering less accessible than encapsulation or basic delivery systems for many research teams.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>53238</offset><text>Biosafety considerations for engineered probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53289</offset><text>The clinical translation of engineered probiotics is tightly constrained by biosafety concerns, as genetic modifications or foreign payloads may introduce unintended risks to the host, the gut microecosystem, or even the broader environment. These risks are amplified in IBD patients, who often have compromised intestinal barriers and dysregulated immune systems—making them more susceptible to microbial perturbations. Below is a detailed analysis of core biosafety risks, evidence-based mitigation strategies, and unresolved challenges that are supported by recent preclinical and early clinical data.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>53896</offset><text>Horizontal gene transfer (HGT): mechanisms, risks, and mitigation</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53962</offset><text>HGT—the transfer of genetic material between nonparent-offspring microorganisms—is among the most critical biosafety risks associated with engineered probiotics. In the human gut, HGT occurs at frequencies 10–100 times greater than those in other environments because of three key factors: (1) high bacterial density (101–1012 cells/g feces) facilitating cell-to-cell contact; (2) the presence of mobile genetic elements (MGEs, e.g., plasmids, transposons, and bacteriophages) that act as “vectors” for gene transfer; and (3) intestinal metabolites that transiently increase bacterial membrane permeability, promoting DNA uptake. With respect to engineered probiotics, HGT of foreign genes to pathogenic gut bacteria could lead to the development of “superbugs” with enhanced virulence or drug resistance, posing severe public health threats.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54821</offset><text>To address this risk, three evidence-based mitigation strategies have been validated in preclinical models, with varying degrees of translational potential.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>54978</offset><text>Chromosomal integration of engineered genes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55022</offset><text>Unlike plasmids (extrachromosomal DNA) that replicate independently and are easily transferred via conjugation, chromosomal integration embeds foreign genes into the probiotic’s genome, greatly reducing HGT risk. This is typically achieved via CRISPR-Cas9-mediated homologous directed repair (HDR), which targets specific genomic loci to insert engineered cassettes. A landmark study by compared HGT frequencies between plasmid-based and chromosomally integrated Lactobacillus acidophilus strains both expressing a green fluorescent protein (GFP) reporter. In vitro cocultures with a clinical isolate of E. coli (strain ATCC 25922) revealed that the HGT frequency of L. acidophilus was 1.2 × 10−5 events per cell, whereas the HGT frequency of chromosomally integrated L. acidophilus was &lt;1 × 10−7 events per cell.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55852</offset><text>In a mouse model of DSS-induced colitis, fecal sampling over 4 weeks confirmed that no horizontal transfer of the chromosomal GFP cassette to native gut bacteria occurred. However, this strategy has several limitations; chromosomal integration can reduce the expression level of engineered genes and requires strain-specific HDR optimization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>56197</offset><text>Suicide plasmids for transient gene expression</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56244</offset><text>Suicide plasmids are engineered to replicate only under specific “permissive” conditions and degrade rapidly when these conditions are removed—ensuring that they are not retained or transferred long term. A recent example by involved a temperature-sensitive suicide plasmid (pTS-SOD) designed for Lactococcus lactis: this plasmid contains a replication origin (oriT) functional only at 30–37° C, whereas at temperatures &gt;37.5° C, oriT is inactivated, and the plasmid is degraded via a built-in restriction enzyme (EcoRI) that cleaves the plasmid backbone.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56810</offset><text>In vitro, L. lactis carrying pTS-SOD retained the plasmid for 72 h at 30° CC but lost &gt;99% of the plasmids within 24 h at 37° C. In a rat model of TNBS-induced colitis, fecal samples collected 7 days post-administration showed no detectable pTS-SOD (via PCR), confirming the “suicide” phenotype of the plasmid. This strategy is particularly useful for short-term therapeutic payloads but is unsuitable for long-term colonization due to plasmid loss.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>57272</offset><text>Auxotrophic markers instead of antibiotic resistance genes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>57331</offset><text>In traditional plasmid-based engineering, antibiotic resistance genes are often used to select for transformed probiotics. However, these genes are high risk for HGT, as they can confer drug resistance to pathogens. Auxotrophic markers—genetic modifications that render the probiotic dependent on an exogenous nutrient for survival—eliminate this risk. The most widely used auxotrophic marker is thyA gene knockout (encoding thymidylate synthase), which prevents the probiotic from synthesizing thymidine (a critical nucleotide for DNA replication).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>57885</offset><text> engineered E. coli Nissle 1917 (a clinically validated probiotic) with thyA knockout and a chromosomally integrated IL-10 cassette. In vitro, the engineered strain (ECN-ΔthyA-IL10) only grew in media supplemented with 50 μg/mL thymidine; without thymidine, &gt;99% of the cells died within 48 h. In a mouse model of colitis, ECN-ΔthyA-IL10 colonized the gut for 14 days when the mice received thymidine-supplemented drinking water (0.1 mg/mL) but was completely cleared within 7 days of thymidine withdrawal. Importantly, no HGT of the thyA knockout or IL-10 cassette was detected in native gut bacteria. Other auxotrophic markers have shown similar safety profiles but require strain-specific nutrient optimization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>58613</offset><text>Containment strategies: ensuring spatial and temporal control</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>58675</offset><text>Containment strategies go beyond HGT mitigation to ensure that engineered probiotics do not persist in the gut or environment outside of therapeutic needs. These strategies are classified into two categories: passive containment (dependence on exogenous factors) and active containment (response to endogenous gut signals). Both aim to limit the probiotic’s lifespan to the duration of IBD activity, reducing long-term ecological impact.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>59115</offset><text>Passive containment: nutrient or temperature dependence</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>59171</offset><text>Nutrient-dependent containment is the most mature passive strategy, but temperature-dependent systems have gained traction for their ability to respond to host physiology (e.g., fever during IBD flares). developed a temperature-activated kill switch for Lactococcus lactis that combines two components. The first is a heat-inducible promoter (Phsp) derived from Bacillus subtilis, which is activated at temperatures &gt;39° C (a common fever threshold in IBD flares), and the second is a cytotoxic gene (cidA) encoding a pore-forming protein that disrupts the bacterial cell membrane when expressed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>59769</offset><text>In vitro, L. lactis carrying the kill switch (LL-TKS) remained viable at 37° C (normal body temperature) but had a 99.9% mortality rate within 6 h at 39° C. In a mouse model of DSS-induced colitis (in which mice developed transient fever up to 39.5° C), LL-TKS was cleared from the gut within 48 h of fever onset, whereas a control strain (without the kill switch) persisted for 10 days. This strategy is advantageous for “on-demand” containment during flares but has several limitations: it does not activate in afebrile IBD patients and requires combination with nutrient-dependent systems for full coverage.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>60393</offset><text>Active containment: response to endogenous gut signals</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>60448</offset><text>Active containment systems use gut-specific signals to trigger probiotic elimination—aligning containment with disease activity. A ROS-responsive kill switch for E. coli Nissle—leveraging the high ROS levels in the inflamed IBD mucosa (10–50 μM H₂O₂, compared to &lt;5 μM in the healthy gut)—uses a peroxide-inducible promoter (PoxrA) that is activated by H₂O₂, and when activated, PoxrA drives the expression of sulA, a gene that inhibits bacterial cell division (leading to apoptosis).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>60955</offset><text>In vitro, E. coli Nissle with the ROS kill switch (ECN-ROS-KS) survived in low-ROS media (&lt;5 μM H₂O₂) but stopped dividing and died within 12 h in high-ROS media (25 μM H₂O₂). In a DSS mouse model, ECN-ROS-KS colonized the inflamed colon for 7 days (during peak ROS production) and was cleared within 5 days as inflammation resolved (ROS levels decreased to &lt;8 μM). This strategy is “self-regulating” but requires further validation in human IBD patients, where ROS levels vary between UC and CD (higher in UC colonic mucosa than in CD small bowel mucosa).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>61539</offset><text>Ecological impact: balancing therapeutic efficacy and microbiome homeostasis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>61616</offset><text>The gut microbiota is a complex ecosystem with overlapping metabolic and functional networks; introducing engineered probiotics could disrupt this balance via three mechanisms: (1) competition for nutrients or adhesion sites with native beneficial bacteria; (2) secretion of antimicrobial molecules (e.g., bacteriocins) that inhibit nontarget microbes; and (3) alteration of gut metabolite profiles. Assessing ecological impact requires long-term (≥12 weeks) studies using multiomics approaches (16S rRNA sequencing, metagenomics, and metabolomics) to capture both taxonomic and functional changes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>62219</offset><text>Taxonomic impact: effects on beneficial and pathogenic taxa</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>62279</offset><text>Most preclinical studies have focused on short-term (4–8 weeks) ecological effects, with mixed results. The effect of E. coli Nissle expressing IL-10 (ECN-IL10) in DSS-treated mice was evaluated, and the results revealed no significant changes in the abundance of the beneficial taxa Faecalibacterium prausnitzii (0.8 ± 0.2% vs. 0.7 ± 0.1% in controls) or Akkermansia muciniphila (1.2 ± 0.3% vs. 1.1 ± 0.2% in controls), while the abundance of the pathogenic taxon E. coli (including AIEC) decreased 30%, likely due to nutrient competition. With respect to alpha diversity, the Shannon index (a measure of microbial diversity) remained unchanged in the context of ECN-IL10 treatment, with values of 4.2 ± 0.3 (ECN-IL10 group) versus 4.1 ± 0.2 (control group).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>63073</offset><text>However, a longer-term study (16 weeks) by revealed that Lactococcus lactis expressing bacteriocins (LL-BAC) caused a 25% reduction in the abundance of Bifidobacterium in mice—likely because of the cross-reactivity of the bacteriocins with nontargeting gram-positive bacteria. This highlights the need for strain-specific antimicrobial payloads.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>63423</offset><text>Functional impact: metabolic and immune perturbations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>63477</offset><text>Functional changes can be more impactful than taxonomic changes, as they directly affect host physiology. Analysis of the fecal metabolomes of mice treated with Lactobacillus paracasei-overexpressing GroESL (LP-GroESL) revealed that butyrate levels increased by 15% (from 2.1 ± 0.3 mM to 2.4 ± 0.2 mM), likely because of enhanced LP-GroESL survival and fermentation of dietary fiber; secondary bile acids decreased by 20%, which may reduce gut epithelial damage (a known effect of secondary bile acids in IBD); and lipopolysaccharide (LPS) levels decreased by 30%, which is consistent with reduced colonic inflammation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>64111</offset><text>In contrast, another study revealed that E. coli Nissle expressing SOD (ECN-SOD) caused a 10% reduction in acetate levels—possibly due to competition with native acetate-producing bacteria. This underscores the need for “metabolic profiling” of engineered probiotics to ensure that unintended metabolite shifts do not exacerbate IBD symptoms.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>64460</offset><text>Unresolved challenges in ecological risk assessment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>64512</offset><text>Ecological impact assessment still has two key gaps: interindividual variability and the absence of long-term human data. For instance, the composition of the gut microbiota varies widely among IBD patients, and an engineered probiotic that is safe in one patient may disrupt the composition of the microbiota in another. Additionally, most studies are in mice, and human data are limited to short-term (4–8 weeks) phase I trials, which are insufficient to capture delayed effects. Future studies should use “microbiome rebound” assays—measuring how quickly the gut microbiota returns to baseline after the cessation of engineered probiotic treatment—to assess the reversibility of any perturbations.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>65225</offset><text>Application of engineered probiotics in IBD treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>65279</offset><text>Application of engineered probiotics in ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>65338</offset><text>Performance of specifically genetically modified probiotic strains in preclinical models</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>65427</offset><text>UC is a chronic inflammatory condition that primarily affects the colonic mucosa and is characterized by persistent inflammation and ulceration of the intestinal mucosa. In recent years, genetically engineered probiotics have shown significant potential for UC treatment. Through genetic modification, Lactococcus lactis strains have been engineered to express anti-inflammatory cytokines, such as IL-10, which markedly alleviated colonic inflammation in animal models. These engineered strains modulate the intestinal immune response by reducing the production of proinflammatory cytokines, thereby alleviating the symptoms of UC engineered. Studies have demonstrated that engineered probiotics constructed through synthetic biology techniques can sense inflammatory signals in the gut and release therapeutic enzymes, such as superoxide dismutase. In UC mouse models, this engineered probiotic significantly reduced oxidative stress levels and promoted intestinal mucosal healing. Further research has demonstrated that these engineered probiotics offer significant advantages in reducing inflammation and promoting tissue repair.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>66560</offset><text>Progress and challenges in clinical trials</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>66603</offset><text>Despite the promising results obtained in preclinical studies, the clinical application of engineered probiotics in the treatment of UC still faces several challenges. At present, some therapeutic strategies based on engineered probiotics have progressed to clinical trials. In particular, preliminary clinical safety evaluations have been completed for a Lactococcus lactis strain engineered to express IL-10, and the results demonstrated good tolerability. However, the therapeutic efficacy of this strain requires further validation in larger trials. Key challenges encountered in clinical trials include ensuring the long-term stability of engineered strains, improving their ability to colonize the human gut, and avoiding adverse immune responses. Moreover, maintaining therapeutic function within the complex intestinal environment while avoiding irreversible effects on the host microbiome remains a critical issue to be addressed.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>67543</offset><text>Applications of engineered probiotics in Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>67602</offset><text>Targeted strategies for inflamed sites in Crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>67662</offset><text>Crohn’s disease (CD) is a chronic inflammatory disorder affecting the entire intestinal wall. Targeted therapy at inflammatory sites has become a research hotspot in therapeutic development. Using genetic engineering techniques, probiotics can be modified to express specific adhesion molecules, enabling selective adherence to the inflamed intestinal regions of patients with CD. For instance, a genetically modified Bifidobacterium strain has been engineered to express adhesins that recognize inflammation-associated glycoproteins, demonstrating strong targeting capabilities in a CD mouse model. Another promising strategy involves engineering probiotics to produce enzymes capable of degrading proinflammatory mediators. For example, an engineered probiotic that has been constructed to secrete proteases can specifically degrade cytokines implicated in the inflammatory cascade, thereby alleviating intestinal inflammation. This targeted approach not only enhances therapeutic efficacy but also minimizes the side effects of drugs in noninflamed regions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>68725</offset><text>Applications of engineered probiotics in combination therapy schemes</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>68794</offset><text>In the treatment of CD, engineered probiotics are commonly used in combination with other therapeutic modalities to improve overall efficacy. Specifically, engineered probiotics can be combined with immunosuppressants or biologic agents. This combination therapy can more effectively regulate intestinal immune responses and promote the repair of the intestinal mucosa. Moreover, combining engineered probiotics with nutritional interventions such as the administration of short-chain fatty acids can improve the gut microenvironment, enhance probiotic colonization and improve therapeutic outcomes. This multipronged therapeutic strategy offers new insights for the personalized treatment of CD.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>69491</offset><text>Personalized intervention strategies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>69528</offset><text>Probiotic customization on the basis of individual gut microbiota characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>69610</offset><text>Application of gut microbiota detection techniques in personalized interventions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>69691</offset><text>The development of gut microbiota detection techniques, combined with machine learning-driven multiomics integration frameworks, provides powerful and essential tools for personalized interventions. High-throughput sequencing enables detailed analyses of the composition and functional activity of individual gut microbiota, while multiomics data (including gut microbiome, host genomics, transcriptomics, metabolomics, and proteomics) are integrated via machine learning algorithms to decode complex host–microbe interactions. These integrated frameworks not only identify dominant and low-abundance microbial populations with their metabolic products but also quantify the microbial–metabolic–host signaling networks that underpin IBD pathogenesis. Currently, 16S rRNA gene sequencing and metagenomic sequencing, coupled with machine learning-based multiomics integration, are widely utilized to generate high-resolution gut microbiota profiles. This approach further enables the identification of IBD-specific microbial signatures and their functional correlates, laying a robust scientific foundation for refining personalized intervention plans.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>70848</offset><text>Selection of appropriate engineered probiotics on the basis of individual microbiota characteristics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70949</offset><text>Precision medicine, which involves the development of personalized treatment plans based on individual genetic features, environmental factors, and lifestyles, is being increasingly anchored in machine learning-driven multiomics integration frameworks for IBD treatment. These frameworks integrate gut microbiota multiomics data with host genomic and phenotypic information to construct predictive models that predict patient responses to specific engineered probiotics. Machine learning algorithms can be used to analyze high-dimensional multiomics datasets and identify nonlinear correlations between microbial/host signatures and treatment outcomes. This enables the prioritization of probiotic formulations most likely to modulate host–microbe interactions favorably, thereby improving clinical responses. Additionally, precision medicine leverages real-time multiomics monitoring combined with machine learning to dynamically track therapeutic responses, allowing timely adjustments to probiotic formulations for optimal efficacy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>71987</offset><text>The potential of precision medicine in IBD treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>72040</offset><text>Concept of precision medicine and its alignment with IBD treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>72107</offset><text>Precision medicine is a medical model that involves the development of personalized treatment plans on the basis of individual genetic features and environmental and lifestyle factors. In IBD treatment, precision medicine is primarily reflected in the formulation of personalized probiotic intervention strategies based on the patient’s gut microbiota characteristics and disease phenotypes. By integrating gut microbiota data with genetic profiles, it is possible to predict patient responses to specific probiotics. These predictive models aid in selecting the engineered probiotics most likely to be effective, thereby improving clinical outcomes. Additionally, precision medicine involves monitoring the patient’s therapeutic responses, enabling timely adjustments to ensure optimal efficacy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>72908</offset><text>Development and implementation of personalized probiotic intervention strategies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>72989</offset><text>The development of personalized probiotic intervention strategies requires comprehensive consideration of the patient’s gut microbiota characteristics, disease phenotype, and therapeutic responses. On the basis of patient gut microbiota data, engineered probiotics simultaneously expressing anti-inflammatory cytokines and antimicrobial peptides can be developed. These probiotics exhibit dual functions: reducing inflammation and inhibiting the growth of harmful bacteria, thereby improving the patient’s gut microenvironment. During the implementation of personalized probiotic intervention strategies, close monitoring of therapeutic response is crucial. Regular fecal microbiota analysis can evaluate changes in the gut microbiota composition, probiotic colonization and effectiveness. Moreover, monitoring clinical symptoms and biomarkers is necessary for timely treatment adjustments. This personalized intervention strategy offers new insights and methods for the treatment of IBD.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>73982</offset><text>Challenges and opportunities for personalized probiotic interventions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>74052</offset><text>Technological innovations driving the development of personalized interventions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>74132</offset><text>Technological innovation is a key factor driving the development of personalized probiotic interventions. Continuous progress in gene editing, synthetic biology, and high-throughput sequencing technologies has allowed researchers to design and optimize engineered probiotics with greater precision. CRISPR-Cas9 gene-editing technology, in particular, enables precise modification of the probiotic genome, facilitating the production of a variety of therapeutic molecules. Moreover, synthetic biology techniques can be employed to construct sophisticated gene circuits, enabling probiotics to sense environmental signals and respond appropriately. These technological innovations provide powerful tools for personalized probiotic interventions, allowing them to better meet the needs of individual patients.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>74939</offset><text>Challenges and future research directions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>74981</offset><text>Although personalized probiotic interventions have shown great potential in the treatment of IBD, their clinical application still faces several challenges. Accurately predicting patient responses to probiotic treatments remains a primary difficulty. Although several predictive models have been developed, their predictive ability and reliability still require further validation. Additionally, ensuring that engineered probiotics retain their therapeutic functionality within the complex intestinal environment without causing irreversible disturbances to the host microbiota remains a critical challenge. Future research should focus on developing more precise predictive models, optimizing the design and function of engineered probiotics, and exploring new therapeutic targets and mechanisms. Comprehensive studies addressing the long-term safety and stability of engineered probiotics are necessary to establish a scientific foundation for the widespread clinical application of personalized probiotic interventions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>76004</offset><text>Regulatory landscape and future directions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>76047</offset><text>The clinical translation of engineered probiotics for IBD is shaped by a complex interplay of regulatory frameworks, manufacturing feasibility, and scientific priorities. As a class of novel biologics with genetic modifications or synthetic components, engineered probiotics face stricter oversight than conventional probiotics do—reflecting concerns about long-term safety, ecological impact, and consistent therapeutic performance. Below is a detailed analysis of the current regulatory landscape, manufacturing and economic challenges, and actionable future research directions to accelerate their clinical adoption.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>76669</offset><text>Regulatory standards for engineered probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>76716</offset><text>Engineered probiotics are universally classified as biologics by regulatory agencies, but their classification subcategories and approval requirements vary by region. These differences arise from varying risk assessments of genetic modification, with a focus on three core pillars: (1) preclinical safety profiling; (2) clinical evidence of efficacy and safety; and (3) manufacturing quality and consistency.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>77125</offset><text>United states food and drug administration (FDA)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>77174</offset><text>The FDA regulates engineered probiotics under the Public Health Service Act (PHS Act) and Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FD&amp;C Act), with two primary pathways depending on the degree of genetic modification. For nongenetically modified engineered probiotics, the FDA typically requires an Investigational New Drug (IND) application for clinical trials, followed by a New Drug Application (NDA) if approved. For genetically modified (GM) probiotics, the FDA mandates a Biologics License application (BLA)—the highest standard for biologics—due to their novel molecular composition.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>77765</offset><text>Key requirements for the BLA of GM probiotics include preclinical safety data; clinical trial design; and chemical, manufacturing, and control (CMC) data. Among these, preclinical safety data include the risk of HGT, acute, subchronic, and chronic toxicity, immunogenicity, and genetic stability, and these data require comprehensive evaluation. Clinical trials include phase I trials, phase II trials, and phase III trials. Phase I trials (n = 20–100 healthy volunteers or mild IBD patients) are conducted to evaluate safety and pharmacokinetics (e.g., gut colonization duration via qPCR); phase II trials (n = 100–300 IBD patients) are conducted to evaluate dose–response relationships and preliminary efficacy (e.g., Mayo score reduction for ulcerative colitis [UC]); and phase III trials (n = 300–1,000 IBD patients) are conducted to confirm long-term efficacy (12–24 months) and rare adverse events. CMC data include strain construction, fermentation process validation, purification and formulation, and quality control methods. These data require the submission of detailed documents.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>78881</offset><text>Notably, the FDA’s 2023 Guidance for Industry: Probiotics for Human Use (FDA-2023-D-0945) emphasizes “risk-based oversight”—GM probiotics with high HGT potential require additional containment data, whereas low-risk strains may qualify for expedited pathways such as breakthrough therapy designation (BTD) if they address unmet needs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>79224</offset><text>European medicines agency (EMA)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>79256</offset><text>The EMA classifies GM-engineered probiotics as advanced therapy medicinal products (ATMPs)—specifically, gene therapy products—under regulation (EC) No 1394/2007. This classification reflects their “novel mode of action” (genetic modification to deliver therapeutic effects) and triggers a specialized approval process managed by the Committee for Advanced Therapies (CAT) in collaboration with the Committee for Medicinal Products for Human Use (CHMP).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>79718</offset><text>Key ATMP requirements distinct from those of the FDA include ecological impact assessment, assessment of ATMPs, and long-term clinical follow-up (LTCF). An ecological impact assessment is mandatory for assessing the potential environmental persistence of genetically modified (GM) probiotics, as well as their ability to transfer genes to environmental bacteria.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>80081</offset><text>An ecological impact assessment is needed to evaluate the potential persistence of genetically modified (GM) probiotics in the environment and their capacity for gene transfer to environmental bacteria. The EMA’s 2022 guidelines on environmental risk assessment for ATMPs (EMA/CHMP/ATMP/483044/2016) require modeling of environmental concentrations and “worst-case scenario” testing. Postapproval requires LTCF to be conducted, aiming to track delayed adverse events and ecological impacts. The EMA mandates a risk management plan (RMP) with predefined endpoints. Prior to IND submission, sponsors must seek scientific advice from the CAT to align study design with ATMP standards. Formal classification confirmation is also required to confirm ATMP status, avoiding postsubmission delays.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>80877</offset><text>For non-GM-engineered probiotics, the EMA follows the traditional centralized procedure (valid in all EU/EEA countries) with requirements similar to those of the FDA but with greater emphasis on “patient-centered outcomes”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>81105</offset><text>National medical product administration (NMPA)</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>81152</offset><text>The NMPA of China regulates engineered probiotics under the regulations of the administration of medical products (2019) and aligns with international standards while imposing the following unique requirements for local relevance: (1) manufacturing facilities must meet cleanroom grade A/B standards for GM strain handling, with negative-pressure labs to prevent cross-contamination; the NMPA’s 2024 technical guidelines for the evaluation of gene therapy products mandate real-time monitoring of fermentation and QC testing of every batch; (2) phase II/III trials must include ≥50% Chinese IBD patients to account for ethnic differences in gut microbiota composition and drug metabolism; multicenter trials must be conducted at NMPA-accredited sites; and (3) the NMPA requires a 3-year post-marketing surveillance (PMS) program with active pharmacovigilance and periodic reevaluation of manufacturing processes.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>82069</offset><text>Manufacturing and economic considerations</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>82111</offset><text>The scalability and cost of engineered probiotics are critical bottlenecks for clinical translation, as their complex production processes are far more resource intensive than those of conventional probiotics. Below is a detailed breakdown of the challenges and mitigation strategies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>82396</offset><text>Scalability challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>82419</offset><text>Scalability is defined as the ability to produce consistent, high-quality batches at volumes sufficient for clinical use (10,000–100,000 doses/year) while maintaining viability and genetic stability.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>82621</offset><text>Fermentation of GM probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>82651</offset><text>Compared with wild-type strains, GM strains often exhibit reduced fitness and require optimized nutrient media and strict temperature/pH control to prevent plasmid loss or off-target mutations. Large-scale bioreactors (500–5,000 L) exacerbate these challenges, as gradients in oxygen concentration or nutrient distribution can lead to batch-to-batch variability. GM probiotics require biosafety level 2 (BSL-2) fermentation facilities to prevent environmental release, including dedicated air filtration systems (HEPA filters) and wastewater decontamination. Compared with conventional probiotic facilities, these requirements increase capital expenditure (CAPEX).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>83320</offset><text>Targeted encapsulation technologies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>83356</offset><text>Laboratory-scale encapsulation (1–10 g batches) uses electrostatic droplet generators or microfluidics to produce uniform particles, but scaling to 1–10 kg batches requires parallelization of the equipment and optimized drying processes. For example, spray drying—common for conventional probiotics—reduces the viability of GM probiotics because of heat stress, necessitating low-temperature lyophilization, which increases energy consumption. The polydopamine-chitosan coating of probiotics requires precise control of the pH and reaction time to avoid aggregation. Scaling this process to 100 L batches requires stirred-tank reactors with inline pH monitoring, increasing process complexity and QC costs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>84077</offset><text>Downstream processing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>84099</offset><text>The purification of GM probiotics requires the removal of fermentation byproducts and the confirmation of GM allele purity. This involves ultrafiltration and flow cytometry sorting, which reduce yield by 20–30% and add 1–2 days to the production time compared with conventional centrifugation-based purification methods.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_3</infon><offset>84426</offset><text>Cost-reduction strategies</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>84452</offset><text>Process optimization</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>84473</offset><text>Continuous fermentation: Replacing batch fermentation with continuous processes reduces batch-to-batch variability by 50% and increases productivity. Replacing expensive PLGA with natural polysaccharide blends maintains 80–90% encapsulation efficiency while reducing material costs by 80%.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_4</infon><offset>84765</offset><text>Regulatory and policy levers</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>84794</offset><text>Seeking FDA BTD or EMA PRIME designation reduces R&amp;D time by 1–2 years and cutting costs by 20–30%. For example, a GM probiotic for refractory UC could qualify for BTD if it demonstrates a 50% remission rate in phase II. Collaborations between academic labs, biotechnology companies, and governments can share R&amp;D costs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>85121</offset><text>Conclusion and outlook</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>85144</offset><text>This review outlines the current state and recent progress in the use of engineered probiotics for treating IBD. Through genetic modification and synthetic biology, these probiotics produce various therapeutic molecules, regulating the balance of the gut microbiota, strengthening intestinal barrier function, and modulating immune responses. Notably, their development and clinical translation are increasingly empowered by ongoing advances in systems biology, multiomics technologies (genomics, transcriptomics, metabolomics), and artificial intelligence (AI), which enable more precise identification of patient-specific microbial and immune dysfunctions—an essential prerequisite for targeted IBD management. Engineered probiotics exhibit significant therapeutic potential for UC and CD, with three key advantages: targeted delivery to inflamed areas (lowering side effects in noninflamed regions), synergistic application with other therapies to potentially enhance efficacy, and the capacity for personalized interventions. Specifically, the integration of multiomics data and AI-driven analysis may decipher individual microbial–immune dysregulation patterns, thereby optimizing treatment outcomes and reducing adverse effects, although this requires further clinical validation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>86435</offset><text>Despite their potential, the following critical challenges remain: improving the survival and colonization of engineered probiotics in the complex intestinal microenvironment; ensuring their long-term safety and stability without inducing irreversible perturbations to the host microbiota; and validating the accuracy, reliability, and generalizability of AI-powered predictive models for patient therapy responses. While systems biology and multiomics technologies offer promising approaches to address these issues, their practical implementation remains challenging. Thus, optimizing probiotic formulations to align with individual patient profiles, guided by systems biology and AI-driven multiomics analysis, remains a key future research direction.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>87190</offset><text>Advancements in gene editing, synthetic biology (for building complex genetic circuits), and high-throughput sequencing have propelled engineered probiotics into a new phase of development. Personalized strategies may further expand their application scope, offering a potentially safer and more tailored alternative to traditional therapies that are often associated with significant side effects. While targeted and personalized approaches involving engineered probiotics are unlikely to completely transform IBD treatment paradigms in the near term, they may emerge as important components of future IBD care. Their successful translation could help reduce unnecessary medical resource use and advance precision/personalized IBD treatment toward a potential clinical gold standard—provided that the current technical and safety challenges are adequately resolved.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>88059</offset><text>Edited by: Charalampia Amerikanou, Harokopio University, Greece</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>88123</offset><text>Reviewed by: Francisco Jose Roig, Universidad San Jorge, Spain</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>88186</offset><text>Ravi Verma, Jawaharlal Nehru University, India</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">CONCL</infon><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>88233</offset><text>Honghua Hu, Macquarie University, Australia</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>88277</offset><text>Author contributions</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">AUTH_CONT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>88298</offset><text>XW: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Methodology, Validation, Visualization, Writing – original draft, Writing – review &amp; editing. YC: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Methodology, Software, Writing – review &amp; editing. JH: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Methodology, Validation, Writing – review &amp; editing. FX: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Methodology, Software, Validation, Writing – review &amp; editing. JJ: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Software, Validation, Visualization, Writing – review &amp; editing. NN: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Software, Supervision, Validation, Writing – review &amp; editing. LJ: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Funding acquisition, Resources, Supervision, Validation, Visualization, Writing – review &amp; editing. YX: Conceptualization, Data curation, Formal analysis, Investigation, Methodology, Software, Validation, Visualization, Writing – original draft, Writing – review &amp; editing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>89441</offset><text>Conflict of interest</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>89462</offset><text>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>89635</offset><text>Generative AI statement</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>89659</offset><text>The author(s) declared that Generative AI was not used in the creation of this manuscript.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>89750</offset><text>Any alternative text (alt text) provided alongside figures in this article has been generated by Frontiers with the support of artificial intelligence and reasonable efforts have been made to ensure accuracy, including review by the authors wherever possible. If you identify any issues, please contact us.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>90057</offset><text>Publisher’s note</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">COMP_INT</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>90076</offset><text>All claims expressed in this article are solely those of the authors and do not necessarily represent those of their affiliated organizations, or those of the publisher, the editors and the reviewers. Any product that may be evaluated in this article, or claim that may be made by its manufacturer, is not guaranteed or endorsed by the publisher.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>90423</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">104998</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Abdi;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lohrasbi;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Asadi;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Esghaei;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jazi;given-names:F. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rohani;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.micpath.2021.104998</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34044041</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microb. Pathog.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">158</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>90434</offset><text>Interesting probiotic traits of mother’s milk Lactobacillus isolates; from bacteriocin to inflammatory bowel disease improvement</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3806</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Abeltino;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hatem;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Serantoni;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Riente;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:De-Giulio;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:De-Spirito;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/nu16223806</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39599593</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nutrients</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>90565</offset><text>Unraveling the gut microbiota: implications for precision nutrition and personalized medicine</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">47</infon><infon key="lpage">65</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Agrawal;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Spencer;given-names:E. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Colombel;given-names:J. F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ungaro;given-names:R. C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2021.04.063</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33940007</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">161</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>90659</offset><text>Approach to the management of recently diagnosed inflammatory bowel disease patients: a user’s guide for adult and pediatric gastroenterologists</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">562</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Aja;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zeng;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gray;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Connelley;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chaganti;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Jacobs;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/nu17030562</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39940420</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nutrients</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>90806</offset><text>Health effects and therapeutic potential of the gut microbe Akkermansia muciniphila</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">59</infon><infon key="lpage">81</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ali;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vora;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mathuria;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kataria;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mani;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/bs.pmbts.2024.07.008</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39266188</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Prog. Mol. Biol. Transl. Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">208</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>90890</offset><text>Advances in CRISPR-cas systems for gut microbiome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2505114</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Alizadeh;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wong;given-names:U.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Siaton;given-names:B. C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:France;given-names:M. T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Patil;given-names:S. A.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:George;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/19490976.2025.2505114</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40382763</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>90940</offset><text>The intestinal mucosa-associated microbiota in IBD-associated arthritis displays lower relative abundance of Roseburia intestinalis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2558</infon><infon key="lpage">2572</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:An;given-names:H. R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Douillard;given-names:F. P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:G. H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhai;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Song;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1074/mcp.M114.039156</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24965555</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mol. Cell. Proteomics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>91072</offset><text>Integrated transcriptomic and proteomic analysis of the bile stress response in a centenarian-originated probiotic Bifidobacterium longum BBMN68*</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1063</infon><infon key="lpage">1076</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Aniwan;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Santiago;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Loftus;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Park;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/ueg2.12350</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36479863</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">United European Gastroenterol J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>91218</offset><text>The epidemiology of inflammatory bowel disease in asia and asian immigrants to western countries</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">111</infon><infon key="lpage">123</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arosa;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Camba-Gómez;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Golubnitschaja;given-names:O.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Conde-Aranda;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s13167-024-00351-x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38463620</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EPMA J.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>91315</offset><text>Predictive, preventive and personalised approach as a conceptual and technological innovation in primary and secondary care of inflammatory bowel disease benefiting affected individuals and populations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Asai;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yoshikawa;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ikeda;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Taniguchi;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sawamura;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Tsuji;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/biom13010010</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36671395</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biomolecules</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>91517</offset><text>Encouraging Tactics with Genetically Modified Probiotics to Improve Immunity for the Prevention of Immune-Related Diseases including Cardio-Metabolic Disorders</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1126579</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ashique;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mishra;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Garg;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sibuh;given-names:B. Z.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Taneja;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rai;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1126579</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37545572</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Nutr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>91677</offset><text>Recent updates on correlation between reactive oxygen species and synbiotics for effective management of ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">731</infon><infon key="lpage">740</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Anzalone;given-names:A. V.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gao;given-names:X. D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Podracky;given-names:C. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Nelson;given-names:A. T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Koblan;given-names:L. W.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Raguram;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41587-021-01133-w</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature biotechnology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>91801</offset><text>Programmable deletion, replacement, integration and inversion of large DNA sequences with twin prime editing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">eaap8914</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arnau;given-names:V. V.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Imhann;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Collij;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jankipersadsing;given-names:S. A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gurry;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Mujagic;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aap8914</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30567928</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Science translational medicine</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>91910</offset><text>Gut microbiota composition and functional changes in inflammatory bowel disease and irritable bowel syndrome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">265</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Barra;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Danino;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Garrido;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fbioe.2020.00265</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32296696</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>92019</offset><text>Engineered probiotics for detection and treatment of inflammatory intestinal diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1302</infon><infon key="lpage">1315</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Baumgart;given-names:D. C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Le-Berre;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJMra1907607</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34587387</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N. Engl. J. Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">385</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>92105</offset><text>Newer biologic and small-molecule therapies for inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">754</infon><infon key="lpage">759</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Braat;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rottiers;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hommes;given-names:D. W.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huyghebaert;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Remaut;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Remon;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2006.03.028</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16716759</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin. Gastroenterol. Hepatol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>92180</offset><text>A phase I trial with transgenic bacteria expressing interleukin-10 in crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">411</infon><infon key="lpage">427</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bruner;given-names:L. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:White;given-names:A. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Proksell;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.pop.2023.03.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37516511</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Prim. Care</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>92268</offset><text>Inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2194794</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Buttimer;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Khokhlova;given-names:E. V.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stein;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hueston;given-names:C. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Govi;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Draper;given-names:L. A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/19490976.2023.2194794</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36994608</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>92295</offset><text>Temperate bacteriophages infecting the mucin-degrading bacterium Ruminococcus gnavus from the human gut</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">660</infon><infon key="lpage">667</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Biela;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Watkinson;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Meier;given-names:U. C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Baker;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gavin;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Becer;given-names:C. R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.bios.2015.01.060</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25660510</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biosensors &amp; bioelectronics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">68</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>92399</offset><text>Disposable MMP-9 sensor based on the degradation of peptide cross-linked hydrogel films using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0024024</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cho;given-names:M. Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Eom;given-names:J. H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Choi;given-names:E. M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yang;given-names:S. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Lee;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Kim;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/cmr.00240-24</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40261032</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clinical microbiology reviews</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">38</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>92532</offset><text>Recent advances in therapeutic probiotics: insights from human trials</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">172</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bermúdez-Humarán;given-names:L. G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chassaing;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Langella;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12934-024-02449-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38867272</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microbial cell factories</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>92602</offset><text>Exploring the interaction and impact of probiotic and commensal bacteria on vitamins, minerals and short chain fatty acids metabolism</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">347</infon><infon key="lpage">360</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Caballero-Flores;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pickard;given-names:J. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Núñez;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41579-022-00833-7</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36539611</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Rev. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>92736</offset><text>Microbiota-mediated colonization resistance: mechanisms and regulation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">151128</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cai;given-names:H. T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:T. X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Feng;given-names:W. T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wu;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhao;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wang;given-names:T. T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2024.151128</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39644601</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">742</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>92807</offset><text>Triple probiotics attenuate colitis via inhibiting macrophage glycolysis dependent pro-inflammatory response</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">617</infon><infon key="lpage">627</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cao;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jin;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gao;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ding;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wen;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Qian;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41565-023-01346-x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36973397</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Nanotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>92916</offset><text>Artificial-enzymes-armed Bifidobacterium longum probiotics for alleviating intestinal inflammation and microbiota dysbiosis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">ii3</infon><infon key="lpage">ii15</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Caron;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Honap;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Peyrin-Biroulet;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjae082</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39475082</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>93040</offset><text>Epidemiology of inflammatory bowel disease across the ages in the era of advanced therapies</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">28</infon><infon key="lpage">46</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ceccato;given-names:H. D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Silva;given-names:T. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Genaro;given-names:L. M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Silva;given-names:J. F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Souza;given-names:W. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Oliveira;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.62347/XILL3707</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39959235</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am. J. Transl. Res.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>93132</offset><text>Artificial intelligence use for precision medicine in inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">963</infon><infon key="lpage">978</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Centanni;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bencardino;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:D’Amico;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zilli;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Parigi;given-names:T. L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Allocca;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/14728222.2024.2433124</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39611536</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Opin. Ther. Targets</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>93234</offset><text>Targeting mucosal healing in crohn’s disease: efficacy of novel pathways and therapeutic targets</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1738</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Charbonneau;given-names:M. R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Isabella;given-names:V. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kurtz;given-names:C. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41467-020-15508-1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32269218</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Commun.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>93333</offset><text>Developing a new class of engineered live bacterial therapeutics to treat human diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">170</infon><infon key="lpage">182</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cao;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Su;given-names:W. H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhan;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Dong;given-names:W. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/path.5358</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31610014</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Pathol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">250</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>93422</offset><text>Fusobacterium nucleatum facilitates ulcerative colitis through activating IL-17F signaling to NF-κB via the upregulation of CARD3 expression</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">123163</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shui;given-names:M. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:H. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Guo;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hao;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2025.123163</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39923539</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biomaterials</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">318</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>93567</offset><text>Inflammation-targeted delivery of probiotics for alleviation of colitis and associated cognitive disorders through improved vitality and colonization</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">10069</infon><infon key="lpage">10092</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chen;given-names:Z. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Xiao;given-names:C. T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:J. T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jian;given-names:S. Q.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:P. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Lin;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.5c02086</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40234746</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Agric. Food Chem.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">73</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>93717</offset><text>The impact of diet on the colonization of beneficial microbes from an ecological perspective</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2696</infon><infon key="lpage">2709</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cherrak;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Salazar;given-names:M. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Näpflin;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Malfertheiner;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Herzog;given-names:M. K. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Schubert;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41564-024-01775-x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39160293</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>93810</offset><text>Non-canonical start codons confer context-dependent advantages in carbohydrate utilization for commensal E. coli in the murine gut</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1302998</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Deng;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pei;given-names:C. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cai;given-names:K. W.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huang;given-names:W. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Xiao;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zhang;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1302998</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38292253</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>93941</offset><text>Lactobacillus acidophilus and its metabolite ursodeoxycholic acid ameliorate ulcerative colitis by promoting Treg differentiation and inhibiting M1 macrophage polarization</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5929</infon><infon key="lpage">5936</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Desmond;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fitzgerald;given-names:G. F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stanton;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ross;given-names:R. P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/AEM.70.10.5929-5936.2004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15466535</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Appl. Environ. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>94113</offset><text>Improved stress tolerance of GroESL-overproducing Lactococcus lactis and probiotic Lactobacillus paracasei NFBC 338</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">214</infon><infon key="lpage">222</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dong;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sahle;given-names:F. F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lohan;given-names:S. B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Saeidpour;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Albrecht;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Teutloff;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2018.12.045</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30597246</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Control. Release</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">295</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>94229</offset><text>pH-sensitive Eudragit® L100 nanoparticles promote cutaneous penetration and drug release on the skin</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">765</infon><infon key="lpage">780</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Du;given-names:Y. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Guo;given-names:H. L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Su;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Guo;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:B. W.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wang;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.093</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38905998</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Colloid Interface Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">673</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>94331</offset><text>Surface nanocoating-based universal platform for programmed delivery of microorganisms in complicated digestive tract</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3983</infon><infon key="lpage">4002</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Doman;given-names:J. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pandey;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Neugebauer;given-names:M. E.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:An;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Davis;given-names:J. R.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Randolph;given-names:P. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cell.2023.07.039</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37657419</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">186</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>94449</offset><text>Phage-assisted evolution and protein engineering yield compact, efficient prime editors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1680</infon><infon key="lpage">1692</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eberl;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Weiss;given-names:A. S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jochum;given-names:L. M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Durai-Raj;given-names:A. C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ring;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hussain;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.chom.2021.09.004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34610296</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Host Microbe</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>94537</offset><text>E. coli enhance colonization resistance against Salmonella Typhimurium by competing for galactitol, a context-dependent limiting carbon source</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">676</infon><infon key="lpage">685</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Freter;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Brickner;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Botney;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cleven;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Aranki;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/iai.39.2.676-685</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">6339388</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Infect. Immun.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">1983</infon><offset>94680</offset><text>Mechanisms that control bacterial populations in continuous-flow culture models of mouse large intestinal flora</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e70206</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gao;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jing;given-names:H. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Qiu;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:S. B.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Xu;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/fsn3.70206</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40370418</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Food Sci. Nutr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>94792</offset><text>Effects of biofilm formation on gastrointestinal tolerance, mucoadhesion and transcriptomic responses of probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1226</infon><infon key="lpage">1233</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gao;given-names:H. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chen;given-names:X. T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hai;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wei;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zhang;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.4014/jmb.2205.05041.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36196014</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Microbiol. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>94908</offset><text>The functional roles of Lactobacillus acidophilus in different physiological and pathological processes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2291164</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gavzy;given-names:S. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kensiski;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lee;given-names:Z. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mongodin;given-names:E. F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ma;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bromberg;given-names:J. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/19490976.2023.2291164</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38055306</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>95012</offset><text>Bifidobacterium mechanisms of immune modulation and tolerance</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1450</infon><infon key="lpage">1461</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gibbons;given-names:S. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gurry;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lampe;given-names:J. W.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chakrabarti;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Dam;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Everard;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/advances/nmac075</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35776947</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv. Nutr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>95074</offset><text>Perspective: leveraging the gut microbiota to predict personalized responses to dietary, prebiotic, and probiotic interventions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1047</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Goldiș;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dragomir;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mercioni;given-names:M. A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Goldiș;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sirca;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Enătescu;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/microorganisms13051047</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40431220</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microorganisms</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>95202</offset><text>Personalized microbiome modulation to improve clinical outcomes in pediatric inflammatory bowel disease: a multi-omics and interventional approach</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">609722</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Han;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lu;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xie;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Fei;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zheng;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wang;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fcimb.2021.609722</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33791234</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Cell. Infect. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>95349</offset><text>Probiotic gastrointestinal transit and colonization after oral administration: a long journey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">662</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hlaing;given-names:S. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kim;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lee;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kwak;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kim;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yoo;given-names:J. W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics12070662</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32674435</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pharmaceutics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>95443</offset><text>Enhanced viability of probiotics against gastric acid by one-step coating process with poly-L-lysine: in vitro and in vivo evaluation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">117812</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hoang;given-names:H. T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jo;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Phan;given-names:Q. T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Park;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Park;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Oh;given-names:C. W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2021.117812</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33712157</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Carbohydr. Polym.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">260</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>95577</offset><text>Dual pH−/thermo-responsive chitosan-based hydrogels prepared using “click” chemistry for colon-targeted drug delivery applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">375</infon><infon key="lpage">388</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Holzapfel;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Arini;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Aeschbacher;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Coppolecchia;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Pot;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3920/BM2017.0148</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Beneficial Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>95714</offset><text>Enterococcus faecium SF68 as a model for efficacy and safety evaluation of pharmaceutical probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1235</infon><infon key="lpage">1248</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hong;given-names:J. N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fu;given-names:T. T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Liu;given-names:W. Z.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Du;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bu;given-names:J. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wei;given-names:G. J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2147/DMSO.S456173</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38496006</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Diabetes Metab. Syndr. Obes.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>95815</offset><text>An update on the role and potential molecules in relation to Ruminococcus gnavus in inflammatory bowel disease, obesity and diabetes mellitus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12917</infon><infon key="lpage">12932</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hu;given-names:Q. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Xu;given-names:X. C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Duan;given-names:Y. X.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Jin;given-names:Y. X.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/acsnano.4c00830</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38720520</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ACS Nano</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>95957</offset><text>Polyphenolic nanoparticle-modified probiotics for microenvironment remodeling and targeted therapy of iInflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0192964</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hu;given-names:P. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yuan;given-names:Y. H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yue;given-names:T. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Guo;given-names:C. F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0192964</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29494656</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS One</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>96087</offset><text>Bile acid patterns in commercially available oxgall powders used for the evaluation of the bile tolerance ability of potential probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">110</infon><infon key="lpage">118</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Huang;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liu;given-names:J. Q.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yu;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mo;given-names:L. H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Get;given-names:R. T.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zhang;given-names:H. P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/cmi.2014.137</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25683610</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cellular &amp; molecular immunology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>96225</offset><text>Regulation of TWIK-related potassium channel-1 (Trek1) restitutes intestinal epithelial barrier function</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e12360</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hua;given-names:S. Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:K. Q.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shang;given-names:P. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Pan;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zhu;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/advs.202512360</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Advanced science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>96330</offset><text>An inflammation-targeting engineered probiotic Escherichia coli Nissle 1917 with high anti-TNF-α nanobody secretion efficacy alleviates ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">857</infon><infon key="lpage">864</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Isabella;given-names:V. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ha;given-names:B. N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Castillo;given-names:M. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lubkowicz;given-names:D. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rowe;given-names:S. E.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Millet;given-names:Y. A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nbt.4222</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30102294</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">36</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>96489</offset><text>Development of a synthetic live bacterial therapeutic for the human metabolic disease phenylketonuria</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">101190</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jensen;given-names:B. A. H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Heyndrickx;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jonkers;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mackie;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Millet;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Naghibi;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2023.101190</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37683651</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Rep Med.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>96591</offset><text>Small intestine vs. colon ecology and physiology: why it matters in probiotic administration</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e2417050</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Jiang;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ma;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhou;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Han;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liang;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Dong;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/adma.202417050</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40451772</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv. Mater.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>96684</offset><text>Synergistic genetic and chemical engineering of probiotics for enhanced intestinal microbiota regulation and ulcerative colitis treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">86</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kharaghani;given-names:A. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Harzandi;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Khorsand;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rajabnia;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kharaghani;given-names:A. A.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Houri;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12941-023-00630-x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37710309</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Ann. Clin. Microbiol. Antimicrob.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">22</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>96822</offset><text>High prevalence of mucosa-associated extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae among Iranain patients with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">430</infon><infon key="lpage">435</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kim;given-names:D. E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lee;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cho;given-names:S. I.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kim;given-names:J. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41587-019-0050-1</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature biotechnology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>97006</offset><text>Genome-wide target specificity of CRISPR RNA-guided adenine base editors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">575</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:H. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jeon;given-names:H. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kim;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Shim;given-names:J. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Lee;given-names:J. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/ijms25010575</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38203747</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Int. J. Mol. Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>97079</offset><text>Lactiplantibacillus plantarum HY7718 improves intestinal integrity in a DSS-induced ulcerative colitis mouse model by suppressing inflammation through modulation of the gut microbiota</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6702</infon><infon key="lpage">6715</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Koga;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3748/wjg.v28.i47.6702</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36620346</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J. Gastroenterol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">28</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>97263</offset><text>Microbiota in the stomach and application of probiotics to gastroduodenal diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1267378</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kang;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cho;given-names:B. K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fbioe.2023.1267378</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37929193</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontiers in bioengineering and biotechnology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>97346</offset><text>Systems and synthetic biology-driven engineering of live bacterial therapeutics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">241</infon><infon key="lpage">250</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kramer;given-names:B. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fischer;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fussenegger;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ymben.2005.02.005</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16140238</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Metabolic engineering</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>97426</offset><text>Semi-synthetic mammalian gene regulatory networks</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">985</infon><infon key="lpage">1001</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kuo;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Uzunovic;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jacobson;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dourado;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gierke;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rajendram;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjae016</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38267224</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>97476</offset><text>Toxigenic clostridium perfringens isolated from at-risk paediatric inflammatory bowel disease patients</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2803</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:KY;given-names:Y. W.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tsai;given-names:S. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Lin;given-names:J. H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Syu;given-names:Z. J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/nu15122803</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37375705</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nutrients</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>97579</offset><text>Probiotic formula ameliorates renal dysfunction indicators, glycemic levels, and blood pressure in a diabetic nephropathy mouse model</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">96</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Leeflang;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wright;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Worthley;given-names:D. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Din;given-names:M. O.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Woods;given-names:S. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41522-025-00734-6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40483298</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">NPJ Biofilms Microbiomes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>97713</offset><text>Evolutionary adaptation of probiotics in the gut: selection pressures, optimization strategies, and regulatory challenges</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1364</infon><infon key="lpage">1376</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Leibovitzh;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lee;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xue;given-names:M. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Raygoza-Garay;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hernandez-Rocha;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Madsen;given-names:K. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2022.07.004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35850197</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">163</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>97835</offset><text>Altered gut microbiome composition and function are associated with gut barrier dysfunction in healthy relatives of patients with crohn’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">724</infon><infon key="lpage">732</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Achkar;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Haritunians;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jacobs;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hui;given-names:K. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:D'Amato;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2016.06.051</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27492617</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">151</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>97983</offset><text>A pleiotropic missense variant in SLC39A8 is associated with Crohn's disease and human gut microbiome composition</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2377576</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:M. F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ding;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wei;given-names:J. G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dong;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Dai;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/19490976.2024.2377576</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39068517</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>98097</offset><text>Gut microbiota metabolite indole-3-acetic acid maintains intestinal epithelial homeostasis through mucin sulfation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2329147</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Han;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sun;given-names:L. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:X. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:W. Z.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hao;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/19490976.2024.2329147</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38528729</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>98212</offset><text>Indole-3-acetic acid alleviates DSS-induced colitis by promoting the production of R-equol from Bifidobacterium pseudolongum</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">361</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:C. X.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Peng;given-names:K. X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xiao;given-names:S. Q.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Long;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yu;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41420-023-01666-w</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37773196</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Death Discov.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>98337</offset><text>The role of Lactobacillus in inflammatory bowel disease: from actualities to prospects</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">138</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sun;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dai;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chen;given-names:H. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yi;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Niu;given-names:J. K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12866-021-02201-6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33947329</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">21</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>98424</offset><text>Ecological and network analyses identify four microbial species with potential significance for the diagnosis/treatment of ulcerative colitis (UC)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">128</infon><infon key="lpage">139</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Litvak;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mon;given-names:K. K. Z.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Nguyen;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chanthavixay;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liou;given-names:M. G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Velazquez;given-names:E. M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.chom.2018.12.003</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30629913</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Host Microbe</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>98571</offset><text>Commensal Enterobacteriaceae protect against Salmonella colonization through oxygen competition</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">04041</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:C. N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liu;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:Q. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Song;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Shi;given-names:J. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7189/jogh.14.04041.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38386717</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Glob. Health</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>98667</offset><text>Temporal relationship between inflammation and metabolic disorders and their impact on cancer risk</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">eabp8798</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Heelan;given-names:W. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hu;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1126/sciadv.abp8798</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36367930</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Sci. Adv.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>98766</offset><text>Mucoadhesive probiotic backpacks with ROS nanoscavengers enhance the bacteriotherapy for inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">98</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:Y. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yang;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tang;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:F. C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Huang;given-names:S. J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Liu;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s40168-022-01296-x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35761415</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microbiome</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>98883</offset><text>TLR4 regulates RORγt+ regulatory T-cell responses and susceptibility to colon inflammation through interaction with Akkermansia muciniphila</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2201</infon><infon key="lpage">2210</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:Y. Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yin;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Huang;given-names:L. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Teng;given-names:H. F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Shen;given-names:T. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Qin;given-names:H. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1039/d0fo02786c</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33595001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biomed. Pharmacother.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>99027</offset><text>Long-term and continuous administration of Bacillus subtilis during remission effectively maintains the remission of inflammatory bowel disease by protecting intestinal integrity, regulating epithelial proliferation, and reshaping microbial structure and function</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">331</infon><infon key="lpage">345</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhao;given-names:W. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lan;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mou;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s13238-020-00745-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32601832</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Protein Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>99291</offset><text>The microbiome in inflammatory bowel diseases: from pathogenesis to therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">655</infon><infon key="lpage">662</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lloyd-Price;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Arze;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ananthakrishnan;given-names:A. N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schirmer;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Avila-Pacheco;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Poon;given-names:T. W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41586-019-1237-9</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31142855</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">569</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>99367</offset><text>Multi-omics of the gut microbial ecosystem in inflammatory bowel diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2198</infon><infon key="lpage">2208</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Luan;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhang;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chen;given-names:C. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jiang;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yao;given-names:Y. G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Deng;given-names:Q. C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/acsnano.1c08244</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35142211</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ACS Nano</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>99441</offset><text>Controlled nutrient delivery through a pH-responsive wood vehicle</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">371</infon><infon key="lpage">384</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Luo;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:De-Souza;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ramachandran;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yi;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Ma;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2022.10.030</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36309096</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Control. Release</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">352</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>99507</offset><text>Precise oral delivery systems for probiotics: a review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">98</infon><infon key="lpage">110</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Luo;given-names:H. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wu;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lin;given-names:S. S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:M. M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Cao;given-names:Z. P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.mattod.2023.01.001</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mater. Today</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>99562</offset><text>Encoding bacterial colonization and therapeutic modality by wrapping with an adhesive drug-loadable nanocoating</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">772</infon><infon key="lpage">786</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lynch;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Goers;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lesser;given-names:C. F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tips.2022.02.002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35232591</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends Pharmacol. Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>99674</offset><text>Emerging strategies for engineering Escherichia coli Nissle 1917-based therapeutics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">25657</infon><infon key="lpage">25670</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lin;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Han;given-names:S. W.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Shi;given-names:X. B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:He;given-names:Z. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/acsnano.4c07750</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39215751</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">ACS Nano</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>99758</offset><text>Oral microto-nano genome-editing system enabling targeted delivery and conditional activation of CRISPR-Cas9 for gene therapy of inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">921</infon><infon key="lpage">931</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ma;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Guo;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xia;given-names:B. B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y. W.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liu;given-names:X. L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yu;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41587-022-01226-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35241840</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>99914</offset><text>Identification of antimicrobial peptides from the human gut microbiome using deep learning</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">81</infon><infon key="lpage">82</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mao;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chen;given-names:M. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41575-021-00555-w</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34785787</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Rev. Gastroenterol. Hepatol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>100005</offset><text>Precision medicine in IBD: genes, drugs, bugs and omics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">10675</infon><infon key="lpage">10690</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mawad;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Helmy;given-names:Y. A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shalkami;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kathayat;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rajashekara;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00253-018-9417-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">30302522</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Applied microbiology and biotechnology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">102</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>100061</offset><text>E. coli Nissle microencapsulation in alginate-chitosan nanoparticles and its effect on Campylobacter jejuni in vitro</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1390351</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Muro;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhang;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:S. X.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhao;given-names:Z. H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jin;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Mao;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fendo.2024.1390351</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39076514</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Endocrinol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>100178</offset><text>The emerging role of oxidative stress in inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e41120</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Muzammil;given-names:M. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fariha;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Patel;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sohail;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kumar;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Khan;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7759/cureus.41120</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37519622</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cureus.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>100246</offset><text>Advancements in inflammatory bowel disease: a narrative review of diagnostics, management, epidemiology, prevalence, patient outcomes, quality of life, and clinical presentation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1999</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Oberoi;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tolun;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Altintas;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sharma;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/foods10091999</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34574109</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Foods</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>100424</offset><text>Effect of alginate-microencapsulated hydrogels on the survival of Lactobacillus rhamnosus under simulated gastrointestinal conditions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1324999</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ohgi;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Saha;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhou;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sakuma;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sakurai;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Nakano;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1324999</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38343714</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>100558</offset><text>In vitro evaluation of the immunomodulatory and wakame assimilation properties of Lactiplantibacillus plantarum strains from swine milk</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">630</infon><infon key="lpage">641</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Oliveira;given-names:R. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ng;given-names:K. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Correia;given-names:M. B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cabral;given-names:V.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Shi;given-names:H. D.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Sonnenburg;given-names:J. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41564-019-0658-4</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31959968</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>100694</offset><text>Klebsiella michiganensis transmission enhances resistance to enterobacteriaceae gut invasion by nutrition competition</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1663</infon><infon key="lpage">1679</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Osbelt;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wende;given-names:M. R. E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Almási;given-names:É.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Derksen;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Muthukumarasamy;given-names:U.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Lesker;given-names:T. R.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.chom.2021.09.003</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34610293</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Host Microbe</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>100812</offset><text>Klebsiella oxytoca causes colonization resistance against multidrug-resistant K. pneumoniae in the gut via cooperative carbohydrate competition</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3510</infon><infon key="lpage">3513</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ott;given-names:S. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Plamondon;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hart;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Begun;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rehman;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Kamm;given-names:M. A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JCM.01512-08</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18701655</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Clin. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>100956</offset><text>Dynamics of the mucosa-associated flora in ulcerative colitis patients during remission and clinical relapse</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2007379</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pan;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:J. J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hou;given-names:W. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lin;given-names:S. S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pang;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/adma.202007379</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33629757</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv. Mater.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">33</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>101065</offset><text>Polymerization-mediated multifunctionalization of living cells for enhanced cell-based therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e202400705</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Phùng;given-names:T. T. T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dupont;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Beney;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chanut;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Karbowiak;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/mnfr.202400705</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39846848</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mol. Nutr. Food Res.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>101160</offset><text>Unlocking probiotic potential: physicochemical approaches to evaluate probiotic bacterial adhesion potential to the intestinal tract</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">930</infon><infon key="lpage">946</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pittayanon;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lau;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Leontiadis;given-names:G. I.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tse;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:Y. H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Surette;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2019.11.294</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31812509</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">158</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>101293</offset><text>Differences in gut microbiota in patients with vs without inflammatory bowel diseases: a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5580</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Praveschotinunt;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Duraj-Thatte;given-names:A. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gelfat;given-names:I.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Bahl;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chou;given-names:D. B.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Joshi;given-names:N. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41467-019-13336-6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31811125</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Commun.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>101400</offset><text>Engineered E. coli Nissle 1917 for the delivery of matrix-tethered therapeutic domains to the gut</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1733992</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Qiu;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ishimoto;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fu;given-names:L. F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Liu;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fcimb.2022.733992.</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35273921</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Cell lnfect. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>101498</offset><text>The gut microbiota and inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1486</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Quagliariello;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chierico;given-names:F. D.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Reddel;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Russo;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Muda;given-names:A. O.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:D'Argenio;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/microorganisms8101486</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32992653</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microorganisms</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>101548</offset><text>Fecal microbiota transplant in two ulcerative colitis pediatric cases: gut microbiota and clinical course correlations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">16</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rahmati;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zarimeidani;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ghanbari-Boroujeni;given-names:M. R.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sadighbathi;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kashaniasl;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Saleh;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s12602-025-10561-y</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Probiotics Antimicrob. Proteins</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>101667</offset><text>CRISPR-assisted probiotic and in situ engineering of gut microbiota: a prospect to modification of metabolic disorders</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">934695</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rodrigues;given-names:V. F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Elias-Oliveira;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pereira;given-names:Í. S.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Pereira;given-names:J. A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Barbosa;given-names:S. C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Machado;given-names:M. S. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.934695</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35874661</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Immunol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>101786</offset><text>Akkermansia muciniphila and gut immune system: a good friendship that attenuates inflammatory bowel disease, obesity, and diabetes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2078</infon><infon key="lpage">2100</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Roy;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dhaneshwar;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3748/wjg.v29.i14.2078</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37122604</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J. Gastroenterol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">29</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>101917</offset><text>Role of prebiotics, probiotics, and synbiotics in management of inflammatory bowel disease: current perspectives</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2345</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ruiz;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Delgado;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ruas-Madiedo;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sánchez;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Margolles;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fmicb.2017.02345</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29255450</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Front. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>102030</offset><text>Bifidobacteria and their molecular communication with the immune system</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">361</infon><infon key="lpage">371</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Raschmanová;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Weninger;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kovar;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/978-1-0716-4779-0_25</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">41028476</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Methods in molecular biology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2697</infon><infon key="year">2026</infon><offset>102102</offset><text>Engineering pichia pastoris strains using CRISPR/Cas9 technologies: the basic protocol</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e1900319</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rottinghaus;given-names:A. G.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Amrofell;given-names:M. B.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Moon;given-names:T. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/biot.201900319</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31860168</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biotechnology journal</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>102189</offset><text>Biosensing in smart engineered probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3289</infon><infon key="lpage">3315</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sang;given-names:G. Z.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:B. K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xie;given-names:Y. J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.7150/thno.103983</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40093907</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Theranostics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>102231</offset><text>Engineered probiotic-based biomaterials for inflammatory bowel disease treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">252</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Seishima;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Iida;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kitamura;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yutani;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Seki;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s13059-019-1879-9</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31767028</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Genome Biol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">20</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>102312</offset><text>Gut-derived Enterococcus faecium from ulcerative colitis patients promotes colitis in a genetically susceptible mouse host</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">715</infon><infon key="lpage">730.e3</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shah;given-names:S. C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Itzkowitz;given-names:S. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2021.10.035</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34757143</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">162</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>102435</offset><text>Colorectal cancer in inflammatory bowel disease: mechanisms and management</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e70426</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shanuke;given-names:D. S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ranasinghage;given-names:N. B. D. P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Illippangama;given-names:A. U.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kulathunga;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bandara;given-names:M. D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/fsn3.70426</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40538989</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Food Sci. Nutr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>102510</offset><text>Co-encapsulation of probiotics and prebiotics: techniques and applications in food fortification</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1307</infon><infon key="lpage">1343</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Singh;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Loftus;given-names:E. V.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Limketkai;given-names:B. N.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Haydek;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Agrawal;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Scott;given-names:F. I.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2024.10.001</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39572132</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">167</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>102607</offset><text>AGA living clinical practice guideline on pharmacological management of moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">9</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sorbara;given-names:M. T.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pamer;given-names:E. G.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41385-018-0053-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">29988120</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mucosal Immunol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><offset>102717</offset><text>Interbacterial mechanisms of colonization resistance and the strategies pathogens use to overcome them</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1352</infon><infon key="lpage">1355</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Steidler;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hans;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schotte;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Neirynck;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Obermeier;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Falk;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1126/science.289.5483.1352</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10958782</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">289</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>102820</offset><text>Treatment of murine colitis by Lactococcus lactis secreting interleukin-10</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1715</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stojanov;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Berlec;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Štrukelj;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/microorganisms8111715</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33139627</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microorganisms</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>102895</offset><text>The influence of probiotics on the Firmicutes/Bacteroidetes ratio in the treatment of obesity and inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">183</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Splichalova;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Donovan;given-names:S. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tlaskalova-Hogenova;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Stranak;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Splichalova;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Splichal;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3390/biomedicines9020183</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33670419</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biomedicines</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>103020</offset><text>Monoassociation of preterm germ-free piglets with Bifidobacterium animalis Subsp. Lactis BB-12 and its impact on infection with Salmonella typhimurium</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">724</infon><infon key="lpage">731</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tang;given-names:T. C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tham;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Liu;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yehl;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Rovner;given-names:A. J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yuk;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41589-021-00779-6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33820990</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Chem. Biol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>103171</offset><text>Hydrogel-based biocontainment of bacteria for continuous sensing and computation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">10</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tomkovich;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jobin;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/imm.12538</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26439191</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Immunology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">147</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>103252</offset><text>Microbiota and host immune responses: a love-hate relationship</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">4</infon><infon key="lpage">22</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Torres;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bonovas;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Doherty;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kucharzik;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gisbert;given-names:J. P.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Raine;given-names:T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjz180</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31711158</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Crohns Colitis</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">14</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>103315</offset><text>ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in crohn’s disease: medical treatment</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">147</infon><infon key="lpage">153</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tursi;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Turroni;given-names:S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bastiani;given-names:R. D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Procaccianti;given-names:G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:D'Amico;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Allegretta;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/MEG.0000000000002884</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39514266</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur. J. Gastroenterol. Hepatol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>103387</offset><text>Gut microbiota in symptomatic uncomplicated diverticular disease stratifies by severity of abdominal pain</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1062</infon><infon key="lpage">1083</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Valdés-Mas;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Leshem;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zheng;given-names:D. P.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cohen;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kern;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zmora;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.016</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">188</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>103493</offset><text>Metagenome-informed metaproteomics of the human gut microbiome, host, and dietary exposome uncovers signatures of health and inflammatory bowel disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">151</infon><infon key="lpage">161</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Varela;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Manichanh;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gallart;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Torrejón;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Borruel;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Casellas;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/apt.12365</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23725320</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">38</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>103645</offset><text>Colonisation by Faecalibacterium prausnitzii and maintenance of clinical remission in patients with ulcerative colitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">878</infon><infon key="lpage">880</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Veiga;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Suez;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Derrien;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Elinav;given-names:E.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41564-020-0721-1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">32393856</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Microbiol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>103764</offset><text>Moving from probiotics to precision probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">493</infon><infon key="lpage">507</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Villablanca;given-names:E. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Selin;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hedin;given-names:C. R. H.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41575-022-00604-y</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35440774</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Rev. Gastroenterol. Hepatol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">19</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>103811</offset><text>Mechanisms of mucosal healing: treating inflammatory bowel disease without immunosuppression?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">927</infon><infon key="lpage">938</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vos;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Buckling;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kuijper;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Eyre-Walker;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bontemps;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Leblond;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tig.2024.07.008</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends in genetics:TlG</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>103905</offset><text>Why do mobile genetic elements transfer DNA of their hosts?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">763</infon><infon key="lpage">776</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wan;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhou;given-names:J. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhang;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Xie;given-names:S. M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/CM9.0000000000003542</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39994836</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Chin. Med. J.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">138</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>103965</offset><text>Epidemiology, pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment of inflammatory bowel disease: insights from the past two years</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">110791</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:L. X.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hu;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:K.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhao;given-names:Y. L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhu;given-names:M. T.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.isci.2024.110791</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39286511</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">iScience</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">27</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>104082</offset><text>Advancements in gene editing technologies for probiotic-enabled disease therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">38</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:X. L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:Y. X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yang;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yang;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wei;given-names:F. F.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yan;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12876-025-03604-9</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39871150</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">BMC Gastroenterol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>104162</offset><text>Effect of probiotics combined with immune checkpoint suppressors and chemotherapeutic agents on digestive system function, intestinal immunity and prognosis in patients with metastatic colorectal carcinoma: a quasi-experimental study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1089</infon><infon key="lpage">1102</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tian;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jiang;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ning;given-names:L. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhu;given-names:X. Q.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Chen;given-names:X. J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2025.01.007</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39978335</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Metab.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>104396</offset><text>Synergistic role of gut-microbial L-ornithine in enhancing ustekinumab efficacy for Crohn's disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1581971</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wei;given-names:J. C.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ding;given-names:W. S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Song;given-names:K. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y. K.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Luo;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Qi;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1581971</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40667443</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontiers in nutrition</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>104496</offset><text>Next-generation probiotics and engineered BEVs for precision therapeutics in osteoporosis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1200994</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:Y. D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gadsden;given-names:S. A.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3389/frai.2023.1200994</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">37928448</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Frontiers in artificial intelligence</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2023</infon><offset>104586</offset><text>Machine learning algorithms in microbial classification: a comparative analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1584</infon><infon key="lpage">1598</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wijnands;given-names:A. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jong;given-names:M. E.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lutgens;given-names:M. W. M. D.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hoentjen;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Elias;given-names:S. G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Oldenburg;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2020.12.036</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">33385426</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gastroenterology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">160</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>104666</offset><text>Prognostic factors for advanced colorectal neoplasia in inflammatory bowel disease: systematic review and meta-analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">227</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:X. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:Q. B.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yang;given-names:C. Q.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Huang;given-names:X. X.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Du;given-names:H. L. Y.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/s12951-025-03280-7</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40114208</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Nanobiotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>104786</offset><text>Reducing severity of inflammatory bowel disease through colonization of Lactiplantibacillus plantarum and its extracellular vesicles release</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0165122</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jha;given-names:R.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zeng;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zhang;given-names:C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/spectrum.01651-22</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">36321893</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Microbiol. Spectr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>104927</offset><text>Probiotics (Lactobacillus plantarum HNU082) supplementation relieves ulcerative colitis by affecting intestinal barrier functions, immunity-related gene expression, gut microbiota, and metabolic pathways in mice</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">333</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:Y. Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zou;given-names:Z. P.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhou;given-names:Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Ye;given-names:B. C.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00253-024-13163-w</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">38739270</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">108</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>105139</offset><text>Dual engineered bacteria improve inflammatory bowel disease in mice</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">120330</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Xu;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hou;given-names:Q. S.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhu;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Feng;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:P. Y.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pan;given-names:Y. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2022.120330</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35051420</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Life Sci.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">292</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>105207</offset><text>The protective effect of Escherichia coli Nissle 1917 on the intestinal barrier is mediated by inhibition of RhoA/ROCK2/MLC signaling via TLR-4</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">22</infon><infon key="lpage">29</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yadav;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Shukla;given-names:P.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/bab.1822</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">31538358</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biotechnology and applied biochemistry</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2020</infon><offset>105351</offset><text>Efficient engineered probiotics using synthetic biology approaches: A review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e2024004008</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yan;given-names:S. Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gao;given-names:J. X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sun;given-names:Q. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jfutfo.2024.04.008</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Fut. Foods</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>105428</offset><text>Research progress on colonization of probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">25</infon><infon key="lpage">28</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yan;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Polk;given-names:D. B.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.4161/gmic.19245</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22356855</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Gut Microbes</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">3</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>105476</offset><text>Characterization of a probiotic-derived soluble protein which reveals a mechanism of preventive and treatment effects of probiotics on intestinal inflammatory diseases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">104854</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yao;given-names:B. Q.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yang;given-names:Z. Q.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhao;given-names:X. R.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Han;given-names:Z. X.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:P. L.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Shang;given-names:N.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2024.104854</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends Food Sci. Technol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">156</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>105644</offset><text>Biofilm-state probiotics: advanced alternatives to traditional probiotics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">268</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yuan;given-names:C. M.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ji;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:X. L.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Ding;given-names:L. G.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Li;given-names:J. D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s11274-024-04065-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39007987</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">World J. Microbiol. Biotechnol.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>105718</offset><text>Important role of Bacillus subtilis as a probiotic and vaccine carrier in animal health maintenance</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">117197</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhai;given-names:Z. N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Qian;given-names:Z. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:A.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zhao;given-names:W. J.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Xiong;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2024.117197</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39084077</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biomed. Pharmacother.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">178</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>105818</offset><text>Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG coating with nanocomposite ameliorates intestinal inflammation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6623</infon><infon key="lpage">6644</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:Z.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Niu;given-names:H.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Qu;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Guo;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wan;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yang;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1080/10408398.2024.2448562</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39745813</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Crit. Rev. Food Sci. Nutr.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">65</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>105908</offset><text>Advancements in Lactiplantibacillus plantarum: probiotic characteristics, gene editing technologies and applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1042</infon><infon key="lpage">1051</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y. N.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wang;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.11817/j.issn.1672-7347.2024.240361</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">39788492</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Cent. South Univ.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2024</infon><offset>106025</offset><text>Probiotics in reducing obesity by reconfiguring the gut microbiota</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2431</infon><infon key="lpage">2453</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhao;given-names:L.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Niu;given-names:M. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ma;given-names:Z. L.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:He;given-names:F. Y.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liu;given-names:X. X.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Gong;given-names:X. W.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.apsb.2025.03.021</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">40487649</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Acta Pharm. Sin. B</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>106092</offset><text>Modified probiotics and the related combinatorial therapeutics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5914</infon><infon key="lpage">5924</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhao;given-names:Z. J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Xu;given-names:S. M.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:W. Y.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wu;given-names:D. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:G. S.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1039/d2fo00226d</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35583304</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Food Funct.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>106155</offset><text>Probiotic Escherichia coli Nissle 1917 for inflammatory bowel disease applications</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">742</infon><infon key="lpage">753</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhou;given-names:X.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Guo;given-names:Q.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Guo;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Li;given-names:B.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Peng;given-names:W.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wang;given-names:D.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2021.09.009</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">34517041</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J. Control. Release</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">338</infon><infon key="year">2021</infon><offset>106238</offset><text>Nanoarmour-shielded single-cell factory for bacteriotherapy of Parkinson’s disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3432</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zhou;given-names:J.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Li;given-names:M. Y.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chen;given-names:Q. F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Li;given-names:X. J.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chen;given-names:L. F.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Dong;given-names:Z. L.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/s41467-022-31171-0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">35701435</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat. Commun.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">2022</infon><offset>106323</offset><text>Programmable probiotics modulate inflammation and gut microbiota for inflammatory bowel disease treatment after effective oral delivery</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1567</infon><infon key="lpage">1574</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zocco;given-names:M. A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Verme;given-names:L. Z.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cremonini;given-names:F.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Piscaglia;given-names:A. C.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Nista;given-names:E. C.</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Candelli;given-names:M.</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-2036.2006.02927.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16696804</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>106459</offset><text>Efficacy of Lactobacillus GG in maintaining remission of ulcerative colitis</text></passage></document>
</collection>